<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="./schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Title of Assignment</title>
        <author xml:id="your_id_here">Your name here</author>
        <version n="num_of_version" date="2016-01-01"/>
        <!--note that the date must be YYYY-MM-DD for the document to be valid-->
    </docHead>
    <blog_post> Root element for Science Blog genre 
    <!-- Global Elements-->
        <!-- Optional elements that can go anywhere -->
        <!-- "n" attribute used to number potentially repeated elements. Optional. -->
        <section_header>’background’ and ‘answer’ are best broken into modular digestible sections
            consisting of several paragraphs. ‘section_header’ should be titled in a way such that
            the following paragraphs either work in concert to make the point specified by
            ‘section_header’, or answer a question put forth by ‘section_header’. </section_header>
        <visual type="">Visuals are any variety of in line imagery used to break up long lengths of text,
            and/or aid in the understanding of a topic. Comics, pictures and graphics are a few of
            the possible visuals that can be used.<!-- Types can be: Photo, Comic, Drawing, Animation,
                Quoted Text, Other --></visual>
        <analogy>Analogies should be used to better illustrate important and difficult to understand
            topics put forth by the other elements.</analogy>
        <roadmap>A roadmap is a list in which several ‘section_headers’ that build upon one another
            to drive home an important point are specified before diving into each section
            independently. This allows the reader to understand the purpose of a section in context
            to avoid getting lost in its details.</roadmap>
        <p n="">Paragraph of text, use to delineate individual paragraphs where necessary, such as in
            background or answer material</p>
        <ref type="">Hyperlink around a phrase that directs to a source or resource, can be found throughout
            the post depending on author's preference<!-- Types can be "source" or "supplement" for
               source material or supplemental material --></ref>
        <important_idea n="">Major points of interest relating to the topic.</important_idea>
    <!-- Structure -->
        <!-- Fitting the genre model, Background is followed by Answer, followed by Sources -->
        <!-- Elements within each parent element can occur in any order, though the listed order is
            standard. Typically, each element is its own paragraph, but can be combined in interest
            of brevity. -->
        <!-- Unless otherwise noted, all following elements are required -->
        <background> The section introduces the main topic. 
            <question>The question or topic that we are trying to answer or simplify to a general 
                audience.</question>
            <scientific_principle n="">Big picture fundamental scientific concepts involved (such as
                gravity, matter and energy, fluid dynamics, acid-base reactions,
                etc.)</scientific_principle>
            <misconceptions n="">Lists any common misconceptions the public has about the topic, or
                includes quoted material from the community that highlights the existing (false)
                notions about the answer<!-- Optional --></misconceptions>
        </background>
        <answer>Body of text that moves towards the answer of the question, presenting topics,
            ideas, analogies, and explanations that lead towards the ultimate conclusion
            <fundamental_science_involved n="">A wide-angled cursory description of the basic ideas
                framing the answer. Can be as little as 1 sentence. Ex. Explain one of Newton’s
                Laws, or introduce the basic idea of chemical reactions, etc. </fundamental_science_involved>
            <question_relevant_topic n="">Specific scientific principles that are directly relevant to
                the explanation of the question. Ex. A description of the chemistry behind acid-base
                reactions. </question_relevant_topic>
            <explanation n="">An in-depth reply to the question proposed in the “background”
                section. Typically, the author will use common vernacular and devices such as
                analogies and visuals in order to clearly convey concepts to readers.</explanation>
            <conclusion>A conclusion that sums up what was just explained. It acts as a concise
                response to the question asked in the “background” section </conclusion>
        </answer>
        <sources> Contains sources the author used to answer the question 
            <citation style="">A
                citation for the source written in the style the author decides to use (ex. MLA, APA
                etc.)<!-- Optional sub-element --></citation> 
        </sources>
    </blog_post>
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
