<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Writing Project 1 - Annotated Bibliography</title>
        <author xml:id="b11">Seth Bakes</author>
        <version n="3" date="2016-07-13"/>
        <!--note that the date must be YYYY-MM-DD for the document to be valid-->
    </docHead>
    <annotated_bib>
        <problem_stmt> The web app Northeastern University uses to help students search for co-ops is
            antiquated. The tools provided to navigate the site are lackluster and the whole service suffers
            from poor contributer (co-op providers) input. It is important to focus on the issue being one of
            usability and interface quality rather then this being a back end problem. This meaning the issue is primarily 
            related to the aspects of the web service that the user can see and interact with (or not in the case of a lack of features).
        </problem_stmt>
        <citation style="MLA" n="1">
            <author>Julie M. Rinder</author>
            <ref>https://scholarsbank.uoregon.edu/xmlui/bitstream/handle/1794/12257/Rinder2012.pdf?sequence=1</ref>
            <title>The Importance of Website Usability Testing</title>
            <!-- Rinder, Julie M. The Importance of Website Usability Testing. University of Oregon, 12 July 2012. 
                Web. 11 July 2016. <https://scholarsbank.uoregon.edu/xmlui/bitstream/handle/1794/12257/Rinder2012.pdf?sequence=1>.-->
        </citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="source">Rinder's capstone report brings together a large collection
                of professional works regarding the history of website usability and the actual 
                process of testing it. The author brings this to us in the form of a scholarly annotated bibliography
                This University of Oregon report also provides us with a large scope
                of website usability, including recent influences on web usability all the way 
                through how businesses can adapt to these influences. 
            </background>
            <summary type="approach">The Importance of Website Usability starts off with a strong idea: that
                perceived usability is key to user satisfaction. Though Rinder often takes a business focused lens
                when discussing usability and why it is important, the ideas are relevant to all circles. The report outlines
                the criteria it used for sources, including looking for authority and quality. After the bulk of the report consisting of
                annotated bibliographies, Rinder has a lengthy conclusion, breaking down what the author considers to be the defining 
                principles of usability, comparing and contrasting researched ideas and often noting the similarities. The majority of his analytical 
                work comes in the conclusion, and it focuses heavily on the importance and process of reliable testing.     
            </summary>
            <relevance type="application"> Rinder presents this simple idea: Users use and return to websites if they can easily find useful information-in other words,
                the acceptability of web applications relies on their usability. This is well said. Unfortunately in some
                cases, users don't have the choice. If you are looking for compelling reading into why you should appreciate well made
                web services, look no further. Although Rinder focuses heavily on usability testing rather then the philosophy behind usability, readers may
                find the conclusion detailing usability more relevant for creating arguments for and how to improve services. 
            </relevance>
        </annotation>
        
        <citation style="MLA" n="2">
            <author n="1">Rex P. Singular</author>
            <author n="2">Roselle S. Basa</author>
            <ref>Journal of Educational Technology and Society 14.4</ref>
            <title>Factors Affecting Faculty Web Portal Usability</title>
            <!-- Bringula, Rex P., and Basa, Roselle S. "Factors Affecting Faculty Web Portal Usability."
                 Journal of Educational Technology & Society 14.4, Advanced Learning Technologies (2011):
                 253-65. Web. 12 July 2016. <http://www.ifets.info/journals/14_4/21.pdf>. -->
        </citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="author">From the College of Computer Studies and Systems at the University of 
                East-Manila, Philippines, Singular and Basa investigate what can impact web portal usability. 
                The results of their research were intended to aid the university's online services, specifically in the
                interest of developing new ones. Included in their work is a large study of the present faculty including the questionaire used.
            </background>
            <summary type="general"> The article takes an analytical approach to different paradigms explaining
                the common occurs low usability of web services. The two authors look at a number of publications that 
                analyze similar topics and add to previous work in the field. Similar to other medium analysis work, the two
                authors develop their own principles of web design and go into an in-depth explanation of each. The authors also
                provide evidence for a number of original thesis statements relevant to the development of faculty and staff web portals.   
            </summary>
            <relevance type="application"> As outlined in preface of their research, the majority of the authors' claims are targeted at university
                web portals for faculty and students. If this is what you are researching, this is paper is loaded with relevant original data and analysis.
                That should not discourage other researchers. The two authors make a number of important queries into the effects of images and layouts to navigability,
                which could be applied to any web service. The data the two authors collected is gathered mostly from tech savy students, which presents a clear bias. 
                Although that may be unavoidable at such a technical college. Despite this the research is valuable and the authors make a number
                of interesting arguments throughout the piece that anyone interested in digital interfaces would benefit from reading. 
            </relevance>
        </annotation>
        
        <citation style="MLA" n="3">
            <author n="1">Alexiei Dingli</author>
            <author n="2">Sarah Cassar</author>
            <ref>http://www.hindawi.com/journals/ahci/2014/479286/</ref>
            <title>An Intelligent Framework for Website Usability</title>
            <!-- Dingli, Alexiei, and Sarah Cassar. "An Intelligent 
                Framework for Website Usability." An Intelligent Framework for
                Website Usability. Department of Intelligent Computer Systems, 
                Faculty of ICT, University of Malta, Malta, 14 Apr. 2014. Web. 
                12 July 2016. <http://www.hindawi.com/journals/ahci/2014/479286/>. -->
        </citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="source"> The introduction to this article discusses a very common
                theme among web design research; websites play a central role in modern
                marketing. Specifically that at one time, it was enough to just own a website, but now that website
                are forced to compete vigorously. This paradigm influences the majority of the piece, and 
                and provides the reader with a valuable bare bones history. 
            </background>
            <summary type="interpretation"> 
                The meat of article is the discussion surrounding the technical elements and
                procedures to automate usability. The authors suggest discuss a number of empirical
                testing methods and already available analysis tools. The articles can be summed up with this: 
                <q>As a means of assisting website designers in developing usable websites, the aim of this paper 
                    is to present a tool which automates the process of website usability evaluation in order to eliminate the current 
                    obstacles preventing this process from being exercised in practice. </q>    
            </summary>
            <relevance type="application"> Despite the overwhelming majority of the article being a discussion about automated 
                usability testing, this article has a number valuable outlines regarding what is expected of usability, referencing
                a number of previously existing standards. Although the bulk of the tools listed and the discussion itself 
                is oriented at an professional audience, anyone can benefit from reading this article by internalizing the paradigms that
                influenced it. In regards to the paper's credibility, it is incredibly well sourced and provides a lengthy look into the research process.
                
            </relevance>
        </annotation>
        
        <citation style="MLA" n="4">
            <author n="1">Rodrigo Coutinho</author>
            <ref>https://www.outsystems.com/blog/2011/01/what-makes-a-great-web-app-great.html</ref>
            <title>What makes a great web app great?</title>
            <!-- Coutinho, Rodrigo. "What Makes a Great Web App Great?" Web log post. N.p.,13 Jan. 2011. Web. 12 July 2016. 
                <https://www.outsystems.com/blog/2011/01/what-makes-a-great-web-app-great.html>.-->
        </citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="author"> Coutinho is an author and developer at Outsystems. Outsystems
                is a business oriented application service that focuses on providing total packages. For example:
                complete services like a web app and mobile that are integrated. 
            </background>
            <summary type="summary"> The author's short blog post provides us with a developer's experience
                of web application design. He begins to talk about the external (user end) experiences that create a valuable
                service, but then switches his focus to the inner workings of a great web app. The author summarizes the characteristics
                that he believes set an application up for success. The author also reminds of a common pitfall of web development, and that is
                how the back end of the application must set the front end up for success. 
            </summary>
            <relevance type="value_stmt"> Although short, the author uses the size of this blog post well. Straight to the point, the author
                identifies what he wants to convey quickly and effectively. Anyone in or outside the industry can benefit from reading this blog 
                post, especially if you are considering developing a web application.  
            </relevance>
        </annotation>
        
        <citation style="MLA" n="5">
            <author n="1">Paul Boag</author>
            <ref>https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2011/08/how-to-build-a-better-web-application-for-your-business/</ref>
            <title>How to Build a Better Web Application for Your Business</title>
            <!-- Boag, Paul. "How To Build A Better Web Application For Your Business – Smashing Magazine." Smashing Magazine. N.p., 10 Aug. 2011.
                Web. 12 July 2016. <https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2011/08/how-to-build-a-better-web-application-for-your-business/>.-->
        </citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="source"> Right out of the gate, Boag's blog post smacks you in the face with its intentions.
                <q>Are you fed up with hearing about yet another Silicon Valley Web application built with fairy dust and
                    funded by magic pixies?</q>
                The answer for many is yes, and Boag's candid humor sets the mood the reader. The post is long, and detailed, but 
                segmented in a way that is easy to digest.
            </background>
            <summary type="approach"> As Boag puts it: <q>For us, developing a web application is about meeting a particular 
                business need</q> A clear and concise explanation, Boag explains how most developers have to work around business interests. Specifically
                stating that it is a luxury for a developer to have the digital infrastructure as the primary concern. Without actually stating it, Boag explains
                why it is common to see poor usiablity on highly funded projects. As a developer himself, Boag uses this blog
                post to share his "secrets" of working with web applications within the confines of business interests. Interestingly, they are not technical
                solutions, but personal ones. This isn't always the approach of software developer, and it leaves the reader with more to think about
                than just the relevant software development issues. 
            </summary>
            <relevance type="application"> Anyone looking to develop business oriented web applications should read this blog post. 
                The questions asked not only point out ways to create better software, but also how to better interact in compartmentalized
                corporations. Contractors, outside developers, or in-house developers will benefit from Boag's ideas. This personal approach to developing 
                is something all industry workers should be conscious of, whether you lead a product or just joined a scrum team. 
            </relevance>
        </annotation>
    </annotated_bib>
    
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
    
</DOC>