<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Writing Project 1 - Annotated Bibilography</title>
        <author xml:id="c12">Brent Christy</author>
        <version n="1" date="2016-07-12"/>
        <!--note that the date must be YYYY-MM-DD for the document to be valid-->
    </docHead>
    
    <annotated_bib>
        <problem_stmt>
            Every day throughout the city of Boston, thousands of commuters spend large 
            portions of their drive waiting in traffic. All it takes for traffic 
            to build up is one accident on a main street and cars will be backed up for 
            miles. Part of this issue is due to the volume of commuters entering and leaving the city during rush hour, but part of the 
            blame can also be placed on traffic control. Traffic control, specificially the use of traffic signals, is fairly far 
            behind today's technology. Although traffic signals 
            are monitored and timings are adjusted every five years, the results are 
            still not optimal. There needs to be a way for signals to utilize current 
            technologies in order to optimize commute times and allow for people's 
            already sparse free time to be spent how they like. Along with people's free time 
            being wasted, there is also a large amount of unecessary fuel consumption happening 
            while waiting in traffic. Something needs to be done about 
            traffic issues throughout high population cities such as Boston. 
        </problem_stmt>
        
        <citation style="MLA"><author n="1">Gilmore, John F.</author>, <author n="2">Khalid J. Elibiary</author>, and <author n="3">Naohiko Abe</author>. 
            <title>"Neural Network System for Traffic Flow Management."</title> AAAI Technical Report (1993): 85-95. Web.</citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="author">
                John Gilmore along with Khalid Elibiary of the Georgia Tech Research Institute produced 
                a paper for Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence regarding the
                use of neural networks to control traffic in 1993 with the assistance of Naohiko Abe
                of Mitsubishi Heavy Industries in Japan.
            </background>
            <summary type="general">
                Gilmore and his associates go into depth about how neural networks can be 
                implemented into a traffic control system to improve traffic conditions. They
                introduce the idea of using the Hopfield neural network model in order to 
                allow the network to learn and build off of its knowledge of previous
                congestion situations to improve traffic conditions. The group forms an 
                energy function which allows them to assign lights and traffic
                conditions different weights. Higher weighted traits, such as how busy an intersection generally is,
                allow lights to have a higher priority and change faster.
            </summary>
            <relevance type="application">    
                The usage of a neural network as described by Gilmore, Elibiary, and Abe 
                can be used as a base for a city wide traffic control system, where the system
                learns and adapts based on previous traffic data. This could cut out a large
                amount of traffic by optimizing the traffic flow.
            </relevance>
        </annotation>
        
        <citation style="MLA"></citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="author"></background>
            <summary type="general"></summary>
            <relevance type="application"></relevance>
        </annotation>
        
        <citation style="MLA"></citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="author"></background>
            <summary type="general"></summary>
            <relevance type="application"></relevance>
        </annotation>
        
        <citation style="MLA"></citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="author"></background>
            <summary type="general"></summary>
            <relevance type="application"></relevance>
        </annotation>
        
        <citation style="MLA"></citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="author"></background>
            <summary type="general"></summary>
            <relevance type="application"></relevance>
        </annotation>
    </annotated_bib>
    
    
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
    
</DOC>
