<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Assignment 1 - Annotated Bibliography</title>
        <author xml:id="g14">Ben Gincley</author>
        <version n="2" date="2016-07-12"/>
        <!--note that the date must be YYYY-MM-DD for the document to be valid-->
    </docHead>

    <annotated_bib>
        <problem_stmt>In neural engineering, there currently exist many gaps between current
            technology available to the public, and where public necessity lies. Demand comes
            primarily from the clinical sector, wherein individuals suffering from neurodegenerative
            diseases are left at a deficit in their ability to sense and interact with the world
            around them. Challenges facing the technology mainly center around decoding the
            biochemical signals within the central nervous system, encoding information technology
            into biochemical signals, and creating devices that are able to function within or in
            tandem with biological systems. Neural engineering as a discipline attempts to close
            these gaps by taking neurobiological, materials science, biotechnological, and computer
            science research and designing devices and techniques to integrate technology with
            neurobiology. Much of the work takes place in pre-clinical and clinical research
            contexts, and the applied aspect of the discipline is still by-and-large in its infancy,
            as technology begins to catch up to what is demanded by the applications. Ultimately,
            the goal of the discipline is to create devices that work seamlessly with biological
            systems, are non-invasive or biologically integrated, and allow complete restoration of
            function without loss of fidelity. <!--problem statement here-->
        </problem_stmt>
        <citation style="APA">Jarosiewicz B, Sarma AA, Bacher D, et al. Virtual typing by people
            with tetraplegia using a self-calibrating intracortical brain-computer interface.
            Science translational medicine. 2015;7(313):313ra179. doi:10.1126/scitranslmed.aac7328. </citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="author">The primary author of this paper, Beata Jarosiewicz, is a
                professor at Brown University's Department of Neuroscience, who has, in her career,
                contributed to or produced 18 publications, garnering nearly 800 citations thus far,
                and is renowned for her work using biotechnology and neuroscience to investigate
                ways to use and optimize brain-computer interfaces (BCIs).
                <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
            </background>
            <summary type="general">Jarosiewicz, et. al., sought to demonstrate that the
                nonstationarity that is convolved with neural signaling, that normally forces
                brain-computer interfaces to require frequent recalibration, can be mitigated using
                software to automatically account for such drift, in a point-and-click model used by
                tetrapalegic patients. <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
            </summary>
            <summary type="approach">The investigators used technological innovations, namely:
                    <q>tracking the statistics of neural activity</q> (neurobiological
                observations), correction for velocity bias (computer engineering), and
                recalibration of the decoder using data inferred from the user's past actions
                (computer engineering) to develop software that extends the time that BCIs can
                function properly before needing to be manually recalibrated.
                <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
            </summary>
            <relevance type="application">The innovations made through this investigation can be
                applied to a wider range of devices, not merely point-and-click oriented BCIs. This
                will further enable the viable use of intracortical BCIs that patients needing
                restoration of independent communication and other assistive devices depend on, and
                lay the groundwork for more optimized methods of accounting for
                nonstationarities.</relevance>
        </annotation>
    </annotated_bib>


    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>

</DOC>
