<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Assignment 1 - Annotated Bibliography</title>
        <author xml:id="g14">Ben Gincley</author>
        <version n="1" date="2016-07-11"/>
        <!--note that the date must be YYYY-MM-DD for the document to be valid-->
    </docHead>

    <annotated_bib>
        <problem_stmt>In neural engineering, there currently exist an array of gaps between current
            technology available to the public, and where public necessity lies. Demand comes
            primarily from the clinical sector, wherein individuals suffering from neurodegenerative
            diseases are left at a deficit in their ability to sense and interact with the world
            around them. Challenges facing the technology mainly center around decoding the
            biochemical signals within the central nervous system, encoding information technology
            into biochemical signals, and creating devices that are able to function within or in
            tandem with biological systems. Neural engineering as a discipline attempts to close
            these gaps by taking neurobiological, materials science, biotechnology, and computer
            science research and designing devices and techniques to integrate technology with
            neurobiology. Much of the work takes place in pre-clinical and clinical research
            contexts, and the applied aspect of the discipline is still by-and-large in its infancy,
            as technology begins to catch up to what is demanded by the applications. Ultimately,
            the goal of the discipline is to create devices that work seamlessly with biological
            systems, are non-invasive or biologically integrated, and allow complete restoration of
            function without loss of fidelity. <!--problem statement here-->
        </problem_stmt>
        <citation style=""/>
        <annotation>
            <background type="">
                <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
            </background>
            <summary type="">
                <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
            </summary>
            <relevance type=""> </relevance>
        </annotation>
    </annotated_bib>


    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>

</DOC>
