<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Writing Project 1: Producing Annotated Bibliographies, a Problem-Seeking
            Project</title>
        <author xml:id="h15">Tammy Huynh</author>
        <version n="1" date="2016-07-11"/>
        <!--note that the date must be YYYY-MM-DD for the document to be valid-->
    </docHead>

    <annotated_bib>
        <problem_stmt>Virtual reality (VR) is a technology that places users in an interactive
            simulated environment. Today VR is used beyond entertainment purposes to treat various
            psychological conditions, including social anxiety and PTSD, by simulating situations
            that trigger targeted symptoms. Expanding upon this, VR can be leveraged in
            motor-related rehabilitation. Computer engineering focuses on the development of
            physical devices that reliably gather and relay data as well as software that interprets
            and displays data in meaningful ways. In relation to VR motor-related therapy, the
            discipline is responsible for syncing users’ movement virtually to a viewable device,
            interpreting the results based on specified criteria, adjusting settings accordingly,
            and iterating procedures. It is also concerned with the cost efficiency and comfort of
            such devices. Game development can be considered a branch of CS (or perhaps its own
            discipline) and is the coding and design (level layout, adjusted difficulty settings,
            art assets) of games. Motor disorders afflict patients from various age groups from
            children with cerebral palsy to post-stroke elders. Thus, it is important to tailor the
            virtual environments to the individual to encourage interactivity, especially for
            children and those with attention deficiencies. Additionally, designing and adjusting
            difficulty settings in relation to performance is vital to prevent frustration or
            boredom and further promote self-engagement. Leveraging VR in motor-related
            rehabilitation has a promising outlook in that it engages users, provides real-time
            feedback and progress tracking, cuts setup times, is tailored to the patient, and can
            potentially move therapies to a home setting.</problem_stmt>

        <!-- Citation 1 -->
        <citation n="1" style="APA"><author n="1">Lange, B.</author>, <author n="2">Koenig,
                S.</author>, <author n="3">Chang, C.</author>, <author n="4">Mcconnell, E.</author>,
                <author n="5">Suma, E.</author>, <author n="6">Bolas, M.</author>, &amp; <author
                n="7">Rizzo, A.</author> (2012). <title level="a">Designing informed game-based
                rehabilitation tasks leveraging advances in virtual reality</title>. <title
                level="j">Disability and Rehabilitation</title>, 34(22), 1863-1870.
            doi:10.3109/09638288.2012.670029</citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="source"> This article provided by USC, Institute for Creative
                Technologies, in the journal Disability and Rehabilitation, </background>
            <summary type="general">highlights the benefits and challenges of implementing VR
                in therapeutic strategies. VR can be implemented in various ways. Sometimes head-mounts are
                used to display the view to the user and adjust in relation to his orientation.
                Body-tracking sensors can also provide a wider range of interactivity. Other times
                6-wall rooms with projections called Cave Automatic Virtual Environments (CAVEs) are
                implemented to provide a less restrained, though more expensive, experience.
                Additionally, VR allows for varied perspectives by offering 1st or 3rd person views,
                which may give new insights to how patients respond to therapy. VR in therapy has
                long been hindered by costs of equipment, but commercial technology, such as the Wii
                and Kinect provide affordable ways to introduce rehabilitation to a home setting. </summary>
            <summary type="interpretation">Still, commercial technologies were not initially
                intended for therapeutic practices; therefore, they must be adjusted accordingly;
                else they may promote improper motor skills.</summary>
            <relevance type="value_stmt">This source is relevant in that it provides a good
                introduction to VR in therapy and some associated problems.</relevance>
        </annotation>

        <!-- Citation 2 -->
        <citation n="2" style="APA"><author n="1">Merians, A.</author>, <author n="2">Jack, D.
            </author>, <author n="3">Boian, R.</author>, <author n="4">Tremaine, M.</author>,
                <author n="5">Burdea, G.</author>, <author n="6"> Adamovich, S.</author>, <author
                n="7">Reece, M.</author>, &amp; <author n="8"> Poizner, H.</author> (2002). <title
                level="a">Virtual Reality–Augmented Rehabilitation for Patients Following
                Stroke</title>. <title level="j">Physical Therapy</title>, 82(9),
            898-915.</citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="">
                <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
            </background>
            <summary type="">
                <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
            </summary>
            <relevance type=""> </relevance>
        </annotation>

        <!-- Citation 3 -->
        <citation n="3" style="APA"><author n="1">Sveistrup, H.</author> (2004). <title level="a"
                >Motor rehabilitation using virtual reality</title>. <title level="j">Journal of
                NeuroEngineering and Rehabilitation</title>, 1(1), 10.
            doi:10.1186/1743-0003-1-10</citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="">
                <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
            </background>
            <summary type="">
                <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
            </summary>
            <relevance type=""> </relevance>
        </annotation>

        <!-- Citation 4 -->
        <citation n="4" style="APA"><author n="1">Barrett, N.</author>, <author n="2">Swain,
                I.</author>, <author n="3">Gatzidis, C.</author>, &amp; <author n="4">Mecheraoui,
                C.</author> (2016). <title level="a">The use and effect of video game design theory
                in the creation of game-based systems for upper limb stroke rehabilitation</title>.
                <title level="j">Journal of Rehabilitation and Assistive Technologies
                Engineering</title>, 3(0). doi:10.1177/2055668316643644</citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="">
                <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
            </background>
            <summary type="">
                <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
            </summary>
            <relevance type=""> </relevance>
        </annotation>

        <!-- Citation 5 -->
        <citation n="5" style="APA"><author n="1">Koenig, S.</author>, <author n="2">Ardanza,
                A.</author>, <author n="3">Cortes, C.</author>, <author n="4">Mauro, A. D.</author>,
            &amp; <author n="5">Lange, B.</author> (2013). <title level="a">Introduction to Low-Cost
                Motion-Tracking for Virtual Rehabilitation</title>. <title level="j">Biosystems
                &amp; Biorobotics Emerging Therapies in Neurorehabilitation</title>, 287-303.
            doi:10.1007/978-3-642-38556-8_15</citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="">
                <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
            </background>
            <summary type="">
                <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
            </summary>
            <relevance type=""> </relevance>
        </annotation>
    </annotated_bib>

    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>

</DOC>
