<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Writing Project 1: Producing Annotated Bibliographies, a Problem-Seeking
            Project</title>
        <author xml:id="h15">Tammy Huynh</author>
        <version n="1" date="2016-07-11"/>
        <!--note that the date must be YYYY-MM-DD for the document to be valid-->
    </docHead>

    <annotated_bib>
        <problem_stmt>Virtual reality (VR) is a technology that places users in an interactive
            simulated environment. Today VR is used beyond entertainment purposes to treat various
            psychological conditions, including social anxiety and PTSD, by simulating situations
            that trigger targeted symptoms. Expanding upon this, VR can be leveraged in
            motor-related rehabilitation. Computer engineering focuses on the development of
            physical devices that reliably gather and relay data as well as software that interprets
            and displays data in meaningful ways. In relation to VR motor-related therapy, the
            discipline is responsible for syncing users’ movement virtually to a viewable device,
            interpreting the results based on specified criteria, adjusting settings accordingly,
            and iterating procedures. It is also concerned with the cost efficiency and comfort of
            such devices. Game development can be considered a branch of CS (or perhaps its own
            discipline) and is the coding and design (level layout, adjusted difficulty settings,
            art assets) of games. Motor disorders afflict patients from various age groups from
            children with cerebral palsy to post-stroke elders. Thus, it is important to tailor the
            virtual environments to the individual to encourage interactivity, especially for
            children and those with attention deficiencies. Additionally, designing and adjusting
            difficulty settings in relation to performance is vital to prevent frustration or
            boredom and further promote self-engagement. Leveraging VR in motor-related
            rehabilitation has a promising outlook in that it engages users, provides real-time
            feedback and progress tracking, cuts setup times, is tailored to the patient, and can
            potentially move therapies to a home setting.</problem_stmt>

        <!-- Citation 1 -->
        <citation style="APA">Lange, B., Koenig, S., Chang, C., Mcconnell, E., Suma, E., Bolas, M.,
            &amp; Rizzo, A. (2012). Designing informed game-based rehabilitation tasks leveraging
            advances in virtual reality. Disability and Rehabilitation, 34(22), 1863-1870.
            doi:10.3109/09638288.2012.670029</citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="source">
                <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
            </background>
            <summary type="">
                <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
            </summary>
            <relevance type=""> </relevance>
        </annotation>

        <!-- Citation 2 -->
        <citation style="APA">Merians, Alma S., David Jack, Rares Boian, Marilyn Tremaine, Grigore C.
            Burdea, Sergei V. Adamovich, Michael Reece, and Howard Poizner. "Virtual
            Reality–Augmented Rehabilitation for Patients Following Stroke." Physical Therapy 82.9
            (2002): 898-915. Web.</citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="">
                <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
            </background>
            <summary type="">
                <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
            </summary>
            <relevance type=""> </relevance>
        </annotation>

        <!-- Citation 3 -->
        <citation style="APA">Sveistrup, H. (2004). Motor rehabilitation using virtual reality.
            Journal of NeuroEngineering and Rehabilitation, 1(1), 10.
            doi:10.1186/1743-0003-1-10</citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="">
                <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
            </background>
            <summary type="">
                <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
            </summary>
            <relevance type=""> </relevance>
        </annotation>

        <!-- Citation 4 -->
        <citation style="APA">Barrett, N., Swain, I., Gatzidis, C., &amp; Mecheraoui, C. (2016). The
            use and effect of video game design theory in the creation of game-based systems for
            upper limb stroke rehabilitation. Journal of Rehabilitation and Assistive Technologies
            Engineering, 3(0). doi:10.1177/2055668316643644</citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="">
                <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
            </background>
            <summary type="">
                <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
            </summary>
            <relevance type=""> </relevance>
        </annotation>

        <!-- Citation 5 -->
        <citation style="APA">Koenig, S., Ardanza, A., Cortes, C., Mauro, A. D., &amp; Lange, B.
            (2013). Introduction to Low-Cost Motion-Tracking for Virtual Rehabilitation. Biosystems
            &amp; Biorobotics Emerging Therapies in Neurorehabilitation, 287-303.
            doi:10.1007/978-3-642-38556-8_15</citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="">
                <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
            </background>
            <summary type="">
                <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
            </summary>
            <relevance type=""> </relevance>
        </annotation>
    </annotated_bib>

    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>

</DOC>
