<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Producing Annotated Bibliographies, a Problem-Seeking Project</title>
        <author xml:id="l18">Daniel Lieman</author>
        <version n="1" date="2016-08-24"/>
        <!--note that the date must be YYYY-MM-DD for the document to be valid-->
    </docHead>
    
    <annotated_bib>
        <problem_stmt>
            Computer Engineers often deal with electronics and any sort of embedded computational and communicating ability in them.
            This makes them uniquely suited to solve an irritating problem faced by Boston residents.  Boston is a wonderful city
            to walk around, but time spent walking can be limited by cell phone battery.  People often need their cell phones while
            walking to use as maps in unfamiliar areas or for the standard use of providing a point of contact for people who need to
            get in touch.  Some people also are getting their batteries drained by whatever new popular app is out.  While people can 
            stop and find an outlet somewhere, this is an annoying break in the walk and outlets aren’t readily available in Boston’s
            many wonderful parks.   Battery capacity itself is currently a hard problem due to safety among other things, but Computer
            Engineers could help by creating a gadget to circumvent that problem.  One possible idea would be a tracked battery swapping
            system similar to a past proposal by Tesla Motors.   Creating the hardware for tracking battery usage would be right within
            a Computer Engineer’s expertise.           
         </problem_stmt>
        <citation style="IEEE"><author>R. Ellis</author> et al., <title>"Battery Recharging and Testing Swap Stations,"</title> in 1st IEEE Conf. SusTech, Portland, OR, 2013, pp. 208-211.</citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="author">
                This article was a collaboration between a students' capstone group from Portland State University and the private company BETTERY.  It involved the 
                design of a battery swap station.
            </background>
            <summary type="general" >
                The paper includes various details on the design of the swap station.  These details include, but are not limited to: the method
                of testing battery capacity, and the hardware used for controls.
            </summary>
            <relevance type="application">
                This article could be used to determine previously attempted methods in the swap station industry.  This could be helpful for
                ensuring no intellectual property is infringed on.  It could also lead to collaborations if the researcher believed they could 
                substantially build on the previous work.
            </relevance>
        </annotation>
        <citation style="IEEE"><author>Z. He</author> et al., <title>"The location studies of charging station for replacing batteries,"</title> in 2011 International Conf. Advanced Power System Automation and Protection (APAP), Beijing, 2011, pp. 2013-2017.</citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="author">This paper is from a collaboration between Electrical Engineering and Economics researchers at the 
                Beijing jiao tong University.  The paper focuses on applications to car charging stations in China.</background>
            <summary type="approach">The paper presents a mathematical model for optimal deployment of charging stations.  It uses a 
                particle swarm approach where particles have various suitability as charging locations.  It provides a analogy for the algorithm used:
                <q>"PSO algorithm originates from the research of bird flock
                    searching for food, bird flock look for food randomly, there
                    is only one piece of food and all the birds do not know
                    where the food is, but they know how far they from the
                    food, the simplest and most effective way is to seek in the
                    area around the bird which is nearest to the food."</q></summary>
            <relevance type="application">The paper provides an interesting method for modeling charging, as well as further references
                about the particle swarm method.  Any researcher wanting to do a test deployment of a set of battery swap stations would find
                this useful in determining how to ensure greatest utilization.</relevance>
        </annotation>
        <citation style="IEEE"><author>D. Zheng</author>, <author>F. Wen</author> and <author>J. Huang</author>, <title>"Optimal planning of battery swap stations," </title> Int. Conf. Sustainable Power Generation Supply (SUPERGEN 2012), Hangzhou, 2012, pp. 1-7.</citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="source">This paper was presented at an international conference on how to provide sustainable forms of energy</background>
            <summary type="interpretation">The paper looks at the costs benefits of charging stations for electric buses.  It uses a Monte Carlo 
            Simulation to optimize battery swap station deployment.  The simulation is the used on a case study.</summary>
            <relevance type="application">This is useful as an additional source in approaching the problem of where swap stations should be deployed.
            Different results between the methodology described in this source and the previous could bring to light the consequences of the assumptions 
            in the respective models.  For example, the swaps in this model are more coordinated.</relevance>
        </annotation>
        <citation style="IEEE"><author>B. Sun</author>, <author>X. Tan</author> and <author>D. H. K. Tsang</author>, <title>"Optimal charging operation of battery swapping stations with QoS guarantee,"</title> 2014 IEEE Int. Conf. Smart Grid Communications (SmartGridComm), Venice, 2014, pp. 13-18.</citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="source">This paper was presented at a conference on communications, however it dealt more with charging policy.  The motivation
                was to guarantee a certain quality of service to impatient electric vehicle users: <q>"The price of EVs will be more acceptable for ordinary
                    customers and they could be free from the battery maintenance
                    problems. Second, the BSS can finish the battery swapping
                    service within 90 seconds, which is even faster than the
                    traditional gasoline refueling."</q></background>
            <summary type="general">This source discusses how batteries are handled after being deposited in a charging station.  It uses probabilistic 
            approaches to model the battery queuing. </summary>
            <relevance type="application">This source deals with the prioritization and methodology of charging batteries deposited.  It also 
            discusses the importance of charging capacity of individual stations.  This is a welcome viewpoint compared to the more network wide
            focus of other sources.</relevance>
        </annotation>
        <citation style="IEEE"><author>K. Korosec</author> 2015, JUNE 10, <title>Tesla's battery swap program is pretty much dead</title> [Online]. Available: http://fortune.com/2015/06/10/teslas-battery-swap-is-dead/</citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="source">Fortune is a well circulated business magazine.  Its website provides well source business new.</background>
            <summary type="interpretation">The article deals with the failures of the Tesla Motors' battery swap program.  It mentions some 
                possible reasons for the unpopularity: <q>"Maybe its because drivers initially had to make an appointment to use, or that they have to pay to use it."</q></summary>
            <relevance type="application">This source warns of possible pitfalls in creating a battery swap system.  Anyone developing swap systems in
            the future should avoid Tesla Motors' mistakes.</relevance>
        </annotation>
    </annotated_bib>
    
    
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>N/A</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
    
</DOC>
