<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Project 1</title>
        <author xml:id="m21">Chris Murphy</author>
        <version n="1" date="2016-07-11"/>
        <!--note that the date must be YYYY-MM-DD for the document to be valid-->
    </docHead>

    <annotated_bib>
        <problem_stmt> My discipline of mechanical engineering typically deals with problems of
            efficiency and in turn sustainability. It addresses current systems in place and works
            to improve their output while reducing their energy consumption. In the case of Boston’s
            public transportation and sanitation, it is important to address the problem of high
            amounts of fossil fuels being burned to keep the city functioning. A change in this area
            will not only help combat global warming as a whole, it will lead to reductions in both
            air and noise pollution in the city. It will affect both the general public who use
            public transportation as well as many residents who live at or near street level in the
            city. My discipline offers insights into the differences between internal combustion
            engines and electric motors. It can compare the cost/benefits of each in terms of
            accessibility, reliability, feasibility, and price. The input it provides can then be
            used to move forward in making a decision on how to best improve or alter the current
            fleet of vehicles that the city uses. </problem_stmt>






        <citation n="1" style="APA"><author n="1">Peter Kelly-Detwiler</author> (Mar 4, 2015).
                <title level="a">Electric Garbage Trucks: Huge Energy Savings And They Won't Wake
                You Up In The Morning</title>. <title level="j">Forbes Magazine</title>, 51 (4),
            541-554. </citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="source">Ian Wright, a Tesla cofounder, saw vast potential for electric
                motors in trucks and other vehicles beyond cars.
                <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
            </background>
            <summary type="general">Garbage trucks are known to be among the biggest wasters of
                energy due to their nature of highly frequent stops. Electrically powered garbage
                trucks are highly efficient due to their nature of capturing all of the energy used
                in braking and then reusing it, while also not releasing any carbon emissions.
                <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
            </summary>
            <relevance type="application"> Electric garbage trucks would have one of the most
                profound impacts on the energy efficiency of Boston’s public vehicles</relevance>
        </annotation>




        <citation n="1" style="APA"><author n="1">Mayor's Office</author> (Apr 7, 2015). <title
                level="a">Mayor Walsh Announces Ordinance to Reduce Diesel Emissions</title>. <title
                level="j">City of Boston.gov</title>, 51 (4), 541-554. </citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="author">Mayor Martin Walsh has announced his support for reducing the
                emissions from diesel vehicles owned or operated by the city of Boston.
                <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
            </background>
            <summary type="general">There are a growing number of health concerns both in the city
                and in the world regarding the problems created by carbon emissions from vehicles.
                    <q>“The asthma rate in Boston’s neighborhoods continues to climb," </q>said
                Councilor Murphy in a statement regarding the declining health of certain areas of
                Boston. <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
            </summary>
            <relevance type="application"> A large step to solving this public health issue could
                lie within eliminating all emissions from the city’s vehicles. </relevance>
        </annotation>





        <citation n="1" style="APA"><author n="1">Rachel Dovey</author> (Jul 17, 2015). <title
                level="a">Ex-Tesla Employee Wants Electric City Bus to Beat Out
                Diesel</title>. <title level="j">Next City</title>, 51 (4), 541-554. </citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="author">Many people look to electric cars as the best way to decrease
                emissions, but often overlook other modes of transportation that could be improved
                <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
            </background>
            <summary type="general">Buses are among the least environmentally friendly forms of
                transportation, averaging around 4mpg. When confronted with the improved versions of
                diesel vehicles, Proterra founder Ryan Popple adds, <q>“Natural gas is harder to
                    see, but it doesn’t really solve the problem and still creates a lot of ozone.
                    Bottom line: It’s a really bad idea to burn fossil fuels in an urban
                    environment.”</q>
                <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
            </summary>
            <relevance type="application"> Switching the city’s fleet of natural gas and hybrid
                buses over to electric would greatly improve transportation efficiency while
                lowering emissions in highly populated areas and travel routes. </relevance>
        </annotation>

        <citation n="1" style="APA"><author n="1">Tina Casey</author> (Jun 10, 2015). <title
                level="a">Electric Buses Could Beat CNG Buses By A Mile — Or Nearly
                6</title>. <title level="j">CleanTechnica</title>, 51 (4), 541-554. </citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="source">The newest versions of electric buses not only beat current
                CNG (Compressed Natural Gas) and diesel buses in terms of emissions, but also in how
                efficiently they use the energy they do have.
                <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
            </background>
            <summary type="general">Proterra is among the largest of recent electric bus
                manufacturers to enter the market. Their product is set apart from other current
                buses not only in the lack of emissions, but also in the efficiency of their buses
                as a whole; they have swapped out heavier building materials in favor of carbon
                fiber and other materials to make their buses lighter and perform better.
                <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
            </summary>
            <relevance type="application"> Boston could benefit from implementing electric buses
                because they not only use cleaner energy, they also use less energy. </relevance>
        </annotation>

        <citation n="1" style="APA"><author n="1"> Kristin Toussaint</author> (Aug 28, 2015). <title
                level="a">Breathing Boston air is like smoking 5 cigarettes a year</title>. <title
                level="j">Boston.com</title>, 51 (4), 541-554. </citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="source">Although most people can’t tell, there is still a fair amount
                of pollution in the air of Boston.
                <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
            </background>
            <summary type="general">Air pollution comes in different forms, including gaseous and
                particulate. In regards to particulate matter, John Walke, Clean Air Director for
                the Natural Resources Defense Council, notes <q>“These are very fine particles, and
                    those particles are particularly dangerous because they’re so small, they can
                    penetrate past the body’s natural defense system.’’</q> Particulate matter is
                one of the leading health hazards the EPA is trying to address in its ordinances 
                regarding emissions standards because lower CO2 does not necessarily mean lower
                particle byproducts. <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
            </summary>
            <relevance type="application">Eliminating particulate matter as a whole from emissions
                would be a large step forward in the respiratory health of the city. </relevance>
        </annotation>
    </annotated_bib>
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>

</DOC>
