<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Writing Project 1: Annotated Bibliographies</title>
        <author xml:id="your_id_here">Chi Mo</author>
        <version n="num_of_version" date="2016-07-12"/>
        <!--note that the date must be YYYY-MM-DD for the document to be valid-->
    </docHead>

    <annotated_bib>
        <problem_stmt>
            <!--problem statement here--> Information Science is basically about how to manage
            information and make the information to be used in a better way. Computer science
            classes which I have to take, gives<note type="instructor">give</note> me the solving
                problems<note type="instructor">problem solving</note> skills in a logical way. In
            other words, Information Science helps things “make more sense”. What I found not making
            sense is that most of street parking in Boston are 2-hour limit parking. Even if you
            find a street parking spot, it’s normally a 2-hour limit parking. It’s not enough for
            visiting a friend, traveling around the city or having a meal in a popular restaurant.
            What can you do in the city within 2 hours? All the parking space near Huntington Ave
            are 2-hour parking, if you have a class right after another class, 2 hours won’t be
            enough and you don’t have time to move your car. A ticket would appear on your car. The
            only place that have 4-hour parking is Ruggles Street near West Village, but we are
            sharing that street with Wentworth. I know that school has parking garages for students
            and staffs. I started to drive to class occasionally, on the first day of this summer, I
            thought there should be fewer students on campus so I drove on the first day of class.
            It took me 10 minutes to park the car that I didn’t need to move it every 2 hours. But
            if I want to park in the garage for Summer2 Day Parking only, it’s going to cost me
            $230, which only four days a week that I have to come to school. 2-hour limit in Boston
            is not a reasonable time for parking. If you stay in the city for couples of years, you
            would know that it’s hard to park with enough time not only around Boston University in
            Allston but also Harvard and MIT in Cambridge. Thus, I think all the 2-hour limit
            parking around universities should be changed into 4-hour parking or universities should
            lower the price of parking.<note type="instructor">I agree this is a worthy problem, but
                how does Info Science help you address this problem? It should come through in your
                sources, but also be mentioned here why an Info Science approach is
                appropriate.</note></problem_stmt>

        <citation n="1" style="APA"><author n="1">Inglis, J.</author>(2015),<title level="a"
                >Technology Can Help Solve Parking Problems</title><title level="w">Frontier
                Group</title>. Retrieved from http://www.frontiergroup.org/blogs/blog
            /fg/technology-can-help-solve-parking-problems</citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="source">
                <q>The city, however, is not managing the supply well. It can be done.</q><note
                    type="instructor">maybe a sentence to introduce this quote</note>When parking
                issue become a non-ignoring problem not only in Boston but also in a lot of big
                cities, people start to think a better way to solve the problem.</background>
            <summary type="general"> The article states parking issues in different
                    neighborhoods<note type="instructor">in Boston? In the U.S.?</note>. To solve
                this problem, some city, such as San Francisco, started to real-time monitor the
                parking available spots. This technology helps people know where can they park so
                that they won’t waste time on finding a parking spot. </summary>
            <relevance type="value_stmt"> In the article, it says that people get frustrating<note
                    type="instructor">frustrated</note> when they can’t find a parking spot. Which
                is exactly how I feel when I drive to school. The point of using technology is a
                good way to solve a real world problem.</relevance>
            <relevance type="application"> As a Information Science student, I not only need to
                develop a technology like this but also need to think how to use technology to solve
                a problem like this.<note type="instructor">I agree, how does this source help you
                    do that?</note>
            </relevance>
        </annotation>

        <citation n="2" style="APA"><author n="1">Mcmorrow, P.</author>(2014),<title level="a"
                >Boston’s parking solution is not more parking</title><title level="w">Boston
                Global</title>. Retrieved from https://www.bostonglobe.com/opinion
            /2014/04/15/boston-parking-solution-not-more-parking/fXh0u6PejrBTW6L1LfyF8K/story.html</citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="source"> The article was written at the time that a developer
                    wants<note type="instructor">wanted</note> to build a 62 apartments condo, with
                52 parking spots. </background>
            <summary type="general"> However, it was denied by Roxbury residents. They think the
                developer should turn the whole building into a parking garage. What will happen
                next is that it’s harder to drive in Boston and harder to park. <q>One of the
                    biggest mistakes municipalities make is requiring too much parking. </q>
            </summary>
            <summary type="interpretation">The demand of parking is way too much than it has right
                now. If the solution is to build more and more parking garage, it’s not going to
                work.</summary>
            <relevance type="value_stmt">However, in the other word, if the government make the
                public transportation more convenience, there would be fewer people driving.<note
                    type="instructor">OK, so what does that mean for your problem? How does this
                    help you think about your problem topically or
                methodologically?</note></relevance>
        </annotation>

        <citation n="3" style="APA"><author n="1">Conti, K.</author>(2014),<title level="a"
                >ommunities make changes to improve parking</title><title level="w">Boston
                Global</title>. Retrieved from https://www.bostonglobe.com
            /metro/regionals/south/2014/07/12/solution-parking-problems-suburban-centers-may-not-more-parking/oShdB1f44
            xiXdjvtnnWj3H/story.html</citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="source"> Parking in the city is always a problem for people especially
                for those who live in big cities.<note type="instructor">I'm unsure if this is
                    background information about the source or author, it reads more like a part of
                    summary</note>
            </background>
            <summary type="interpretation">
                <q>A parking study found that between on-street spots and municipal lots, Dedham
                    Square actually had plenty of parking, but it was not being managed
                    properly.</q> But the good thing is that the community is making changes to
                improve that. At least the community is trying to make it better by making some of
                the parking spots first 15 minutes free and using electronic pay station instead of
                the meters. </summary>
            <relevance type="value_stmt">It looks like there are not lack of parking space but need
                a good management.</relevance>
            <relevance type="application"> For example, parking near Northeastern University is not
                managed well. It’s hard for a person to get something done within 2 hours around
                school. If the meters’ limit can be changed into 4 hours, there should be less
                    complaints.<note type="instructor">does this article help you get tools for
                    managing parking better?</note>
            </relevance>
        </annotation>

        <citation n="4" style="APA"><author n="1">Doyle, P.</author>(2012),<title level="a">Why
                Parking in Boston Should Be More Expensive</title><title level="w">Boston
                Magazine</title>. Retrieved from
            http://www.bostonmagazine.com/2012/10/the-take-parking-in-boston/</citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="source"> Parking in Boston is such a big problem that according to the
                    article,<q>as bad as driving is in Boston, it’s a dream compared with the
                    parking.</q><note type="instructor">again, I don't think this is
                    background</note>
            </background>
            <summary type="interpretation"> Compared with other cities, parking fee in Boston is not
                so correct. People like to park on the street, like me, is because it’s much cheaper
                than a garage. I pay $1.25/H for street parking but $12/h in garage. However, in
                other major cities like Chicago or DC, citizens pay more to street parking than
                garage.</summary>
            <relevance type="application"> Also, increasing the T fare is not helping the parking
                problem. I pay 5/day for street parking if I drive to school but 5/day for T with
                doubled time. If we can increase the street parking fee and decrease the garage
                parking as well as T fare, the parking problem is Boston shouldn’t be as terrible as
                now. </relevance>
        </annotation>

        <citation n="5" style="APA"><author n="1">Barter, P.</author>(2013)<title level="a">"Cars
                are parked 95% of the time". Let's check!</title>
            <title level="w">Reinventing Parking</title>. Retrieved from
            http://www.reinventingparking.org/2013/02/ cars-are-parked-95-of-time-lets-check.html </citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="author"> The author is a person who cares about everything related
                with parking. I took a glance at his Google+ profile, all the articles and journals
                are about parking. </background>
            <background type="source">This article shows the author's one research on
                parking.</background>
            <summary type="approach"> The reason that people care a lot and complaint a lot about
                the parking is that most of time, the car is parked. When the owner is at home, at
                work, or shopping, the car need to be parked. According to the article<q>Since there
                    are 168 hours in a week, the typical UK car is parked 96.5% of the time -  even
                    higher than Shoup's US estimate!</q></summary>
            <relevance type="application"> The author collected a lot of data and made them into
                understandable numbers of percentage. One of the most important things of
                information science is to deal with data. As an information science student, I need
                to know how to collect data, manage raw data and make it into useful
                    information.<note type="instructor">right, but be specific; does this give you
                    concrete steps to take in order to collect the pertinent
                data?</note></relevance>
        </annotation>
    </annotated_bib>


    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>There is a lot going right here. Specifically, I think you do a good job of summarizing the sources. The issue I see is in making claims about relevance. It is often unclear exactly how the source helps you approach the problem, except in a very general way. Where will you get data? What kind of data is important for you? What kinds of models will help you understand and solve the parking problem? Part of this is making a clear case why an Info Science approach is appropriate for this problem; for example, if you simply want all the meters to be 4-hours, then that seems like a problem that a political organizer could undertake--starting a petition or filing paperwork with the city. Why would this problem need an Info Scientist?</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>

</DOC>
