<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Project 1 Annotated Bibliography</title>
        <author xml:id="m19">Sydnee Mizuno</author>
        <version n="1" date="2016-07-11"/>
        <!--note that the date must be YYYY-MM-DD for the document to be valid-->
    </docHead>

    <annotated_bib>
        <problem_stmt> Electrical engineering is a broad field that can cover anything from
            artificial intelligence, to cutting edge healthcare solutions, to personal electronics.
            There are countless other applications in this discipline, but the end goal is the same
            – to improve the overall quality of life. One way that engineers are trying to achieve
            this goal is by designing and implementing solutions to help improve the production and
            distribution of fresh food. While the lack of access to food is a global problem, it can
            especially affect urban areas. And as time goes on, the population will only to continue
            to grow and increase the severity of this problem. While the quantity of available food
            is certainly important, the quality should be considered too; to feed a hungry
            community, bringing in more fast food chains is not a healthy solution. This is where
            electrical engineers can help. By using skills from their discipline, they can create
            innovative technology to grow and deliver fresh produce year round. This technology
            already exists here in Boston and Cambridge, and it is led by startups that have visions
            for a healthier future. </problem_stmt>

        <citation n="1" style="APA"><author n="1">Vanni, O.</author> (2016, June 22).<title
                level="a"> Boston's Budding Agricultural Tech Cluster Has a Growing Problem to
                Solve</title>.<title level="w"> BostInno</title>. Retrieved from
            http://bostinno.streetwise.co/2016/06/22/boston-agriculture-and-food-tech-companies/</citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="source">The site BostInno, which covers local news about technology
                and startups, </background>
            <summary type="general"> gives an overview of the numerous food-related challenges in
                the world. There is a spectrum of issues from malnutrition and obesity to food
                scarcity and starvation. Within the U.S., <q>14 percent of households - translating
                    to 17.4 million of them - throughout the U.S. experienced food insecurity at
                    some point in 2014</q> (1). In both the U.S. and the rest of the world, the
                population will only grow and worsen this problem. Thankfully, many companies are
                currently looking for solutions, including two local startups. Grove Labs in
                Somerville created a product that allows people to grow produce in their own homes.
                Freight Farms in Boston repurposed shipping containers to grow crops. </summary>
            <relevance type="value_stmt">This article is helpful in spotlighting the different local
                companies that are solving today's food issues with engineering
                skills.</relevance><relevance type="application">Interested readers could click
                through the links provided in the article to find more in-depth information about
                each company in order to join the solution.</relevance>
        </annotation>

        <citation n="2" style="APA"><author n="1">Subbaramann, N.</author> (2015, April 12).<title
                level="a"> Somerville's Grove Labs Wants to revolutionize fresh food</title>.<title
                level="w"> Boston Globe</title>. Retrieved from
            https://www.bostonglobe.com/magazine/2015/04/11/somerville-grove-labs-wants-revolutionize-fresh-food/g4M3EqLuJhRl63OWNiP9wJ/story.html</citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="source"> The Pulitzer Prize winning newspaper Boston Globe </background>
            <summary type="general"> ran an article about the company Grove Labs and its
                revolutionary approach to fresh food. Starting in a fraternity room at MIT, founders
                Jamie Byron and Gabe Blanchet created an indoor aquaponics system and garden. They
                eventually took this hobby and turned it into a well-funded business. The current
                working prototype uses <q>well-designed smart lighting and sensors to monitor the
                    growing conditions within the system, all of which feed data into a smartphone
                    app</q> (1).</summary>
            <relevance type="value_stmt">Not only does the article show Grove Labs' success in
                numbers with its $2 million funding and 50 early customers, it also features a
                consumer's positive opinion. Alexi Conine, who lives in the South End of Boston,
                praises the Grove Labs' product for providing fresh food regardless of the season.
                This is especially important in a city like Boston with its record of cold, snowy
                winters that make farming difficult.</relevance><relevance type="application">This
                article provides Grove Labs' background, product reviews, and product features that
                could positively influence potential customers to buy a system and reap its
                benefits. </relevance>
        </annotation>

        <citation n="3" style="APA"><author n="1">Here and Now Staff.</author> (2015, February
                23).<title level="a"> Freight Farms: How Boston Gets Local Greens, Even When Buried
                in Snow</title>.<title level="w"> NPR</title>. Retrieved from
            http://www.npr.org/sections/thesalt/2015/02/23/388467327/-freight-farms-grow-local-flavor-year-round</citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="source"> NPR's food blog "The Salt" </background>
            <summary type="general"> explores how the Boston startup Freight Farms has impacted the
                local food space. In 2010 the co-founders Jon Friedman and Brad McNamara looked for
                ways to grow food anywhere. They came up with the idea to use shipping containers as
                controlled farming environments. Using digital technology, systems that include
                pumps, irrigation, LEDs, nutrients, and pH levels can be remotely monitored and
                controlled. </summary>
            <summary type="interpretation">This article clearly endorses Freight Farms' solution to
                healthy food distribution in urban areas. It presents the farmers Shawn and Connie
                Cooney as satisfied customers. </summary>
            <relevance type="value_stmt">With their four shipping containers, the Cooneys can grow
                the same amount of produce as on four acres of land. And with the climate controls,
                they can grow produce every day of the year. NPR's article demonstrates how
                technology has provided these farmers with the capability to manage a profitable
                business in a city to the benefit of all. </relevance>
        </annotation>

        <citation n="4" style="APA"><author n="1">Schoenfeld, B.</author> (2011, September
                21).<title level="a"> How the Farm-to-Table Movement Is Helping Grow the
                Economy</title>.<title level="w"> Entrepreneur</title>. Retrieved from
            https://www.entrepreneur.com/article/220357</citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="author"> Award-winning author and television writer Bruce Schoenfeld </background>
            <summary type="general"> discusses the benefits of fresh, locally grown food. Besides
                the obvious health advantages of accessible agriculture, there are also major
                economic advantages. In Seattle, small farms are making $10,000 to $1 million
                anually. In Cleveland, there is the potential to generate $750 million if the city
                grows just 5% of the total food it consumes. The farm-to-table movement creates jobs
                and revenue from farm work and the sale and distribution of produce. This movement
                is not just for fancy restaurteurs; many markets exist near lower income
                neghborhoods that provide access to healthy food at a steep
                discount.</summary><summary type="interpretation">With the numerous examples of
                economic prosperity resulting directly from local agriculture, Schoenfeld strongly
                supports the growth of it.</summary>
            <relevance type="application">This article is a good source for readers interested in
                learning about the economic effects of locally grown food. It could also inspire
                them to investigate innovations in this food movement or even create their own.
            </relevance>
        </annotation>

        <citation n="5" style="APA"><author n="1">Bellows, A.</author>, <author n="2">Brown,
                K.</author>, &amp;<author n="3">Smit, J.</author> (2004).<title level="a"> Health
                Benefits of Urban Agriculture</title>.<title level="w"> Community Wealth</title>.
            Retrieved from
            http://community-wealth.org/content/health-benefits-urban-agriculture</citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="author"> Members of the Community Food Security Coalitions's North
                American Initiative on Urban Agriculture <q>present research on the practical health
                    benefits of farming in the city</q> (1). </background>
            <summary type="general"> When there is easier access to fresh food, community members
                are more likely to eat healthily. Food security is also increased with this access;
                when there is personal interaction between a consumer and a local producer, instead
                of say a massive supermarket, there is an increase in<q>knowledge and commitment to
                    healthy, sustainable, and secure food products and practices</q> (5). Small
                scale agriculture also provides economic advantages by saving household food
                dollars.</summary>
            <relevance type="application">This paper is a comprehensive source of arguments
                supporting the practice of urban agriculture.</relevance>
        </annotation>
    </annotated_bib>


    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>

</DOC>
