<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Producing Annotated Bibliographies, a Problem-Seeking Project</title>
        <author xml:id="p22">Matt Parlon</author>
        <version n="6" date="2016-07-12"/>
        <!--note that the date must be YYYY-MM-DD for the document to be valid-->
    </docHead>
    
    <annotated_bib>
        <problem_stmt>
            Northeastern University advertises itself as one of the most “green” schools in the country. Meanwhile, this school continues to utilize energy produced at fossil fuel burning facilities. I plan to explore the major arguments against fossil fuels burning energy generation facilities while providing an economical alternative. The argument against burning fossil fuels for energy production is to include the unfair burden of the externalities associated with the electricity we all benefit from as well as the continuation of the cyclical expansion of income inequality. While providing a healthy alternative, I will utilize incentives brought to light by various solar developers.  Northeastern University, as an institution of higher learning has a responsibility to show Boston how we can help those less fortunate than us. Not only will running Northeastern University, at least partially, off of solar energy save money, it will help to combat the stigma that for each environmental gain, there is an equal and opposite economic loss.  <!--problem statement here-->
        </problem_stmt>
        
        <citation style="APA">
            <author> World Health Organization</author>.
            (2014, March 25).
            <title> 7 million premature deaths annually linked to air pollution </title>.
            Retrieved from <ref>http://www.who.int/mediacentre/news/releases/2014/air-pollution/en/</ref>
        </citation> 
        
        <annotation> 
            <background type="author">
                The World Health Organization was established in 1948 and is now the leading internation source of public health information. <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
            </background> 
            <background type="source">
                This particular piece by the WHO is valuable to many as it is an update to a previous, popular study on the health effects associated with air pollution.
            </background>
            
            <summary type="approach">
                While this article remains broad in the exact location of its studies, it uses advanced technological tools such as <q>satellite data, ground-level monitoring measurements and data on pollution emissions from key sources</q> to get pinpoint the dispersion of airborne pollutants. <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->      
            </summary>
            <summary type="general"> 
                This update to a study conducted in 2012 on the relationship between air pollutants and various diseases shows that the current situation is worse than previously thought. In particular, this study outlines how the most voulnerable groups to air pollution, children and the elderly, are the most exposed to it due to their more stagnant lifestyle. 
            </summary>            
            <summary type="interpretation">  
                While the statistics in this study generally speak for themselves, it is worth pointing out that the sources of the pollutants do not effect all people equally. For this reason, it is important to understand the actual externality dispersion so that our portions of the burden are put into perspective.
            </summary>
            
            <relevance type="application"> There are many application of this article. However, first and foremost, it is to be used to set the groundwork for any arguement regarding public health as it related to air pollution. No arguement can be formed without first establishing the concrete relationship between airbourne pollutants and public health issues.    
            </relevance>
            <relevance type="value_stmt"> The fact that this artice represents an update to a study should only provide more reader confidence in the World Health Organization. Although he origional statement made in 2012 had to be updated, the fact that they are on an ever expanding search for information makes their input paramount to any legitimate claim on the current state of worldwide air quality.                
            </relevance>
        </annotation>
        
        
        
        
        
        <citation style="APA">
            <author>Israel, B. </author>
            (2012, November 16).
            <title> Coal plants smothering communities of color, report finds </title>.
            <author>. The Daily Climate. </author>.
            Retrieved from <ref>http://www.dailyclimate.org/tdc-newsroom/2012/11/coal-power-injustice</ref>
        </citation> 
        
        <annotation> 
            <background type="author">
                The Daily Climate was founded in 2007 and has, to this day, provided readers with a one-stop media outlet that aggregates all climate change news in simple language. <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
            </background> 
            <background type="source">
                This article explores the communities most affected by the pollutants put into the air by coal-fired power plants.
            </background>
            
            <summary type="approach">
                In this piece, The Daily Climate breaks down a report conducted by the NAACP that focused on the communities surrounding all 378 coal fired power plants in the United States of America in 2012. <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->      
            </summary>
            <summary type="general">  
                The report focused heavily on the layout of minorities and people of color within three miles of the coal-fired power plants.
            </summary>            
            <summary type="interpretation"> 
                Although there was a slight correlation found between minorities and vicinity to these plants, the stronger relationship can be found between poverty-stricken communities and vicinity to these plants. These people who are the least able to afford medical care are the most exposed to airborne health dangers.
            </summary>
            
            <relevance type="application">  
                Facts stated by this article must be taken into consideration by anyone evaluation the demographics associated with diseases related to air pollution.
            </relevance>
            <relevance type="value_stmt">  
                Although the study evaluated by this piece was racially driven, the numbers associated with it can be utilized to obtain conclusions not explicitly stated by The Daily Climate.
            </relevance>
        </annotation>
        
        
        
        
        <citation style="APA">
            <author>Wilson, J.</author>
            (2015, May 31).
            <title> Why cities make people stupid: Air pollution significantly reduces children's IQ, study finds </title>
            <author>. Natural News. </author>
            Retrieved from <ref>http://www.naturalnews.com/049903_air_pollution_city_life_intelligence.html</ref>
        </citation> 
        
        <annotation> 
            <background type="author">
                Natural News is a media outlet focused on the quality of life people are achieving and how it is related to manmade changed in their environment.<!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
            </background> 
            <background type="source">
                In 2015, Natural News published this article relaying the findings of a study conducted by Colombia University on the mental effects of air pollution on young children.
            </background>
            
            <summary type="approach">
                This article points to several examples of decreased IQs in groups that were subject to increased exposure to air pollutants during their primary developmental stages of life. <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->      
            </summary>
            <summary type="general"> 
                Generally speaking, this article only points out that, of the groups studied, there was a linear relationship found between ones exposure to air pollutants in their early stages of life and their IQ later in life. There was, however, no explicit proof of causation. 
            </summary>            
            <summary type="interpretation">   
                The unfortunate truth that this article outlines is that we outsource the externalities of energy generation so that the wealthy can utilize the benefits without having to endure any of the downsides.
            </summary>
            
            <relevance type="application"> 
                This piece is the final building block to the argument that the cycle of wealth inequality is being continued by the forced exposure to pollutants that would decrease ones ability to gain the means to escape said situation.
            </relevance>
            <relevance type="value_stmt">  
                While this cannot be used to prove direct causation, it will be helpful to point out the correlation between decreased developmental yields in children and their levels of exposure to pollutants in the air.
            </relevance>
        </annotation>
        
        
        
        <citation style="APA">
            <author>BlueWave Capital.</author>
            . (2016, January 21).
            <title>BlueWave, Partners with Massachusetts’ Avidia Bank to Deliver Premium Home Solar Loan Product</title>
            . Retrieved from <ref>http://bluewave-capital.com/?p=2742</ref>
        </citation> 
        
        <annotation> 
            <background type="author">
                BlueWave Capital is a solar developer based in Boston founded by John DeVillars. Mr. DeVillars has been a lifelong advocate for environmental protection.<!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
            </background> 
            <background type="source">
                BlueWave published this article, themselves. They can be held accountable for all economic claims made within said article. With the intense scrutiny on solar right now, no developer would make any claims that cannot be confidently backed up
            </background>
            
            <summary type="approach">
                This source makes clear the economic benefit behind solar energy that is currently available in Massachusetts. BlueWave was sure to mention <q>the launch of its Home Solar Loan, a product that offers residents the opportunity to reduce their electricity bills by up to 50%+ with a rooftop solar installation</q><!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->      
            </summary>
            <summary type="general">  
                By installing solar on one’s roof, one may reduce their yearly electricity bill greatly. BlueWave also offers a community Solar program that allows people to purchase their electricity from a large scale solar array at a discount of approximately 10%. 
            </summary>            
            <summary type="interpretation">  
                This article makes clear that utilizing renewable energy sources does not necessarily require a large investment. In other terms, economic and environmental benefits do not have an inverse correlation.
            </summary>
            
            <relevance type="application">
                By observing the economic benefits associated with solar energy, the argument for local fossil fuels benefiting the American economy can be disregarded. 
            </relevance>
            
            <relevance type="value_stmt">    
                BlueWave does not put out press releases without completion of their objective. For this reason, all sources from their site can be useful tools when looking for examples of economic viability in green energy.
            </relevance>
        </annotation>
        
        
        
        
        
        <citation style="APA">
            <author>SunEdison </author>
            .(2016, March 22).
            <title> Why Solar Works for Colleges</title>
            . Retrieved from <ref>http://www.sunedison.com/blog/why-solar-works-colleges</ref>
        </citation> 
        
        <annotation> 
            <background type="author">
                SunEdison is a solar developer that has been in business since the beginning of the solar boom. They have been through many ups and downs as a company but their experience cannot be overstated. <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
            </background> 
            <background type="source">
                This piece found on SunEdison’s blog takes the lessons learned from past experience as takes out case specific events to generate the overarching benefits solar has to college campuses. 
            </background>
            
            <summary type="approach">
                By approaching the environmental, social, and economic aspects of solar equally, SunEdison is sure to make a sustainability-based argument. <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->      
            </summary>
            <summary type="general"> 
                SunEdison primarily focuses on the social and economic incentives to adopt solar as a university. They outline how young adults are getting more and more interesting in renewable energy and sustainability.
            </summary>            
            <summary type="interpretation">   
                By providing a school with a means to incur increased applications, SunEdison has appealed to schools capitalistic side, which is normally the most difficult and important aspect of persuasion in the solar market.
            </summary>
            
            <relevance type="application">
                As far as convincing Northeastern to accept this proposed change, this source should prove vital in the explanation of an all-encompassing approach. 
            </relevance>
           
        </annotation>

        
    </annotated_bib>
    
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
    
</DOC>
