<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Title of Assignment</title>
        <author xml:id="your_id_here">Your name here</author>
        <version n="num_of_version" date="2016-01-01"/>
        <!--note that the date must be YYYY-MM-DD for the document to be valid-->
    </docHead>

    <annotated_bib>
        <problem_stmt> World War II saw Americans willfully ration clothes and gasoline, plant war
            gardens, and participate in scrap metal drives to manufacture bullets. The effort on the
            home front came as an overlooked victory, proving that the nation could survive — thrive
            even — without superfluous luxuries when organized under a common cause. Although U.S.
            government’s propaganda based success to conserve resources at home was a fantastic
            accomplishment, it came with a disconcerting lesson. Without an enemy, Americans lost
            their capacity to skirt comforts for conservational purposes. As it happens, the
            overwhelming amount of research indicates that there still is an enemy — although it
            does not present itself in a swastika emblazoned SS jacket, but with climbing
            temperatures and rising sea levels — however a complicated mesh of conflicting interests
            seems to be hindering Americans from readopting the thrifty traits of their
            grandparents. The consequence is a culture that continues to increase its consumption,
            ignoring the all but certain consequences. As the speed at which items are deemed
            obsolete increases, driving the economy further toward a reliance on disposable
            commodities, the rate at which our landfills reach max capacity increases in step,
            despite our technological potential to accomplish the opposite. Further encouragement
            for America to deal more effectively with its waste addiction should come from an
            awareness of what is transpiring beyond its own shores. Population growth compounded
            with the entrance of developing countries in consumer markets guarantees that demand for
            first world commodities is to skyrocket. The amount of waste produced by such an
            increase in demand, spells uncertain questions for how factories and our environment
            will respond to this change. Luckily, a solution to our apathy might be found in new
            technologies. By levering technology to sort our waste for us, both in our home and in
            public, the current flow of thousands of tons of metals, rare earth and plastics could
            be directed out of our landfills rather than into them. This is crucial not only in
            ensuring that less waste reaches our landfills, but also in ensuring that what does
            reach our landfills does so safely. </problem_stmt>

        <!-- 1 -->
        <citation style="MLA">
            <author> Unni Eikeseth </author>
            <author> Chris Veløy </author>
            <ref>http://sciencenordic.com/machines-are-better-people-sorting-household-trash</ref>
            <title>Machines are better than people at sorting household trash</title>
        </citation>

        <annotation>
            <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
            <background type="source"> Science Nordic is an independent news site, focused on the
                coverage of scientific developments in Nordic countries. As such, their coverage of
                automated waste assortment in Norway fits nicely into the domain of the website. </background>
            <summary type="general">A broad overview is given of new waste sorting technology at a
                waste disposal plant on the outskirts of Oslo. In addition to providing coverage of
                the capabilities of the plant (in sorting between plastic and food waste), the
                article also refers back to failures in similar technology that had been attempted
                in the 1980s.</summary>
            <summary type="approach">With improvements in spectrography, infra-red sensors and
                hardware it seems the Oslo plant has found its solution. </summary>
            <summary type="interpretation">The article carries a hopeful tone both for the future of
                the Oslo plant, and for similar technologies in the world at large. </summary>
            <relevance type="value_stmt">Given the success of the technology in question, both in
                Norway and in other countries, one would hope that in 2016 this system for waste
                management would be ubiquitous and expanded upon. There is little evidence to
                suggest that this is the case, making the technology discussed still of pinnacle
                importance. </relevance>
            <relevance type="application"> Communities scouting to find functional technologies for
                their waste processing could find inspiration from the Oslo plant discussed.
            </relevance>
        </annotation>

        <!-- 2 -->
        <citation style="MLA">
            <author>Mahmudul Hasan Russel</author>
            <author>Mehdi Hasan Chowdhury</author>
            <author>Md. Shekh Naim Uddin</author>
            <author>Ashif Newaz</author>
            <author>Md. Mehdi Masud Talukder</author>
            <title>Development of Automatic Smart Waste Sorter Machine</title>
        </citation>

        <annotation>
            <background type="author">The paper's authors are a group of engineers based out of
                Bangladesh's Chittagong University and the University of Rajshashi. The authors
                present an in-depth technical report on how they sought to address the automated
                sorting of recyclable goods.</background>
            <summary type="general">The paper is broken into eight sections. The authors open with a
                broad overview of the world's waste problem, followed by discussion of potential
                resources that could be harvested from this waste. They then delve into the fine
                level details of their sorting system before resurfacing in the last three sections
                to critique their project. </summary>
            <summary type="approach">The technical solution -- detailed in sections three to five --
                discusses a replicable system of OP Amps, IR, LDR, and other components accompanied
                by flowcharts and explanations. </summary>
            <summary type="interpretation">Although the project in question doesn't address the
                issue of waste storage through a particularly novel approach, it is a logical one,
                and is fit for the task at hand. </summary>
            <relevance type="value_stmt">The issues with grammar in the paper are far outweighed by
                the technically challenging solution to a serious problem that is put on display. </relevance>
            <relevance type="application">Engineers looking for a highly detailed report on creating
                a control flow to develop sensor based systems can gain insight from this
                paper.</relevance>
        </annotation>

        <!-- 3 -->
        <citation style="MLA">
            <author>Kelsey Campbell-Dollaghan</author>
            <ref>http://gizmodo.com/this-trash-sorting-robot-could-revolutionize-recycling-511989613</ref>
            <title>This Trash-Sorting Robot Could Revolutionize Recycling</title>
        </citation>

        <annotation>
            <background type="author">Campbell-Dollaghan, a popular Gizmodo contributor, details an
                innovative approach to waste sorting specifically outfitted for use on construction
                sites created by ZenRobotics.</background>
            <summary type="general">Campbell-Dollaghan references information made public by the
                company to highlight both the innovation in market, and in methodology used by
                ZenRobotics. The article opens by making the staggering point that the construction
                center is responsible for a third of all waste created. By reintroducing the
                materials from active demolition cites into future projects, this number could be
                successfully and profitably lessened.</summary>
            <summary type="approach">Of particular interest in the article is the approach taken by
                ZenRobotics. Rather than using the more conventional servos to merely push or drop
                waste into different bins, the system relies upon a mobile arm to grab waste from a
                conveyor belt and sort it accordingly. </summary>
            <relevance type="value_stmt">What the source seems to lack is critical insight into the
                more nuanced potential of the system in question. As a result, it comes across more
                as a public service announcement for social media than as a serious intellectual
                investment. </relevance>
            <relevance type="application">Engineers looking to think outside the box can certainly
                find inspiration from within the lines of this text, however if they seek more
                in-depth knowledge they should visit the ZenRobot's website.</relevance>
        </annotation>

        <!-- 4 -->
        <citation style="MLA">
            <author> H.G. Barrow </author>
            <author>J.M. Tenenbaum </author>
            <author>R.C. Bolles </author>
            <author>H.C. Wolf </author>
            <title>Parametric Correspondence and Chamfer Matching: Two New Techniques for Image
                Matching</title>
        </citation>

        <annotation>
            <background type="author">The authors in question are all published and highly
                referenced members of the artificial intelligence community. In this instance, they
                use their knowledge of the field to discuss two areas of computer
                vision.</background>
            <summary type="general"> By combining parametric correspondence and chamfer matching,
                the researchers demonstrated a means by which a camera can automatically reorientate
                itself to a predetermined setting. </summary>
            <summary type="approach"> The paper addresses parametric correspondence as being the
                ability to distinguish the offset of an image by referencing small predetermined
                landmarks. These landmarks are identified through the use of chamfer matching.
                Chamfer matching was used to identify these landmarks due to its fast
                computation speed and resistance to lighting disturbances.</summary>
            <summary type="interpretation">Although the methods discussed have the failing of a high
                error rate in certain applications, they could be a vital tool under the right
                conditions.</summary>
            <relevance type="value_stmt">The credentials of the authors speak for themselves, as
                they make a highly complex topic both informational and accessible.</relevance>
            <relevance type="application">This paper serves as a strong display of how engineers
                might think about object recognition in a slightly unorthodox manner.</relevance>
        </annotation>

        <!-- 5 -->
        <citation style="MLA">
            <author> </author>
            <ref/>
            <title/>
        </citation>

        <annotation>
            <background type="author"/>
            <background type="source"/>
            <summary type="approach"/>
            <summary type="general"/>
            <summary type="interpretation"/>
            <relevance type="application"/>
            <relevance type="value_stmt"/>
        </annotation>

    </annotated_bib>


    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>

</DOC>
