<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title> Project 1: Annotated Bibliographies </title>
        <author xml:id="p1_s25">Leo Stolov</author>
        <version n="1" date="2016-07-13"/>
        <!--note that the date must be YYYY-MM-DD for the document to be valid-->
    </docHead>

    <annotated_bib>
        <problem_stmt> One of the unsolved problems with living in a city such as Boston is the
            process of package delivery. If a package is being delivered to a dorm, or to an
            apartment while the resident is not at home to open the door, often times it is
            redirected to a different location to be picked up at a later time. This means that the
            recipient would have to take time out of his or her day to grab the package while the
            building is operating, and carry it all the way back to its intended location. This
            major inefficiency and inconvenience can be solved if the resident knows or controls
            exactly when the package is coming, or if it comes so quickly after ordering that the
            wait time is insignificant. These solutions can be realized through the use of drone
            technology, and the use of unmanned vehicles for delivery. Drones can send real time
            information to the recipient, can be activated at any time, and can arrive at the end
            location independently of the schedule of a mail delivery worker. The successful
            implementation of drones revolves heavily on the use of sensors, and the successful
            integration of the mechanical, electrical, and software components that make them work.
            In terms of technical hurdles, autonomous vehicles must have complex control systems
            that respond quickly to any and all obstacles. These characteristics are exactly what
            the mechatronics discipline deals with, and mechatronics engineers would be integral in
            the development of this idea that could positively benefit the lives of millions of
            people. </problem_stmt>

        <citation n="1" style="APA">
            <author n="1">Brar, S.</author>
            <author n="2">Rabbat, R.</author>
            <author n="3">Raithatha, V. </author>
            <author n="4">Runcie, G.</author>
            <author n="5">Andrew Yu</author> (2015,November 8). <title level="a">Drones for
                Deliveries</title> (Rep. No. 2015.11.8). Retrieved July 13, 2016, from Sutardja
            Center for Entrepreneurship and Technology website:
            http://scet.berkeley.edu/wp-content/uploads/ConnCarProjectReport-1.pdf </citation>

        <annotation>
            <background type="source"> This paper, which was created in an open classroom
                environment within the Sutardja Center for Entrepreneurship and Technology at UC
                Berkeley, provides an in depth examination on the current climate of package
                delivery using drones. </background>
            <summary type="general"> The authors, after looking at current strategies of relevant
                companies, technological capabilities, and limitations of delivery drones, conclude
                that the idea <q>will eventually be successful in the last mile delivery
                space</q>(17). </summary>
            <relevance type="application">While the report delves heavily into the financial aspect
                of the concept, it also provides a good summation of the current state of technology
                related to drone delivery. </relevance>
            <relevance type="application">In general, it is a good resource for those looking for
                current solutions for existing technical hurdles, such as battery life, charging
                technology and flight planning, which is useful information for the design of a
                drone.</relevance>
        </annotation>

        <citation n="2" style="APA">
            <author n="1">French, S.</author> (2015, December 15). <title level="a">Drone delivery
                is already here — and it works. </title>Market Watch. Retrieved from
            http://www.marketwatch.com/story/drone-delivery-is-already-here-and-it-works-2015-11-30</citation>

        <annotation>
            <background type="author"> This article, written by drone reporter Sally French,
                explores an already existing and successful drone delivery service from a tech
                startup called Matternet. </background>
            <summary type="general"> The article breaks the process of the delivery down step by
                step, detailing some of the technical capabilities of the drone, as well as the
                technical decisions made by the company to create a successful service. </summary>
            <relevance type="application">Though the drones were implemented to only delivery
                medically related supplies in other countries, such as Switzerland, Haiti, and the
                Dominican Republic, the company is a useful case study of what goes into the
                successful application of a similar drone delivery service in other parts of the
                world. </relevance>
            <relevance type="application">For an engineer, many of the decisions made by the
                company, such as the use of landing pads on both the sending and recieving ends, can
                influence the conceptualization phase of drone design.</relevance>
        </annotation>

        <citation n="3" style="APA"><author n="1">Carr, E. B.</author> (2013, March 27). <title
                level="a">Unmanned Aerial Vehicles: Examining the Safety, Security, Privacy and
                Regulatory Issues of Integration into U.S. Airspace.</title> Retrieved from
            http://www.ncpa.org/pdfs/sp-Drones-long-paper.pdf</citation>

        <annotation>
            <background type="source"> This publication, produced by a large public policy research
                organization called the National Center for Policy Analysis, compiles past and
                current information regarding unmanned aerial systems. </background>
            <summary type="general"> The paper reviews the history of unmanned aircraft, examines a
                plethora of issues regarding the implementation of aerial drones into the national
                airspace, and concludes with a number of recommendations to work through these
                issues. </summary>
            <relevance type="application"> In terms of technical relevancy, the paper provides a
                good description of the security and privacy issues that have to be considered
                before drones can successfully be deployed in residential areas. </relevance>
            <relevance type="application">This information is especially important to those working
                on drones within cities, since it can help set a threshold for what it means for a
                drone design to be safe in public places.</relevance>
        </annotation>

        <citation n="4" style="APA">
            <author n="1">Bacon, J.</author> (2016, February 25). <title level="a">Special delivery:
                Ground drones coming to America.</title> USA Today. Retrieved from
            http://www.usatoday.com/story/tech/2016/02/23/special-delivery-ground-drones-ready-roll-england/80792992/</citation>

        <annotation>
            <background type="author"> This relatively recent article, written by USA Today
                journalist John Bacon, informs of a British company named Starship Technologies and
                their development of a land based delivery drone. </background>
            <summary type="general"> The article provides an overview of the service, and details
                some of the technical decisions made by the company, such as a four mile an hour
                travel speed, real time tracking of the vehicle by the customer, and use of cameras
                for human oversight for theft prevention.</summary>
            <relevance type="application"> Even though the company is still in the testing phase of
                their service, this source provides an excellent case study for the initial
                implementation of land drones for package delivery, a not so common approach to
                last-mile delivery. </relevance>
        </annotation>

        <citation n="5" style="APA">
            <author n="1">Amzajerdian, F.</author>
            <author n="2">Pierrottet, D.</author>
            <author n="3">Petway, L.</author>
            <author n="4">Vanek, M.</author>
            <title level="a">DEVELOPMENT OF LIDAR SENSOR SYSTEMS FOR AUTONOMOUS SAFE LANDING ON
                PLANETARY BODIES </title>[Scholarly project]. Retrieved July 13, 2016, from
            http://ntrs.nasa.gov/archive/nasa/casi.ntrs.nasa.gov/20100036247.pdf</citation>

        <annotation>
            <background type="source"> This report, produced by the esteemed NASA Langley Research
                Center, describes the development of Lidar sensors under the Autonomous Landing and
                Hazard Avoidance project. </background>
            <summary type="general">The paper describes three different Lidar sensors and details
                their individual functions and capabilities as they relate to future missions
                involving precision landings on the Moon or Mars. </summary>
            <summary type="approach">The authors provide technical diagrams and quantifiable data to
                thoroughly characterize these Lidar systems.</summary>
            <relevance type="application">While the report is focused solely on applications for
                landing on planetary bodies, the technical features of the sensors, which include
                the generation of elevation maps, hazardous feature avoidance, and highly accurate
                ground velocity, distance, altitude, and attitude data, are all very relevant to and
                can be used for the application of delivery drone technology. </relevance>
        </annotation>
    </annotated_bib>


    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>

</DOC>
