<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>MBTA Train System Space Issue</title>
        <author xml:id="v27">Djordje Vlajkovic</author>
        <version n="1" date="2016-07-13"/>
    </docHead>
    
    <annotated_bib>
        <problem_stmt>In today's Boston, an outdated public transportation system known as the MBTA is using older model train cars to transport its passengers. The limited amount of space in these cars fill up quickly and 
        eventually there is nowhere for these people to go. This leads to delays and extremely uncomfortable conditions in which riders must endure on their commutes. The lack of space can also lead to the spread of
        bacteria, germs and viruses that could infected commuters who are squished together like packed sardines. It is crucial that this problem be addressed because this form of transportation is 
        used by many who find it to be the most practical and affordable way to travel around the city. But with proper help in the mechanical engineering discipline and funding, these issues can be resolved. This solution will lead to an
        an outcome where the transportation service will provide a more comfortable, healthier and enjoyable experience for customers.
        </problem_stmt>
        <citation style="APA"><author>Grabar, H.</author> 
            (2016, February 12). <title>Subway Cars Should Be Like Centipedes.</title> 
            Retrieved July 11, 2016, from http://www.slate.com/articles/business/metropolis/2016/02/subways_should_have_open_gangway_cars_why_does_the_u_s_resist_it.html </citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="source">This article by the Slate, a popular magazine that examines
            and analyzes issues in today's society,</background>
            <summary type="general">takes a look into the space situation with subway systems in America. The article first examines why subway cars are becoming so overcrowded in these American cities compared to other global cities. Then it 
                looks at the solutions these other cities like Paris, Tokyo and Toronto have come up with to fix this issue. There are also examinations into methods like taking out seating which would provide more space and
            allow the trains to move faster without the extra weight.</summary>
            <relevance type="application">What the author finds to be the best solution to improving the space in these subway cars is having gangway trains instead of the string of separate cars
              that attach to one and another. The article goes on to say that these gangway trains have shown encouraging results and do show an effect on the crowdedness of these train systems.</relevance>
        </annotation>
        
        <citation style="APA"><author>Annear, S.</author> (2013, October 22).
        <title>MBTA Orange Line Trains Will Be Replaced, Red Line Vehicles Added.</title>
            Retrieved July 11, 2016,from http://www.bostonmagazine.com/news/blog/2013/10/22/mbta-ornage-line-trains-upgrades-red-line-governor-patrick/</citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="author">The article, written by Steve Annear a digital writer at Boston Magazine and former writer at Boston Metro newspaper, </background>
            <summary type="general">discusses the newly passed bill that will improve the MBTA system. The article discusses how the MBTA will be <q>replacing the entire fleet of 120 Orange Line cars, and 74 Red Line cars,</q> 
             which will provide more seating and space for riders. The article goes on to discuss the planned timetable for these improvements which were estimated to go into effect by 2019.
            </summary>
            <relevance type="application"> For people already using the subway and train systems these new additions to the Orange and Red line will provide them with a more comfortable riding experience. These new improvements 
                may also lead to more timely and accurate scheduling that will lead to less delays and faster commutes.
            </relevance>
        </annotation>
        
        <citation style="APA"><author>Gans, F.</author> (2015, December 22).<title> MBTA Riders Demand Improvements in Service amid Fare Hike Plan.</title> The Boston Globe (Boston, MA). 
            Retrieved July 12, 2016, from https://www.bostonglobe.com/metro/2015/12/22/next-stop-resistance-prospect-higher-fares/2MSl8eUccvmczziTtY9haP/story.html</citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="source">
                This article from the Boston Globe, one of the most prestigious newspaper companies in the country,
            </background>
            <summary type="general">takes a look into the new fare hikes by the MBTA and overall reception by their customers. First the article goes into the 10 percent hike increase
                and the frequency at which these prices are going up at. When interviewing some of the riders of the MBTA, the reception was seen be as negative, as one rider put it, <q>It’s not 
                a big amount, but think ahead. If every 24 months they keep on raising it, one day, it’s going to be $40 a week. And then one day, it’s going to be $50 a week. I don’t know why 
                they can’t just keep it a normal fare</q>. Later the article goes on to examine the demand by the customers for improved services, but also acknowledges that people are skeptical of these
                upcoming improvements.
            </summary>
            <relevance type="value_stmt">It seems as if the author was able to understand and amplify the overall reception and feeling of the public.    
            </relevance>
        </annotation>
        
        <citation style="APA"><author>McDonald, C.</author> (2016, June 28). <title>Meet The Germs Sharing Your Seat On The Subway.</title> Retrieved July 12, 2016, from 
            http://www.popsci.com/subway-bugs-boston</citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="source">Popular Science, a long running, award winning magazine that finds all of the new and most popular topics in the science community, 
            </background>
            <summary type="approach">takes a look at the microbes and germs that infest the inside of a subway cars in large cities. First the author goes through previous studies done by 
                researches in cities like San Francisco and New York who took samples from subway cars and were able to find a plethora of germs and microbes that exist within these trains. From there it goes 
                on to talk about how recently in Boston, a research team went to examine some of these subway cars where they collected and analyzed the samples they acquired. From there it divulges into more of
                 the research, examining the results and what actually exists in these subway cars.
            </summary>
            <relevance type="application"> The article brings more awareness to the idea that public transportation can be a simple way of contracting these germs and bugs from other individuals. What can be
                done to prevent this is having these systems to implement improvements that will provide less opportunities for these germs to spread and grow.
            </relevance>
        </annotation>
        
        <citation style="APA"><author>Fishbein, R.</author> (2016, May 3).<title> Report: The Subway Is Crowded and Getting More Crowded So Please Everyone Stop Moving To NYC.</title>
            Retrieved July 12, 2016, from http://gothamist.com/2016/05/03/sorry_guys_at_capacity.php</citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="author">The author, Rebecca Fishbein, who is an associate editor and writer at the Gothamist 
            </background>
            <summary type="general">addresses the overcrowding crisis found in subway systems. The story goes more in depth with the issue in New York City, where this has been a reoccurring problem for years and how 
                it is only getting worse. The article talks about the upcoming projects that should address this issue,</summary><summary type="interpretation">but then shows skepticism on whether or not it will actually ever happen. 
                Throughout the piece there is continual jest at the New York subway city and the overcrowding epidemic.</summary>
            <relevance type="application"> The message that is being sent to all people living in large metropolitan areas, who use public transportation is to apply pressure on the officials running these transportation 
                systems. It is a calling to make the people's voices be heard and react the diminishing quality of public transportation.
            </relevance>
        </annotation>
    </annotated_bib>
    
    
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
    
</DOC>
