<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Writing Project 1</title>
        <author xml:id="v26">Michael Van Wickle</author>
        <version n="1" date="2016-07-13"/>
        <!--note that the date must be YYYY-MM-DD for the document to be valid-->
    </docHead>
    
    <annotated_bib> 
        <problem_stmt>
            Many members of the populace of the city of Boston, along with the United States and the World, do not have access to the benefits of modern technology.
            The problem stems from systemic inequality which is well beyond the scope of this class, or any single discipline.
            Reducing the problem to just that of the distribution of technology, it becomes more manageable.
            A simple statement of the problem: how could the distribution of technology expand to the disparate of the world?
            The following will focus on possible litigious or business facing solutions.
        </problem_stmt>
       
        <citation n="1" style="IEEE">
            <author n="1">Thomas, J.</author>, (2013).
            "<title level="a">Association for Molecular Pathology et al. v. Myriad Genetics et al.</title>."
            <title level="j">United States Reports</title>. 569. Available: http://www.supremecourt.gov/opinions/12pdf/12-398_1b7d.pdf.
        </citation>
        <annotation>This judgement,
            <background type="source">rendered by the Supreme Court of the United States, the highest court in the United States,</background>
            <summary type="general">deals with the patentability of isolated deoxyriboneucleic acid (DNA). Decided by the court, was that isolated DNA was not patentable.</summary>
            <summary type="general">It more broadly deals with the patentability of <q>laws of nature, natural phenomena, and abstract ideas</q>(2)</summary>.
            <relevance type="application">This judgement, while not exactly perfectly to the problem, could be used as a model argument against such patented technologies that some may view as human rights or fundamental to life.</relevance>
        </annotation>
       
        <citation n="2" style="IEEE">
            <author n="1">United Nations Human Rights Council</author>. (2016, June, 27).
            "<title level="a">The promotion, protection, and enjoyment of human rights on the Internet</title>."
            <title level="j">United Nations General Assembly</title>. 32nd Session. Agenda item 3. Available: http://www.un.org/ga/search/view_doc.asp?symbol=A/HRC/32/L.20.
        </citation>
        <annotation>This statement,
            <background type="source"> from the United Nations (UN) Human Rights Council, which deals with the promotion and protection of human rights worldwide,</background>
            <summary type="general">broadly states that access to the internet is a "universal" right.</summary>
            <summary type="general"></summary>
            <relevance type="value_stmt">This declaration is non-binding, meaning that it does not compel member states to act. However, it does represent the conviction of the UN that internet access is a fundamental human right.</relevance> 
        </annotation>
        
        <citation n="3" style="IEEE">
            <author n="1">Circuit Judge Tatel</author> and <author n="2">Circuit Judge Srinivasan</author>. (2016, June 14).
            "<title level="a">United States Telecom Association et al. v. Federal Communications Commission and United States of America</title>."
            <title level="j">United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit</title>. 15-1063. 
        </citation>
        <annotation>This judgement,
            <background type="source">from the District of Colombia Circuit, a court on the second highest level in the United States,</background>
            <summary type="general">states that the an order from the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) is valid. The order stated, generally, that broadband service providers must treat all network traffic the same.</summary>
            <summary type="general">The FCC order essentially ensured that internet providers follow the rules of "net neutrality" which has been a governing principle since its inception.</summary>
            <relevance type="application">This judgement and the order that it upheld could be used to prevent internet providers from throttling internet connection speeds to the lower classes of society.</relevance>
        </annotation>
       
        <citation n="4" style="IEEE">
            <author n="1">Daron Acemoglu</author>. (2003).
            "<title level="a">Technology and Inequality</title>,"
            <title level="j">National Bureau of Economic Research Reporter</title>. Winter 2003. Available: http://www.nber.org/reporter/winter03/technologyandinequality.html
        </citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="source">The National Bureau of Economic Research (NBER) is a United States based organization focusing on non-biased economic research.</background>
            This paper <summary type="general">gives a high level overview of the causes of inequality with respect to technology.</summary>
            <relevance type="application">This paper could be used, by analyzing the enumerated problems, in an attempt to reverse some inequalities.</relevance>
        </annotation>
      
        <citation n="5" style="IEEE">
            <author n="1">C.K. Prahalad</author> and <author n="2">Allen Hammond</author>. (2002)
            "<title level="a">Serving the World's Poor, Profitably</title>."
            <title level="j">Harvard Business Review</title>. September 2002. Available: http://www.hbr.org/2002/09/serving-the-worlds-poor-profitably.
        </citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="source">The Harvard Business Review is a publication affiliated with Harvard University.</background>
            <summary type="general">This article lists ways that large businesses could help the disparate of the world while also serving their own interests.</summary>
            <relevance type="application">The ideas laid out in this piece could be used as a template for multi-national corporations as they attempt to start human-rights programs.</relevance>
        </annotation>
    </annotated_bib>
    
    
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
    
</DOC>
