<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>MBTA Train System Space Issue</title>
        <author xml:id="v27">Djordje Vlajkovic</author>
        <version n="1" date="2016-07-11"/>
    </docHead>
    
    <annotated_bib>
        <problem_stmt>In Boston today an outdated public transporation system known as the MBTA is
        using older train cars to hold its passengers. The space in these cars fill up quickly and 
        eventually there is no where for these people to go.
        </problem_stmt>
        <citation n="1" style="APA"><author>Grabar, H.</author>
            (2016, February 12).<title>Subway Cars Should Be Like Centipedes</title>
                Retrieved July 11, 2016,from http://www.slate.com/articles/business/metropolis/2016/02/subways_should_have_open_gangway_cars_why_does_the_u_s_resist_it.html </citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="source">This article by the Slate, a popular magazine that examines
            and analyzes issues in today's society,</background>
            <summary type="general">takes a look at space situation with subway systems in America.
                The article first examines why subway cars are becoming so overcrowded in these American
            cities. Afterwards it looks at the solutions other cities like Paris, Tokyo and Toronto have done
            to fix this issue.</summary>
            <relevance type="application">What the author finds to be the best solution to improving the space
              in these subway cars is having gangway trains instead of the string of separate cars
              that attach to one and another.</relevance>
        </annotation>
        
        <citation style="APA"><author>Annear, S.</author>(2013, October 22).
        <title>MBTA Orange Line Trains Will Be Replaced, Red Line Vehicles Added.</title>
            Retrieved July 11, 2016,from http://www.bostonmagazine.com/news/blog/2013/10/22/mbta-ornage-line-trains-upgrades-red-line-governor-patrick/</citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="author">The article, written by Steve Annear a digital writer at Boston Magazine
            graduate from Roger Williams University former writer at Boston Metro newspaper,</background>
            <summary type="general">
            discusses the newly passed bill that will improve the MBTA system. The article discusses how both the Orange
            and Red line will both have new sets of vehicles that will provide more seating and space for riders. The 
            planned timetable for these improvements are to be avaliable by 2019.
            </summary>
            <relevance type="application">For people already using the subway and train systems these new additions
                to the Orange and Red line will provide them a more comfortable riding experience. These new improvements 
                may also lead to more timely and accurate scheduling that will lead to less delays and faster commutes.
            </relevance>
        </annotation>
        
        <citation style="APA"><author>Gans, F.</author>(2015, December 22).
            <title>MBTA Riders Demand Improvements in Service amid Fare Hike Plan.</title>The Boston Globe (Boston, MA).
            Retrieved July 12, 2016, from https://www.bostonglobe.com/metro/2015/12/22/next-stop-resistance-prospect-higher-fares/2MSl8eUccvmczziTtY9haP/story.html</citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="source">
                This article from the Boston Globe, one of the most well known newspaper companies in the country,
            </background>
            <summary type="general">takes a look into the new fare hikes by the MBTA and overall reception by their customers. First the article goes into the 10 percent hike increase
                and the frequency at which these prices are going up at. When interviewing some of the riders of the MBTA, the reception was seen be as negative, as one rider put it <q>"It’s not 
                a big amount, but think ahead. If every 24 months they keep on raising it, one day, it’s going to be $40 a week. And then one day, it’s going to be $50 a week. I don’t know why 
                they can’t just keep it a normal fare”.</q> Later the article goes on to examine the demand by the customers for improved services, but also acknowledges that people are skeptical of these
                upcoming improvements.
            </summary>
            <relevance type="value_stmt">It seems as if the author was able to find the sway of the public was moving towards in the sense of the situation.    
            </relevance>
        </annotation>
        
        <citation style="APA"><author>McDonald, C.</author>(2016, June 28). <title>Meet The Germs Sharing Your Seat On The Subway.</title>Retrieved July 12, 2016, from 
            http://www.popsci.com/subway-bugs-boston</citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="source">Popular Science, a long running, prestigious magazine that finds all of the new and most revelant topics in the science community,
            </background>
            <summary type="approach">=takes a look at the microbes and germs that can be found all over the inside of a subway car. First the author goes through previous studies done by 
                researches in cities like San Francisco and New York took samples from subway cars and were able to find a plethora of germs and microbes that exist within these areas. The articles goes 
                on to talk about how recently in Boston research team went to examine some of these subway cars and collect and analysis the samples they acquired. From there it divulges into more of
                 a research and science background examining the results and what actually exists in these areas.
            </summary>
            <relevance type="application"> The article brings more awareness to idea that public transporation can be a simple way of contracting these germs and bugs from other individuals. What can be
                done is for these systems to implement improvements that will provide less opportunity for these germs to spread and grow.
            </relevance>
        </annotation>
        
        <citation style="APA"><author>Fishbein, R.</author>(2016, May 3).<title>Report: The Subway Is Crowded and Getting More Crowded So Please Everyone Stop Moving To NYC.</title>
            Retrieved July 12, 2016, from http://gothamist.com/2016/05/03/sorry_guys_at_capacity.php</citation>
        <annotation>
            <background type="author">The author, Rebecca Fishbein, who is an associate editor and writer at the Gothamist 
            </background>
            <summary type="general">addresses the overcrowding crisis found in the subway system. The story goes more in depth with problem, going into how this has been a reoccuring problem for years and how 
                it is only getting worse. 
            </summary>
            <relevance type="application"> This piece is a message to all people living in large metropolitian areas who use public transportation to apply pressure on the officials running these transportation 
                systems. It is a calling to make the people's voices be heard and react the dimishing quality of public transportation.
            </relevance>
        </annotation>
    </annotated_bib>
    
    
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
    
</DOC>
