<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Project 2: Feasibility Study</title>
        <author xml:id="b11">Your name here</author>
        <version n="num_of_version" date="2016-08-01"/>
    </docHead>
    
    <fsb_rpt>
        <!-- Title Page, Page 1 -->
        <page type="ttl">
            
            <contributors>Seth Bakes</contributors>
            <date>01 August 2016</date>
            <title>Revamping MyNEU COOL</title>
            
        </page>
        
        <!-- Table of Contents, Page 2 -->
        <page type="tbl_contents">
            
            <sect lvl="1" n="1">Executive Summary</sect>
            <sect lvl="1" n="2">Prelimainary Requirements Analysis</sect>
                <sect lvl="2" n="1">Objectives</sect>
                <sect lvl="2" n="2">Rules</sect>
                <sect lvl="2" n="3">Interactions with existing infastructure </sect>
            <sect lvl="1" n="3">Success Criteria</sect>
            <sect lvl="1" n="4">Cost Estimates</sect>
                <sect lvl="2" n="1">Programmers</sect>
                <sect lvl="2" n="2">Hardware</sect>
            <sect lvl="1" n="5">Reporting Outline</sect>
            <sect lvl="1" n="6">Conclusion</sect>
        </page>
        
        <!-- Executive Summary, Page 3 -->
        <page type="exec_sum"> Northeastern University is well known for our
            exceptional co-op program. As it stands, we are not representing this 
            program well. The purpose of this project is to create a new web portal
            to replace the current MyNEU COOL. As a software <note type="peer" resp="#c12">student</note>studnet here at Northeastern
            University I am wholy committed to this project and believe it can be done in 
            a reasonable timeframe. There are few limitations to the project (The major
            being reliable co-op position liasons), and tangible benefits. The revamping
            of our web portal will put a new face on the NEU co-op search process and 
            encourage our students to use the service, in turn <note type="peer" resp="#c12">yielding</note>yeilding more support for
            our student feedback database and overall improvements to the co-op process on 
            the faculty and student end. 
        </page>
        
        <!-- Preliminary Requirements Analysis, Page 4 -->
        <page type="pre_req_ana">
            
            <app_ovr type="obj">Co-op search <note type="peer" resp="#c12">improvements</note>iprovements: The primary objective of this
                project is to improve the overall quality of the co-op search process. This process
                is undertaken by the overwhelming majority of students, making this a very visible
                improvement on the part of the <note type="peer" resp="#c12">*lowercase* university</note>University. The goal is <note type="peer" resp="#c12">in part -- add space</note>inpart to increase user feedback,
                make the process easier and more intuitive, overall replace and improve what is generally 
                considered a poor service. 
            </app_ovr>
            
            <app_ovr type="obj">Experiential Learning: As students of the University, this
                project will help provide valuable development experience to multiple <note type="peer" resp="#c12">students</note>studnets.
                This includes students from different majors collaborating for a full cross discipline
                project. This exemplifies Northeastern's experiential learning goals, and creates student
                involvement.
            </app_ovr>
            
            <app_ovr type="rls">Graphic Identity: The design <note type="peer" resp="#c12">add space betweent "and" and "implementation"</note>andimplementation of this web 
                portal will uphold Northeastern University's expectations for colors, logos,
                and branding. <note type="peer" resp="#c12">Should probably add "The" to make it a complete sentence.</note>Primary colors used will be Northeastern Red (CC0000), Warm Grey 
                11 (615445), and Black (000000), along with the thematic <note type="peer" resp="#c12">*capitalize* Northeastern</note>northeastern header standard
                on all digital frontend space. 
            </app_ovr>
            
            <app_ovr type="synergy">Existing myNEU COOL: This portal will require all of the 
                <note type="peer" resp="#c12">perhaps expand on what this previous info is?</note>previous information in the system to work. This is make transition rather seamless, 
                and allow for users to keep the information they are accustomed too. The goal here
                is to prevent users from having to relearn a new system, rather they will immediately
                know how to use it. 
            </app_ovr>
            
        </page>
        
        <!-- Success Criteria, Page 5 -->
        <page type="sccs_crt">
            
            <req_sect>User Interactions
                <req n="1">Seamless transition: Our new <note type="peer" resp="#c12">Consistency with capitalization of "web portal" in the Success Criteria Section</note>Web portal must be able to utilize all of the 
                    existing MyNEU COOL data. This includes co-op reviews, individual user preferences, and 
                    just the list of jobs itself. These aspects of COOL will not be changed, so that users
                    experience no loss of the past functionality.   
                </req>
                <req n="2">Improved Feedback: The web portal will only be considered a success if feedback
                    from students and faculty shows an improved satisfaction. This includes not only improved
                    levels of student feedback within the system (co-op reviews) but also of the overall sentiment
                    towards the service. 
                </req>
            </req_sect>
            
            <req_sect>Technical  
                <req n="1"> Interactions with existing Systems: This Web Portal must integrate
                    with the existing database models supporting MyNEU COOL. The only backend changes deemend
                    acceptable are those aimed at improving database interactionationary tools on the user end. This
                    may include changing the type of database used, but all the data will have to be migrated. 
                </req> 
                <req n="2">Improved navigability and new features: The new MyNEU web Portal will allow for new ways to interact
                    with the co-op database, and make it more straight forward to use the existing filters. On top of adding new filters, 
                    the web portal will have a new feedback system.
                </req>
            </req_sect>
        
        </page>
        
        <!-- Cost Estimates, Page 6 -->
        <page type="cost">
            
            <est type="fnc"> Developers: The project's main cost will be the wage of 5 Northeastern University Students. They will be 
                paid a negotiable group upon <note type="peer" resp="#c12">beginning</note>beggining the project, and another upon successful implementation and approval of their web portal. 
            </est>
            
            <est type="fnc"> Hardware: The project's implementation may require new or updated hardware. This is yet to be determined, but every effort
                will be made to use the existing hardware.
            </est>
           
        </page>
        
        <!-- Reporting Outline, Page 7 -->
        <page type="rpt">
            
            <tmln date="2016-09-01">Research and design Phase Begins: The development team will begin researching and drafting designs for the portal and its 
                aesthetics. </tmln>
            
            <tmln date="2016-10-01">Initial Design up for Approval: mockups of the actual page will be presented. Presentation will also include 
                any believed changes to the database. Sample data will be taken from the current database for example usage. </tmln>
            
            <tmln date="2016-10-02">Project will begin development after official design undergoes approval. This includes slowly migrating 
                parts of the current MyNEU COOL database to the sytem for testing. Bi weekly IPR (In progress review) will be held with the same
                liason staff.</tmln>
            
            <tmln date="2016-10-14">IPR #1</tmln>
            
            <tmln date="2016-10-28">IPR #2: Demo included for staff usage.</tmln>
            
            <tmln date="2016-11-14">IPR #3: Student feedback requested.</tmln>
            
            <tmln date="2016-11-28">IPR #4: Demo included for staff usage. </tmln>
            
            <tmln date="2016-12-05">Final approval: Projected timeframe for seeking final design approval. This will include an in-depth trial of the web portal
                with migrated data. Students from NEU will attend and provide feedback. </tmln>
            
            <tmln date="2016-12-10">Integration and integration testing: The service will be replaces and we will be monitoring it constantly for errors or unexpected
                behavior.</tmln>
            
        </page>
        
        <!-- Conclusion, Page 8 -->
        <page type="conc">       
            
            <fsb>The project is feasible. All of the students working on it have web development experience and with the provided timeframe of three months
                we are fully confident that this project can be completed, on time. The addition of student feedback throughout the process increases our ability
                to create the ideal improvements, securing the valuable student approval. We are also provided in-depth views for NEU staff and increasing our availabilty
                for feedback.</fsb>
            
            <cond>The only condiftion is that our timeline not be shortened. This timeline is already short for a standard web package development, and any attempts
                to rush the product compromise the result. That being said, the team is confident it can be delivered on time on the condition that new hardware is not 
                needed to host the service. In the event that we need to purchase new hardware the timeline may be increased, or we can look into external hosting.</cond>
            
            <sum> In summary, this project will provide Northeastern University with a valuable <note type="peer" resp="#c12">student</note>studnet experiential learning program and improve a widely used
                service. It is no secret that our current co-op database (MyNEU COOL) is antiquated, and studnet feedback is very low. By developing a replacement web
                portal and migrating all of the current data, we can improve that service without <note type="peer" resp="#c12">losing</note>loosing any aspect of the service that students are accustomed too. 
                By minimizing changes to the current system's underworkings and instead "re-skinning" it, we can avoid a costly experience, and utilize our current
                system in the improvement.</sum>
            
        </page>
    </fsb_rpt>
    
<!--paste body of your template file here-->
        
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="c12"/>
        <report type="peer" resp="#c12">
            <p>This is a feasibility report on redoing the myNEU COOL co-op web application. It is a
            response to student's negative opinions of the current application which is in need of
            an overhaul.
            
            I think that my main issue is the lack of any feasibility section. I see requirements and success criteria, 
            but I don't see anything analyzing the actual feasibility of the project. 
            The feasibility is touched upon in different sections like requirements and success criteria 
            so a main feasibility section may feel redundant to you. Should the elements that make it
            feasible be explicitly layed out or should the reader be able to infer based on the requirements? We have 
            a page type="fsb" where one could list the different types of feasibility examined and this is
            what I used. I think that this is one of the most important sections where you can convince readers why it is 
            feasible or not depending on the current financial situation or current technical abilities of the students.
            
            A quick fix that I think you could add would be to add a subtitle of Feasibility Report to the 
            title page. Another simple fix: Table of Contents under Cost Estimate says Programmers but
            the section title is Developers. One thing that I like in your report is how everything seems to be bulleted or 
            within sections rather than in paragraphs. It makes the sections that you are highlighting 
            stand out and your point is clearly conveyed.
            
            In the executive summary, you say that as a software student, you're fully committed to the project
            and think that it could get done in a reasonable timeframe. Reading from the outside this kind of 
            seems like there could be some bias in the paper. With yourself being committed to the project, it
            could seem like you would maybe want to over or under-represent the facts to make it seem like 
            the project is more feasible than it actually is. Perhaps a less personal approach to the paper
            would make sense.
            
            In the reporting section, we may want to ask Kevin to add dates for the different "tmln" elements,
            as they don't show up on the formatted document. Also, we may want to ask Kevin to allow multiple "reqt_sect"
            elements in the Success criteria section, as Oxygen is saying your second one isn't valid.
            </p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>