<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Writing Project 2</title>
        <author xml:id="c12">Brent Christy</author>
        <version n="2" date="2016-08-01"/>
    </docHead>

    <fsb_rpt>
        <page type="ttl">
            <title>Boston Traffic Signal Neural Network</title>
            <subTitle>Feasibility Report</subTitle>
            <date>August 1st, 2016</date>
            <contributors>Brent Christy</contributors>
        </page>
        <page type="tbl_contents">
            <sect n="1" lvl="1">Executive Summary</sect>
            <sect n="2" lvl="1">Preliminary Requirements</sect>
            <sect n="3" lvl="1">Feasibility</sect>
            <sect n="1" lvl="2">Technical</sect>
            <sect n="2" lvl="2">Economic</sect>
            <sect n="6" lvl="1">Success Criteria</sect>
            <sect n="7" lvl="1">Design</sect>
            <sect n="8" lvl="1">Cost Estimate</sect>
            <sect n="9" lvl="1">Risk Analysis</sect>
            <sect n="10" lvl="1">Conclusion</sect>
        </page>

        <page type="exec_sum">A network linked traffic signal control system is proposed throughout
            the city of Boston. The network will autonomously adjust traffic signal timing depending
            on the current traffic conditions. The goal of using autonomously adjusting traffic
            signals as opposed to timed signals is to reduce the amount of time spent in traffic in
            the city. Less time spent in traffic will result in lower fossil fuel emissions as well
            as a higher quality of life for commuters. The current traffic signal system in Boston
            is well set up to be adapted and take on the proposed neural network system of signals. </page>

        <page type="pre_req_ana">
            <app_ovr type="obj">The objective of the proposed system is to provide an overall
                decrease in traffic throughout the city of Boston, especially during peak travel
                times.</app_ovr>
            <app_ovr type="synergy"> The proposed system will utilize the current traffic control
                system which has central control of 544 of 845 lights operated by the Boston
                Transportation Department
                    <ref>https://www.cityofboston.gov/images_documents/TMC%20Annual%20Report%20FY2013_tcm3-40150.pdf</ref>.
                The program will also utilize several sensors present at some stop lights throughout
                the city.</app_ovr>
            <app_ovr type="rls">The proposed system will have to comply will all state and federal
                laws regarding traffic signals.</app_ovr>
        </page>

        <page type="fsb">
            <fsb_hlgt type="tcnl"> The proposed neural network will require several improvements to
                the current control system. Currently, most traffic signals are controlled by preset
                timers. These timers are set by traffic control engineers once every five years
                after observing traffic for several days. The other traffic signals use both the
                timers and some sensors to determine how many cars are currently at the
                intersection. For the neural network traffic system, three major actions will need
                to take place. First, the remaining 301 of 845 lights will need to be connected to
                the central traffic system. This will allow the central program to control all
                lights in the city. Second, sensors will have to be places at large intersections in
                the city. These sensors will tell the central network how many cars are at major
                intersections and allow the network to adjust traffic flow depending on this
                traffic. The sensors can be applied either on traffic poles or underneath the
                pavement. As there will be a fairly large number of sensors, most will have to be
                applied to poles as the roads should not be dug up. Last, the neural network will
                need to be implemented. This neural network will be connected to all of the traffic
                lights and receive the sensor data from the main intersections. The network can
                leverage several papers already written on the subject of traffic control with
                neural networks. </fsb_hlgt>
            <fsb_hlgt type="econ">The effective costs of the project will go to three categories:
                connecting the lights to the central network, adding sensors to main intersections,
                and coding the neural network. The majority of the cost will go towards the
                development of the neural network. Based on the Boston Transportation Department's
                current budget, there is a sizeable amount of money that could be used towards these
                purposes each year over the course of the next ten years. </fsb_hlgt>
        </page>

        <page type="sccs_crt">
            <req_sect>Installation
                <req n="1" title="Central Network"> All traffic lights must be connected to a central network.
                This will allow all signals to be controlled by the neural network implemented in a central
                location.</req>
                <req n="2" title="Sensors Installed"> Pressure and visual sensors must be added to 
                high traffic volume intersections throughout the city. This will allow the neural
                network to adjust the signal timings based on current conditions.</req>
            </req_sect>
            
            <req_sect>Software Components
                <req n="3" title="Autonomously operating"> The timing system must be able to 
                autonomously operate. Once implemented, the traffic control system should
                not require human input unless under extreme circumstances. It should be able to 
                learn from previous traffic situations and improve its handling of traffic flow
                in these situations. </req>
                <req n="4" title="Current Condition Adjustment"> The traffic control system must be able
                to adjust the timings of lights based on the current conditions. Based on the
                inputs from sensors at different locations in the city, the traffic control system should 
                change the timing.</req>
            </req_sect>
        </page>

        <page type="dsn">
            <img
                url="http://image.slidesharecdn.com/neuralnetworkforreal-timetrafficsignalcontrol-150206235042-conversion-gate02/95/neural-network-for-real-time-traffic-signal-control-7-638.jpg?cb=1423266888"
                >Neural Network Structure</img>
        </page>

        <page type="cost">
            <est type="fnc">$5,000 per light to connect each to the central network. (301 lights) =
                $1,505,000</est>
            <est type="fnc">$2,000 per intersection that needs sensors (50 intersections) =
                $100,000</est>
            <est type="fnc">$500,000 to develop neural network</est>
        </page>

        <page type="rpt">
            <tmln date="2017-01-01" n="1"> Neural Network Development: The software team will begin neural network
            development. </tmln>
            
            <tmln date="2017-03-01"> Sensor Installation: Sensors will begin to be installed at major
            intersections.</tmln>
            
            <tmln date="2017-03-15"> Connection of lights: Unconnected lights will begin to be connected
            to the central network.</tmln>
            
            <tmln date="2017-06-01"> Neural Network Check-In: The neural network team should have a working
            model by this point. It should be tested with model data to check accuracy. At this point,
            some sensors will be installed at major intersections and the network can begin to learn.</tmln>
            
            <tmln date="2017-11-01"> Installation and Connection Check-in: 150 of the previously disconnected
                lights should be connected to the central network at this point. All sensors should be installed
                at major intersections.
            </tmln>
            
            <tmln date="2017-12-01"> Neural Network Implementation Roll-out: Traffic signals will start to be
            controlled by the neural network at this point. </tmln>
        </page>

        <page type="rsk_ana"> There are several potential risks to this system. One risk is lights
            getting disconnected from the central system. This can be combated by having preset
            timers as backups to the network timing. Preset timers is the current format, so this
            backup would not add much extra work to the system. Another risk is the introduction of
            self driving cars. Self driving cars may eliminate the need for traffic signals which
            would prove the system useless. In order for traffic signals to become useless, all cars
            would need to be autonomous. This is not likely to happen, as there are many cars on the
            that people will want to continue to drive despite the availability of autonomously
            driving cars.
        </page>

        <page type="conc">
            <fsb>Given the current budget and technology, it appears to be reasonable to complete
                this task within the proposed ten year time frame. With much research already done
                on the subject of neural networks, it would be reasonable to create over the course
                of several years.</fsb>
            <cond>Despite budget concerns throughout the city, this would be a good allocation of
                funds to increase the quality of life of workers around the area.</cond>
            <sum>The project appears to be technically feasible in that all proposed actions can be
                completed given the correct time and resources. Given some room in the Boston
                Transportation Department's budget, there is also enough monetary resources for the
                project to work. Last, the large time period proposed for the project will allow the
                system to be implemented in a timely manor. Overall, it appears reasonable that the
                system can be implemented.</sum>
        </page>

    </fsb_rpt>

    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="m20">Chi Mo</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" resp="#m20">
            <p> After reading this feasibility report about the traffic lights neural network, I can
                see that the feasibility report is well organized and easy to understand. After a
                glance, the report looks feasible. It looks like the author is trying to make the
                Boston’s traffic signal more efficient. I don’t understand where does the number 544
                of traffic lights come from? It doesn’t have any explanation of it. It has two
                feasibility pages which I’m confused so I went through the XML page and realized
                that they are in different types. I feel like it can be one page with two
                paragraphs. In this draft, it doesn’t have the report page and financial page. I
                think it won’t hurt to have these two pages since they are the part of the schema
                and may influence the audience’s decision after they read the report. In the risk
                analysis page, the author should not only mention the risk but also explain how will
                this project reduce some of the risk. You can’t let people know the risk but no
                solving plans to it. Also, how is the current Boston traffic signal set up? Why does
                it need to be changed into a neural network? I think it will be better if the author
                mentioned these. The author uses most of the schema in the same way that we think
                when we develop the schema. In the success criteria, I’m not sure it we need more
                words to explain it or just do the same as the author did in bullet points? The
                schema is well formed and easy to use, thus, the rules of the schema is easy to
                follow as the author did. </p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
