<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Writing Project 2</title>
        <author xml:id="d13">Daniel Doherty</author>
        <version n="1" date="2016-07-31"/>
    </docHead>

    <pub_init_proposal>
        <cover_page>
            <title>Improving the MBTA</title>
            <author>Daniel Doherty</author>
            <submit_date>August 1, 2016</submit_date>
            <audience> To: The City of Boston </audience>
        </cover_page>

        <tbl_cont>
            <section n="1"> 1.0 Introduction 2.0 Background 3.0 Purpose 3.1 Scope 3.2 Objectives 4.0
                Methodology 5.0 Feasibility 5.1 Social 5.2 Economic 5.3 Environmental 6.0 Conclusion
                7.0 References </section>
        </tbl_cont>

        <intro type="abstract">
            <!--attribute options: ltr_int, exec_sum, abstract-->
            <p>The MBTA was created in 1964 to replace the Metropolitan Transit Authority (MTA). The
                MBTA is the fourth largest public transportation system in the country, averaging
                1.3 million riders on a weekday. The MBTA is responsible for operating the commuter
                rail, subway and bus system in Boston. The Green Line is the single busiest subway
                system in the country and averages over 250,000 riders a day. The MBTA is the single
                largest consumer of electricity in the state and is used by 33% of workers in the
                city proper as their primary method of commuting. Given Boston's high dependence on
                the public transportation system, it is essential for the T to operate efficiently
                for commuters to reach their place of work and for the economic success of the city
                of Boston. <!--does not allow a second paragraph here--> However, in recent years
                the MBTA has suffered a variety of incidents that highlight the major problems with
                the system and show that improvements must be made. The MBTA is $8 billion dollars
                in debt and has put off required maintenance due to budget concerns. As a result,
                the MBTA has become a poorly run organization has numerous issues with all aspects
                of their operation. However, the most frequent complaints about the MBTA are
                centered around the subway system and rightly so. The subway system is outdated,
                overcrowded and often delayed due to technical issues. If Boston is going to
                continue to be a modern city that seeks to reduce the consumption of fossil fuels,
                the subway system must be updated. </p>
        </intro>

        <background>
            <p>
                <crnt_cond> The Boston subway system can only be described as old. The four main
                    lines in the city, the Red Line, Green Line, Orange Line and Blue Line all use
                    cars that were constructed prior to 1990. <q>"Out of the MBTA's 218 Red Line
                        cars, 132 are over 25 years old."</q> The Orange Line cars were all
                    implemented between 1979-1981 and have not undergone any major upgrades since.
                    However, the Green Line currently uses some of the oldest cars, with a third of
                    the fleet being originally constructed in the 1960's. These cars were never
                    meant to accommodate the heavy commuter traffic they support daily and depend on
                    outdated forms of technology that often fail and create delays, interrupting the
                    city's economy. </crnt_cond>
                <subj_hist> The problems of the MBTA subway system were especially apparent during
                    the winter of 2014-2015, when Boston received record snowfall levels that
                    paralyzed the city. The frequent storms resulted in massive subway delays and
                    the complete closure of the sections of the Red, Orange and Green lines that
                    were above ground. These delays were mainly caused by engine failure, as the
                    older cars utilize Direct Current (DC) systems that struggle in the snow and
                    freezing temperatures. Cities such as New York have resolved this problem by
                    implementing cars using Alternating Current systems, which are more capable of
                    handling inclement weather. Furthermore, the state of the subway system was a
                    major reason that the citizens of Boston rejected consideration to host the 2022
                    Summer Olympics as it was widely believed the MBTA was incapable of handling the
                    surge of riders in its current state and incapable of implementing the necessary
                    improvements in time. The state of the subway system in Boston negatively
                    impacts the economy, environment and the society in which we live and must be
                    provided with significant investment to allow Boston to continue to develop into
                    a truly modern and green
                    city.<!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
                </subj_hist>
            </p>
        </background>

        <purpose>
            <p>
                <scope type="what"> Massachusetts must provide the MBTA with significant funding to
                    completely overhaul the subway system to implement much needed improvements that
                    will allow the subway to operate efficiently. </scope>
                <scope type="who"> The Massachusetts legislature has consistently left the MBTA
                    underfunded since 2000 when it imposed a cap on their budget due to serious
                    concerns about financial mismanagement at the MBTA. As a result, the MBTA has
                    been forced to delay planned repairs until such time when they receive the
                    necessary funding, causing the subway's infrastructure to fall into
                    disrepair.</scope>
                <!--attribute options: what, who, when, where-->
                <objective> The main objectives of this project is to replace all cars constructed
                    prior to 1990 with modern cars, repair the subway tracks and stations, and
                    extend the subway lines to accommodate additional riders once the system is
                    capable of handling the increase in
                    traffic.<!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
                </objective>
                <goal> By improving the efficiency and service of the MBTA subway system, more
                    commuters will choose to use public transportation as their primary means of
                    transportation. The subsequent reduction of the amount of cars driving into the
                    city each days will make Boston a greener, more environmentally friendly city as
                    it will reduce the amount of fossil fuels required for the city to function.
                    Increased use of an efficient subway system that gets workers to their places of
                    business on time will improve the standard of living in the city and reduce the
                    anger caused daily by traffic delays.
                    <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
                </goal>
            </p>
        </purpose>

        <approach type="action">
            <!--attribute options: execution, action-->
            <p> To implement the upgrade to the subway system, the MBTA must first be granted the
                necessary funds to purchase modern cars that are better suited for Boston's harsh
                winter conditions and can accommodate more passengers. Boston has purchased some
                replacement cars for the Red and Orange lines from a Chinese company but these deal
                now faces corruption charges in addition to these cars having technical issues after
                they were implemented in parts of China. The State Legislature most be petitioned to
                grant appropriate funding to the MBTA now that Gov. Charlie Baker's has forced
                administrative changes to the MBTA to address the mismanagement of the MBTA in
                recent years. Once funding has been secured, new cars using modern AC technology
                should be purchased from a reliable company with a proven record and implementation
                of the new cars into the subway should be sub-contracted to a private company to
                avoid the problems associated with the Big-Dig project.
                <!--add quote from the article supporting this statement-->
            </p>
        </approach>

        <feasibility type="economic">
            <!--attribute options: economic, social, environmental, cannot add more than 1 feasbility section?-->
            <p> The economic benefits of an upgraded subway system are numerous. Most importantly,
                an efficient transportation system that does not suffer from frequent delays will
                not interrupt the business of the city. During the winter of 2015, it was estimated
                the a statewide travel ban would result in a loss of $265 million a day, and the
                complete shutdown of the MBTA several times that winter resulted in the loss of
                hundreds of millions of dollars in profits for businesses in Boston. An overhaul of
                the T system would result in fewer economic interruptions and make Boston a more
                attractive location for economic development, which would provide more jobs and
                opportunity for the citizens of Boston.</p>
        </feasibility>

        <conclu>
            <p> Funding the suggested repairs in this proposal will greatly benefit the citizens,
                businesses and culture of the City of Boston in the years to come. By improving the
                efficiency of the subway by funding modern technology, the T's capacity and
                reliability will be increased, resulting in more commuters utilizing its services.
                This will reduce the amount of cars traveling into the city each day and lower the
                amount of carbon pollutants released by cars. This will make Boston an
                environmentally friendly city capable of accommodating larger crowds such as those
                seen during the Olympics, which would provide further economic opportunity to the city.</p>
        </conclu>

        <references>
            <citation n="" style=""> </citation>
        </references>
    </pub_init_proposal>

    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="peer_id_here"/>
        <report type="peer" resp="#peer_id_here">
            <p>Peer review report will appear here.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
