<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>How Toxins Work (Blog Post - WP2)</title>
        <author xml:id="g_14">Benjamin Gincley</author>
        <version n="1" date="2016-07-31"/>
        <!--note that the date must be YYYY-MM-DD for the document to be valid-->
    </docHead>
    <blog_post>
        <background>
            <pb/><section_header>How does venom work?</section_header>
            <question>Are there different kinds and why are some animals
                resistant or immune to the venom?</question>
            <pb/>
            <scientific_principle n="1">Venom is a mixture of chemicals that different organisms
                have evolved to use as a defense mechanism or to immobilize prey. <important_idea
                    n="1">There are different kinds of venoms, namely, neurotoxins (that affect the
                    nervous system and cause paralysis, convulsions, etc.) and haemotoxins, which
                    affect the blood (prevent clotting, etc.).</important_idea> We'll focus on
                neurotoxins.</scientific_principle>
            <misconceptions n="1">One common misconception people have is the difference between
                venom and poison. <important_idea n="2">Venom is dealt by biting, stinging, or
                    otherwise injecting into body tissue through a wound, while poison is a secreted
                    toxin that, when ingested, inhaled, or absorbed, delivers its
                    effects.</important_idea><analogy>For example, people can eat many venomous
                    snakes and scorpions because they do not secret their toxin onto their skin or
                    other body tissues. Poison ivy secretes its toxin onto its leaves, and doesn't
                    go around trying to bite or sting people.</analogy></misconceptions><pb/>
            <visual type="comic"
                url="http://www.birdandmoon.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/toxic.jpg">Comic courtesy
                of birdandmoon.com</visual>
        </background>
        <answer>
            <pb/>
            <section_header>What, basically, is going
                on?</section_header><fundamental_science_involved n="1">Understanding how
                neurotoxins work relies on a basic understanding of neurobiology. Nerve cells in the
                body, be they in the brain, spinal cord, or connecting to your muscles, rely on a
                combination of chemical and electrical signals to transmit information from one cell
                to the next and one part of the body to the next. Cells in the body exist in a fluid
                matrix that contains all sorts of different chemicals, and the concentration of
                these chemicals is often different inside and outside of the cell's membrane that
                separates it from the rest of the world. Many of these particles are ions, meaning
                they lack or possess extra electrons, effectively giving them an electric charge.
                When the concentration of these ions is different inside and outside of the cell, it
                creates a difference in potential charge, called the Resting Membrane
                Potential.</fundamental_science_involved><question_relevant_topic n="1">Cells
                possess tiny channels in their membranes that allow these ions to travel into and
                out of the cell, which effectively changes the electrical potential difference
                between the inside and the outside of the cell. These channels can be opened either
                by a change in the electrical potential in the membrane, or by the presence of a
                particular chemical that causes them to change shape and open or close them. The act
                of opening or closing many of these channels at once results in a sudden transfer of
                ions into or out of the cell, which often changes the balance of charge that was
                maintained and therefore causing the voltage across the membrane to
                spike.</question_relevant_topic><important_idea n="2"> The key ions used by neurons
                are potassium ions and sodium ions.</important_idea><pb/><visual type="drawing"
                url="https://dundeemedstudentnotes.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/picture22.jpg"
                >Depiction courtesy of dundeemedstudentnotes.wordpress.com</visual><pb/><visual
                type="drawing"
                url="https://figures.boundless-cdn.com/19537/full/figure-35-02-04.%402x.png"
                >Depiction courtesy of Boundless.com, The Nervous System, Figure 35.</visual>
            <important_idea n="3">The core unit of transmission is called the Action Potential, in
                which there is a sudden change in this electric potential in a local area of the
                cell, and the arrangement of channels in the cell membrane allows for this local
                change in potential to propagate, or travel down, the length of the cell
                membrane.</important_idea>
            <fundamental_science_involved n="2">Neurons contain a long extensions called an axon,
                which allows this current to travel a relatively far distance before reaching the
                end of the cell. Once it reaches the end of the cell, the current arrives at a
                synapse, or a gap between the current cell and the next one. The current has no
                place left to go, as it has reached the end of its cell, but at the synapse there
                are structures that can secrete chemicals called
                neurotransmitters.</fundamental_science_involved>
            <question_relevant_topic n="2">These neurotransmitters can leave the cell, travel
                through the intercellular space, and make contact with the cell on the other side by
                interacting with receptors on the next cell's membrane. These receptors respond
                uniquely to the neurotransmitters they are designed to bind
                with,</question_relevant_topic>
            <important_idea n="3">but it is important to note that what is occurring is an
                interaction between complementary shapes, meaning that if a different molecule had a
                region that was similar in shape to the neurotransmitter in question, it too would
                interact with the receptor.</important_idea><pb/><visual type="drawing"
                url="http://i.imgur.com/LsVfrJu.png"/><pb/><analogy>Imagine the shape-fitting toys
                that toddlers play with, where you insert a triangle or a circle piece into various
                cutouts, trying to match the correct shape with the correct hole. The
                neurotransmitter is the inserted piece, and it only inserts into the correct hole,
                or receptor. As an example, let's say the neurotransmitter dopamine is a triangle
                piece, and serotonin is a circle. Dopamine will only fit in the triangle receptor,
                and serotonin will only fit in the circle receptor.</analogy>
            <fundamental_science_involved n="3">Once activated, the receptor continues the signal
                cascade in the next cell, either chemically or electrically, furthering the
                transmission of the signal to its destination, whether it be to the brain to signal
                something, or to a muscle to tell it to
                move.</fundamental_science_involved><pb/><visual type="drawing"
                url="http://i.imgur.com/5IeQkm4.png"/><pb/><analogy>Now consider a modified version
                of the shape matching toy mentioned earlier where instead of falling through the
                hole, the insert has a larger block connected to it, so the piece inserts where the
                shapes match but the rest of the piece hangs out. The natural neurotransmitter is a
                triangle inserted into a triangle hole successfully, but there can be other
                chemicals that can interact with the board too. Another piece with a triangle that
                fits the hole is referred to as an agonist (one that binds successfully to the
                receptor), and a piece that partially fits the hole but doesn’t fit perfectly and
                prevents other pieces from fitting is referred to as an antagonist (obscures the
                receptor without activating it).</analogy><pb/>
            <explanation n="1">Neurotoxins are molecules that affect the chemical transmission
                between neurons, by affecting the cell transmitting the chemicals (pre-synaptic) or
                receiving them (post-synaptic). Some neurotoxins like tetrodototoxin (TTX), which is
                found in pufferfish and poison dart frogs, acts by blocking the sodium channels in
                the pre-synaptic cells. <analogy>TTX is a large chemical (compared to a sodium ion)
                    that attaches to the channel and stops it like a cork for tens of seconds at a
                    time.</analogy> This blockage prevents sodium ions from entering the cell, and
                as a result, the cell can no longer transmit action potentials. Contact to your
                hands would cause paralysis, as even though your brain is telling your hand to move,
                the message stops upstream of the muscles, and they do nothing. The toxin becomes
                fatal when it reaches critical tissue like the heart or lungs, where the stoppage of
                the involuntary nerve impulses that tell your lungs to expand and contract or your
                heart to beat causes those organs to become paralyzed. Then you
                die.</explanation><pb/><explanation n="2">Other toxins can interact with other ion
                channels or receptors to produce various effects, some of which can become very
                complicated and involved. Some toxins like tetanus bind to presynaptic inhibitory
                interneurons (neurons that release chemicals to other neurons to prevent them from
                firing action potentials), resulting in repeated muscle spasms because they can't
                "turn off" the muscular neurons. This ultimately leads to paralysis. Overall, most
                neurotoxins lead to paralysis in one way or another, and nature has come up with
                creative ways to cause this from perceivably every angle that it possibly
                can.</explanation><pb/><visual type="drawing" url="http://i.imgur.com/9YFCOhI.png"
                /><pb/><explanation n="3">Why some animals are immune or resistant to toxins,
                animals like the mongoose that can sustain repeated cobra bites, comes down to
                shape, once again. These animals have evolved channels and/or receptors that have a
                slightly different shape that prevent the toxin from interacting, while continuing
                to allow the normal molecules to do their thing. Let's return to our original
                analogy. <analogy>Imagine if the triangle hole now had a circular bump around it
                    that prevented larger pieces from staying in place. The normal piece can still
                    fit fine, but now the toxin piece can no longer fit properly because of the
                    bump.</analogy> Toxin can't bind, toxin can't block the channel, toxin can't
                prevent the cell from signaling, and the mongoose goes on its merry way getting bit
                by cobras. It's not immune, as given enough toxin pieces, eventually as soon as one
                comes off, another toxin piece takes its place, and the cell can't take in sodium
                fast enough for an action potential, but the animal is at least resistant to a few
                bites.</explanation>
            <conclusion><pb/><section_header>So, how does venom
                    work?</section_header><important_idea n="4">Venom is a chemical compound
                    that interacts with receptors and channels in nerve cell membranes that disrupt
                    the transmission of messages, namely via action potentials, between the
                    neurons.</important_idea> This often results in paralysis in some way or
                another, as the messages from the brain or spinal cord can no longer get to the
                muscle tissue. The result, a paralyzed animal that either can't move and is much
                easier to kill, an animal who suffocates to death because their lungs can't move, or
                a potential predator that now has a paralyzed arm or tentacle and won't come near
                you ever again (or probably survive much longer). <important_idea n="5">Animals can
                    resist these toxins by changing the shape of their receptors or channels so that
                    the toxins can no longer bind to them or block
                    them.</important_idea><pb/><visual type="photo"
                    url="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/lsLdLKATnyk/maxresdefault.jpg">Image courtesy of
                    Super Lion's YouTube video</visual></conclusion>
        </answer>
        <pb/><sources>Depending on your neurobiology experience, a myriad of sources can elucidate
            the mechanisms involved in various toxins. <ref type="source"
                url="https://bigpictureeducation.com/venoms-and-nervous-system">Big Picture</ref>
            provides some nice introductory/summary information on neurotoxins and some examples.
            Rose Eveleth with Ted Ed does a great job explaining what the difference between poisons
            and venoms are in a <ref type="source"
                url="http://ed.ted.com/lessons/venom-vs-poison-what-s-the-difference-rose-eveleth"
                >fun and informative video.</ref> Toxipedia is a <ref type="source"
                url="http://www.toxipedia.org/display/toxipedia/Neurotoxins">fantastic resource for
                more information</ref> on neurotoxins, providing lots of different mechanisms that
            have been discovered so far. For more info on TTX, the quintessential neurotoxin used in
            examples, <ref type="source"
                url="http://www.life.umd.edu/grad/mlfsc/zctsim/ionchannel.html">see here.</ref>
        </sources>
    </blog_post>
    <docReview>
<!--<<<<<<< Updated upstream-->
        <note type="peer" resp="#g14">
        *Answer to Kevin's Questions On Board*
        So far, the overall flow and inclusion of elements is going well, and I feel that I have
        made a good effort to use all of the elements we included in the schema that have relevance
        to the post. The difficulty has mostly been formatting with images, understandably, in that
        sizing and centering/placement is not ideally accounted for in the source code. I feel I am
        nearly finished in the process, and am open to suggestions to clarify content or include
        more elements as necessary. Of particular note might be the picture at the end that is way
        too big for the space, and might want to try to create a smaller version of the image to
        use. Also, I added captions to some images to accredit them, including the text in the visual
        element, but they don't appear in the formatted version. I should look into getting those
        captions printed on the screen. I am also open to suggestions about how I handled the
        sources section, as I used the informal annotation paragraph with links style as opposed to
        a formal citation.</note>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="peer_id_here"/>
        <report type="peer" resp="#peer_id_here">
            <p> I would split the two diagrams that show the the sodium-potassium pump and the direction of with some text instead of having one
                immediately after the other. You could move the action potential diagram down after
                the part you talk about it in the text. For the shape diagrams, I'd put them below
                the text you reference them in, instead of above. I feel like that would improve the
                flow of the post. I know you mentioned you tried to do captions but they didn't
                work, but I definitely feel like they could improve the post if you could get them
                to work (mabye put the captions on the actual image). If you want, you could also use the captions to reference diagrams from the text (Example: "As you can see in figure 1,  Dopamine will only fit in the triangle receptor...") For the action potential diagram, I'd use something that shows the synapse transmitting neurotransmitters, since that is the part that is crucial in explaining how venom works. I'd throw in an analogy in the paragraph right after the "basically what's going on?" section to break up some of the biology jargon.
                A few typos (just ctrl-F for
                them): "Neurons contain a long extensions", "secret" instead of secrete </p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
