<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Title of Assignment</title>
        <author xml:id="l18">Daniel Lieman</author>
        <version n="1" date="2016-08-01"/>
    </docHead> <note peer should inlcude permanent address in heading> </note>
    <cover_letter>
        <header>
            <name>Daniel Lieman</name>
            <contact_info>
                <!-- One or More Contact -->
                <contact type="phone"> 410-660-1969 </contact>
                <contact type="email"> djlieman712@gmail.com </contact>
            </contact_info> 
        </header>
        <greeting>Hello Mathworks,</greeting>
        <intro_para>
            <intent type="Purpose">I am interested in <note peer working as a ></note> C++ Engineer - Physical Modeling Electrical Simulation at Mathworks.</intent>
            <reason><!-- Optional --> I have enjoyed my work with Simulation Engineering in
                the past</reason> and <proposition>I think I will bring all the necessary abilities to go above and beyond my job
                    requirements.</proposition>
        </intro_para>
        <para_background>
            <!-- One or More -->
            <experience type="work">I bring previous experience with C++ from my work at RKF ENgineering. I used C++ while contributing to their satellite communication simulations.</experience>
            <experience type="school">I have used your software before in my classes.  I also have experience with AC and linear analysis.</experience>
        </para_background>
        <para_closing>
            <compatability>I think I will fit in well with the Mathworks.</compatability> <note peer "fit in well at Mathworks"
                or "fit in well with the Mathworks team?" 
              
            <next_step>I hope you will email me at djlieman712@gmail.com so we can discuss the next step in
                the hiring process.</next_step>
        </para_closing>
        <signature>
            <salutation>Sincerely,</salutation>
            <name>JDaniel Lieman</name>
        </signature>
    </cover_letter>
        
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="m21"/>
        <report type="peer" resp="#peer_id_here">
            <p>This cover letter is for second or third year coop within the computer engineering/science fields.
                You are trying to appy for a specific C++ engineering position at Mathworks for the job. 
            </p>
            <p> I am critiquing the language, brevity, and flow/syntx of the paper. Overall, the letter is very brief 
                and does not contain a lot of in depth information. Statements such as, "I think I will bring all the the 
                necessary abilities to go above and beyond" and "I have used your software before in my class" are blanket
                statements that do not provide any insight into your abilities or why you are different from other applicants.
                Additionally, the flow in and between setences should be analyzed; while each one may contain the information
                you want, they do not all flow smoothly into one another
               </p>
            <p>The aspects I identified earlier are major points of a cover letter that employers look for; they already have
                your resume and by viewing your cover letter, are looking for a concise statement about the type of person you
                are, your experience, and why you would be the best fit for the job compared to other applicants. By making 
                your letter easily readible and stand out from the rest, you will increase your chances of success. Instead of 
                saying "I think I will fit in well with the Mathworks," you must explain why you will fit in and give specific 
                examples. 
            </p>
            <p>To improve your cover letter, I would suggest brainstorming a list of specific traits and experiences you posess.
                You have the correct order of information listed, but need to elaborate on each section. Try adding at least 3
                new pieces of information to each of the sections. When you are done, read it out loud- this will help you determine
                how well the letter flows between sentences and sections. Additionally, your tone should display enthusiasm and bring
                more of a "this is what I can do for you/bring to the table" attitude than a "this is who I am" statement. Incorporating
                these changes should have large impact on the overall message of your cover letter. 
                
            </p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>