<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Assignment 2</title>
        <author xml:id="m20">Chi Mo</author>
        <version n="1" date="2016-07-30"/>
    </docHead>
    
    <fsb_rpt>
        <page type="ttl" ><title>Waitless App Feasibility Report</title>
            <contributors>Chi Mo</contributors>
            <date>2016-07-30</date>
        </page>
        <page type="tbl_contents">           
            <sect n="1" lvl="1">Exclusive Summary</sect>
            <sect n="2" lvl="1">Preliminary Requirements Analysis</sect>
            <sect n="1" lvl="2">Application Overview</sect>
            <sect n="3" lvl="1">Feasibility</sect>
            <sect n="4" lvl="1">Success criteria</sect>
            <sect n="5" lvl="1">Cost Estimates</sect>
            <sect n="6" lvl="1">Report page</sect>
            <sect n="7" lvl="1"> Risk Analysis</sect>
            <sect n="8" lvl="1">Financial</sect>
            <sect n="9" lvl="1">Conclusion</sect>
        </page> 
        <page type="exec_sum">
            The app <note type="peer" resp="#v26">Is it necessary to capitalize the A in App?</note> is called Waitless and it's designed for helping people get a seat for a restaurant which doesn't take reservations
            so that they don't need to be arrived and wait for 45 minutes. If you always have dinner outside in Boston, you may find this 
            situation very common. This new app is going to short the waiting time. After you download this app on your phone and the restaurant 
            also has this app downloaded on their device, the time saving trip is started. You can start to wait when you heading to the place 
            and you can see the waiting time so that you can check the time and decide which place you want to go. It's smiliar when you check 
            the route on Google Map and the app will tell you that how long will it take for you to get there and how long is the waiting time. 
            It's a combination of Google Map, Yelp and waiting time of all the restaurants. Also, it can make the points card electronical.
        </page>
        <page type="pre_req_ana">
            <app_ovr type="rls"> 
                Currently, people need to go to the restaurant first, get in a line if it’s busy there, and wait until your turn. Since 
                there won’t be enough space for customers to wait inside the restaurant, customers will have to wait outside. In Boston, the 
                winter is cold and long which is up to 6 months of a year. Therefore, by possibility, there will be 50% of times that a customer
                waits for food is going to be in the cold winter. Some of the restaurants call by name which means the customer can’t leave. 
                Some of restaurants use the “buzz thing” to let customers know their turn but they can’t stay too far from the restaurant. 
            </app_ovr>
            <app_ovr type="obj">                
                After installing Waitless, all these problems solved! No need for waiting outside in the wind for a long time and you can 
                plan your time for your meal.Besides, you don’t need to remeber to carry all the points cards with you or get more points cards 
                if you didn’t bring your own.
            </app_ovr>            
            
            
        </page>
        <page type="fsb">
            <fsb_hlgt type="tcnl">
                In order to develop an App like this, we need to understand how does a restaurant calculate the time. Also, the other 
                problem is that how can we make everything live. Making the points card electronic is the easy part, as long as the 
                restaurant has some kind of points card. A good way to develop the calculating the time is that every restaurant has 
                its own average of dinning time for every numbers of party. As long as we have the average, it will be easy to calculate 
                time. The App is a live based App which means it will sync the changes at backend every few seconds.                 
            </fsb_hlgt>
        </page>
        <page type="sccs_crt"><req_sect>
            <req n="1">Needs two computers. The computers need IOS Xcode installed and Java access. 
                Xcode is for the IOS App design and Java is for the Android.</req>
        </req_sect></page>
        <page type="cost">
            <est type="lgl">$5000 for attorney to get the App lience and patent</est>
            <est type="fnc">$5000 for paying the computer developers to develop the code</est>   
        </page>
        <page type="rpt">
            <tmln date="2016-08-01" n="1">Get the idea and find people to work with</tmln>
            <tmln date="2016-08-05" n="2">Starting the GUI design</tmln>
            <tmln date="2016-09-20" n="3">Get data from restaurant</tmln>
            <tmln date="2016-10-20" n="4">Inner testing</tmln>
            <tmln date="2016-10-31" n="5">Trail testing</tmln>
            <tmln date="2016-11-01" n="6">Release</tmln>
        </page>
        <page type="rsk_ana">
            The risk of this App is the lack of users. The way to avoid it is to send advertisements in popular restaurants around Boston. 
            The App is free first 6-months to restaurants so that they will get to know it well and starting using it. 
        </page>
        <page type="fnc">
            <fnc type="fund"> The cost of developing the IOS APP is the cost of human. It may need 3 person to get all these done. 
            One for the GUI design for the customer side, one for GUI design for the restaurant side and the last one is to get all the 
            data from customer and restaurants. There will be no more cost other than people. Thus, developing a software doesn't need 
            huge funds. </fnc>
        </page> 
        <page type="conc">
            <fsb>This App is a feasible application. According to the design, this App should be capable on IOS and Android.</fsb>
            <cond>On the restaurant side, most of them have one device to take waiting list, other wise, it needs a person to 
                count the tables and calculate the time. If we can make it as a App, things are going to be a lot much easier. 
                On the customer side, with this App, it will save a lot of time. Instead of waiting outside the restaurant 
                in the cold freezing weather, it's better to have an App like this to get on the waiting list before you arrive. </cond>
            <sum> This Waitless will give both customers and restaurants convenience and help them save time.</sum>        
        </page>                
    </fsb_rpt>
        
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="v26"/>
        <report type="peer" resp="#v26">
            <p>
                This draft feasibility report describes an app called Waitless, which shows potential
                restaurant patrons wait times at various restaurants. In the report, conforming to
                the genre, is evidence that the development of the app is feasible. 
            </p>
            <p>
                A feasibility report is a paper written to explain and show why it is possible that
                a project or idea can be made into reality. The feasibility of the project is
                displayed via data or other logical evidence. The situation described is very
                appropriate to the genre and the situation is clearly presented.  
            </p>
            <p>
                For the most part, the sentence structure and word choice are genre appropriate. A
                potential problem that I noted was extensive use of pronouns such as "we" and "you".
                The problem with these pronouns is that a feasibility report is meant to present
                evidence in a formal fashion; these pronouns make the paper seem too casual. My
                advice to remedy this would be to replace, where appropriate, replace the pronouns
                with something less direct, e.g., "one". It should be noted that it is appropriate
                to use "we" when referring to the team developing the app. Another note, regarding
                word choice, more technical jargon could be used. This could be necessary to explain
                in a more in depth fashion how the back-end of the app functions, how the app works,
                and how specifically development will take place.
            </p>
            <p>
                The rules of the schema are mostly followed well. One noticeable exception is in the table
                of contents where the "n" and "lvl" attributes are not used. Another location where
                the schema isn't followed exactly, is in the report page, the timeline elements are
                missing "n" attributes. These "n" attributes are not shown to be required in Oxygen,
                but our schema documentation shows them as required.
            </p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>