<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>P2 Cover LEtter</title>
        <author xml:id="m21">Your name here</author>
        <version n="3" date="2016-08-08"/>
        <!--note that the date must be YYYY-MM-DD for the document to be valid-->
    </docHead>
    <cover_letter>
        <header>
            <name>Chris Murphy</name>
            <contact_info>
                <!-- One or More Contact -->
                <contact type="address">50 River Farm Drive</contact>
                <contact type="address">East Greenwich, RI 02818</contact>
                <contact type="phone"> 401-864-2559 </contact>
                <contact type="email"> murphy.christo@husky.neu.edu </contact>
            </contact_info>
        </header>
        <greeting>Dear Mr. Stefanick,</greeting>
        <intro_para>
            <intent type="purpose">I am writing to apply for an HVAC engineer co-op position,
            </intent>
            <intent type="connection"><!-- Optional --> which I was recommneded for through my previous boss,
                John Donahue at Control Consultants Inc.</intent> 
            <reason><!-- Optional --> I am currently enrolled in a BS/MS program at Northeastern University 
                for Mechanical Engineering and Engineering Management </reason>and <proposition>am looking to gain hands-on experience 
                    in the HVAC industry.</proposition>
        </intro_para>
        <para_background>
            <!-- One or More -->
            <experience type="school">Through my rigorous coursework, I have gained experience with thermodynamics, 
                fluid dynamics, heat transfer, and modeling skills with <programs>AutoCAD</programs>and <programs>SolidWorks</programs>. </experience>
            <experience type="work">During my last coop, I gained valuable experience in the HVAC control field; 
                I was responsible for <skills>creating point lists</skills> for incoming jobs and AutoCAD system drawings for approved 
                jobs. I routinely contacted contractors regarding plans and visited active sites to perform inspections.</experience>
            <experience type="work"> Due to a previous internship at the Naragansett Bay Commission, I also have experience in the water 
                utility and treatment field.</experience>
            <experience type="personal">Additionally, this coming fall I plan on joining the Northeastern chapter of MCAA (NUMCAA)
                to further my skills with mechanical contracting. </experience>
        </para_background>
        <closing_statements>
            <compatability>EMCOR is one of the leading mechanical contractors in the Boston metropolitan area. 
                After my previous experience with HVAC controls, I am looking to broaden my skills in mechanical 
                contracting and I believe working at EMCOR would be a challenging and rewarding path to new 
                knowledge in the industry. I trust that I would be a driven candidate capable of taking on the 
                adversity and problem solving needed when in the office or out in the field. </compatability>
            <next_step><pb/>I am eager to start my future in the HVAC industry and appreciate your consideration for 
                a position at EMCOR Northeast. I look forward to hearing from you soon.</next_step>
        </closing_statements>
        <signature>
            <salutation>Sincerely,</salutation>
            <name>Chris Murphy</name>
        </signature>
    </cover_letter>
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="l18">Daniel Lieman</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" resp="#l18">
            <p>You have written a cover letter with the intention of getting an HVAC engineering Co-Op.  You want to work with EMCOR because it is prestigious.
            You hope to get hands on experience and have listed your experiences and abiities that qualify you for that.</p>
            <p>You could pay a bit more attention to how specific things fit with specific elements and attribute values. 
            The typing of experience could especially use a look over.  This is an organizational thing.  
            </p>
            <p>For experience, you may want to make the things you learned in class stand out more by mentioning how you used them. 
                You may also want to go into more detail on why NUMCAA is useful.  
                Make sure that you don't sacrifice brevity too much if you decide to go into more detail.</p>
            <p>It would be good if you went into more detail about what you like about EMCOR as a company.
                The letter can come as you just picking a large local employer when you write 
                "EMCOR is one of the leading mechanical contractors in the Boston metropolitan area".
                Try doing some research on the company culture or impressive projects it has done.  </p>
        </report>
        
        
        
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
