<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Project 2 Feasibility Report</title>
        <author xml:id="m19">Sydnee Mizuno</author>
        <version n="2" date="2016-08-03"/>
    </docHead>

    <!--paste body of your template file here-->

    <fsb_rpt>
        <page type="ttl">
            <title>Project 2 Feasibility Report</title>
            <subTitle>Solar-powered Roadways</subTitle>
            <contributors>Sydnee Mizuno</contributors>
            <date>August 1, 2016</date>
        </page>

        <page type="tbl_contents">
            <sect n="1" lvl="1"> Executive Summary </sect>
            <sect n="2" lvl="1"> Preliminary Requirements Analysis </sect>
            <sect n="3" lvl="1"> Feasibility </sect>
            <sect n="4" lvl="1"> Success Criteria </sect>
            <sect n="5" lvl="1"> Design </sect>
            <sect n="6" lvl="1"> Cost Estimates </sect>
            <sect n="7" lvl="1"> Reporting </sect>
            <sect n="8" lvl="1"> Risk Analysis </sect>
            <sect n="9" lvl="1"> Financial Planning </sect>
            <sect n="10" lvl="1"> Conclusion </sect>
        </page>

        <page type="exec_sum"> In 2006 the startup Solar Roadways was founded by Julie and Scott
            Brusaw. Solar Roadway's goal is to create solar panels that can replace existing roads.
            These panels are hexagonal layers of tempered glass with solar cells and LEDs in between
            them. By using these panels throughout the U.S. instead of concrete and asphalt roads,
            it is estimated that we could generate three times more electricity than we use. The
            embedded LEDs would offer greater visibility than painted road lines and provide smart
            information about oncoming traffic. Additionally, these roads with electricity and smart
            networks could promote a wider usage of electric vehicles.<pb/> Despite these
            advantages, the endeavor of replacing our country's current highway systems is
            unfeasible. Besides the obvious difficulties that would be encountered with the vast
            scope of the project, there are also issues with the solar panels themselves. The rest
            of this study will address the requirements needed for solar-powered roadways and how
            they are not met.</page>

        <page type="pre_req_ana">
            <app_ovr type="obj"> Solar Roadway's mission is to generate clean, reneweable solar
                energy on roadways. To accomplish this, the startup has developed modular solar
                panels that can replace asphalt surfaces. By using these panels, substantial amounts
                of electricity could be generated. Also, embedded LEDs and sensors could create a
                smart highway system. </app_ovr>
            <app_ovr type="rls"> In 2009, Solar Roadways received a $100,000 grant from the
                Department of Transportation (DOT) to seek engineering input and write a concept
                paper. Then in 2011 the DOT gave another grant of $750,000 to develop a working
                prototype the size of a parking lot. In addition to giving Solar Roadways money for
                reaearch and devleoplment, the DOT is also working with them to test the safety and
                functionality of the solar panels. Before any major implementations could happen in
                the U.S., Solar Roads would need the DOT's approval. </app_ovr>
            <app_ovr type="synergy"> With the use of solar roads, the existing roads in our country
                would need replacement. Also this new road system would need to be integrated into
                current electric grids.</app_ovr>
        </page>

        <page type="fsb">
            <fsb_hlgt type="tcnl"> The current prototype for solar-powered roads consists of two
                layers of glass panels that enclose a circuit board with LEDs, solar cells, and
                heating elements. The glass is tempered and textured to provide safety and traction
                for traffic. Solar Roadways has reported that this glass surface has been tested in
                a university lab, and that a vehicle stopped within the required braking distance.
                However, the DOT has not confirmed this. Also, the DOT was unable to send its impact
                load testing equipment to Solar Roadways, so the glass panels' load carrying
                capacity has only been officially tested through 3D modeling. Solar Roadways has not
                yet decided on any specific solution to keep these panels clean. The LEDs that are
                embedded in the panels would replace the need for painting road lines. They would
                also increase visibility. Solar Roadways envisions these LEDs flashing in response
                to oncoming obstacles like pedestrians and wildlife. The circuits also contain solar
                cells to collect energy, and they also contain heating systems to keep the panels
                above freezing. This would prevent the accumulation of snow and ice. Difficulties
                have been ecountered in the manufacture of these panels. With the rise of smart,
                personal electronics, companies have focused on making circuits smaller. This
                presents a problem with finding circuits big enough for Solar Roadways' panels.
                Another major issue is the efficiency of the solar cells being used. At this time,
                the cells have not been tested anywhere except at the Brusaws' house. This is
                problematic because there has been no independent testing acorss different
                environments.</fsb_hlgt>
            <fsb_hlgt type="econ"> Solar Roadways has not completed a cost analysis yet. But in
                2010, co-founder Scott Brusaw estimated that a 12 by 12 foot panel would cost
                $10,000. With about 29,000 square miles of paved roads in the US, it is estimated
                that the total replacement cost would be $56 trillion.</fsb_hlgt>
            <fsb_hlgt type="socl"> If these solar-powered roads were adopted, Solar Roadways would
                only be the manufacturer of the solar panels. The goverment and other independent
                companies would be left to solve the logistics of replacing the country's current
                transportation infastructure. </fsb_hlgt>
        </page>

        <page type="sccs_crt">
            <req_sect> Solar Panel Components <req> The solar panels that would make up the roadways
                    are hexagonal pieces of tempered glass that encase a circuit board. This circuit
                    board contains solar cells to capture energy, LEDs for road lines and displays,
                    and heating systems to prevent snow buildup. </req></req_sect>
            <req_sect>Testing <req> Before solar-powered roads could be adopted throughout the
                    country, they would need to be rigorously tested. The Department of
                    Transportation would need to test the panels for safety, efficieny, and
                    reliability. These and other independent tests would be needed in addition to
                    the Brusaws' home tests.</req></req_sect>
            <req_sect>Implementation <req>The Department of Transportation and other service
                    agencies would need to handle the installation of Solar Roadways' panels. They
                    would be responsible for creating building projects, financing them, and
                    installing them.</req></req_sect>
        </page>

        <page type="dsn">
            <img url="http://imgur.com/rksJf69">Solar Panel Layers</img>
            <img url="http://imgur.com/wk5Pmgh">LEDs in Panels</img>
        </page>

        <page type="cost">
            <est type="fnc"> At this time, all costs are estimated because Solar Roadways has not
                conducted a cost analysis. It is estimated that the company's solar panel pieces
                would cost $70 per square foot. By replacing asphalt roads in the U.S. with these
                panels, it would cost about $56 trillion.</est>
        </page>

        <page type="rpt"> Solar Roadways has tested most of its design at the founders' home, and it
            has posted some of those reults to the company website. The company has also
            collaborated with the DOT and various university labs for testing. It will continue to
            test and report its findings to these organizations as product development
            continues.</page>

        <page type="rsk_ana"> There are potential risks to using solar-powered roads. One of these
            is the strength of the glass panels. Solar Roadways uses tempered glass, and it
            manufactures it similar to bulletproof and bomb blast resistant glass. The company
            self-reports that the roads can hold 250,000 pounds. Another risk is road traction. To
            increase traction, the solar panels are textured for grip. Another risk is a damaged or
            defective panel. Solar Roadways says the smart network of panels could report the
            location of a defective panel, and it could be collected and reprogrammed
            quickly.</page>

        <page type="conc">
            <fsb> While the benefits of solar-powered roads are great in theory, there is not enough
                evidence to prove that they could be practically implemented throughout the U.S. </fsb>
            <cond> At this time, the majority of testing has been completed at the Brusaws' home,
                and the results have been self-reported. The DOT and other organizations would need
                to independently test and verify the solar panels' performance. Also, Solar Roadways
                would need to run a financial analysis of its product in order for any organization
                to seriously consider financing it.</cond>
            <sum>With the lack of official testing and the extreme cost of road replacement, it is
                unfeasible to adopt these new types of roads across the country. While it may be
                possible to expand this technology from the Brusaws' small prototype parking lot to
                the entire highway system, today is not that day.</sum>
        </page>
    </fsb_rpt>

    <!-- Questions about Draft -->
    <!-- 1.	I think that my feasibility section is going well. I addressed a lot of technical feasibility, and I also addressed the financial concerns. 
2.	I’m not entirely sure about my “Report” section.
3.	I think I’m very far along in my draft. It could use revisions, but everything I want is in it.
4.	The main place that I could use advice in the “Report” section. 
 -->

    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="b11"/>
        <report type="peer" resp="#b11">
            <p>Sydnee's feasibility study looks at solar-powered roads developed by Solar Roadway's.
                Taking an objective look at different steps required to put solar panels on all U.S
                roadways, Sydnee breaks down concerns over the practicality of this project, while
                also laying out conditions for how it could become a reality. She does this while
                giving a clear stance that she does not see sufficient evidence that the project is
                feasible. </p>
            <p>My first thought upon reading Sydnee's study is that is well polished enough to be a
                final draft. In her writer's memo she states that everything which she intends to
                include is present. Starting with the executive summary, Sydnee's thoughts are
                clearly stated. Looking at the Report page, I see "The company has also collaborated
                with the DOT and various university labs for testing". For the relevancy of this
                page, I think it would help to see some more detail from this thought. "What kind of
                testing do they do? Why is it relevant? How do they report this data to the DoD?"
                She does go into this slightly in the feasibility study:technical section, but it
                would be very relevant to read about any specific tests taking place. If Solar
                roadway's also had a time frame estimate that would be a compelling piece of
                evidence to support or not support this project. A similar issue in the conclusion
                can be found under the cond paragraph. She brings up testing again, and the piece
                would definitely benefit from a list of what conditional testing is needed.
                Including earlier examples in the piece (specifically from the technical feasibility
                paragraph). Lastly I think the success criteria would benefit from an expansion of
                what tests Brusaws conducted, looking specifically here: "These and other
                independent tests would be needed in addition to the Brusaws' home tests", asking
                "what are these home tests?". Overall Sydnee does an excellent job presenting her
                ideas, and supporting them through her research, the only room for improvement I
                have to suggest is fleshing out references of tests with more detail, adding to the
                technical relevancy for this feasibility study. </p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
