<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Individual Assignment for Project 2</title>
        <author xml:id="p22">Matt Parlon</author>
        <version n="3" date="2016-08-08"/>
    </docHead>

    <!--paste body of your template file here-->

    <pub_init_proposal>
        <cover_page>
            <title> Bringing Solar to Boston </title>
            <author> Matt Parlon </author>
            <submit_date> 8/15/2016 </submit_date>
            <audience> Mr. Marty Walsh </audience>
        </cover_page>

        <tbl_cont>
            <section n="1">1.0: Introduction </section>
            <section n="2">2.0: Background </section>
            <section n="3">3.0: Purpose </section>
            <section n="4">4.0: Approach </section>
            <section n="5">5.0: Feasibility </section>
            <section n="6">6.0: Conclusion </section>
        </tbl_cont>

        <intro type="abstract">
            <!--attribute options: ltr_int, exec_sum, abstract-->
            <p> As it stands, Massachusetts is one of the nations foremost clean energy friendly 
                states.  One would infer that Boston, the state capitol, would lead the way and set 
                the example for the rest of the Massachusetts. Boston is a diverse, growing city and 
                its energy policy should reflect that. By decentralizing the energy generation of 
                Boston, the associated financial gain can be properly distributed across all income 
                levels. By providing a tax credit equal to 25% the value of the investment
                associated with using solar energy, Boston could greatly reduce its load on the 
                grid and its yearly carbon emissions.  
            </p>
        </intro>

        <background>
            <p>
                <crnt_cond> 
                    Currently, there are several federal and state incentives associated with meeting a portion of ones 
                    energy demand with solar energy. The Federal ITC reimburses investors of photovoltaics with a tax credit 
                    equal to 30% of their invested capital. In Massachusetts, there is a SREC (Solar Renewable Energy Credit)
                    that also provides money to counter the required upfront investment associated with solar. Net metering
                    allows generators of solar energy to sell their excess energy back to the grid at a price that is slightly 
                    less than what the grid charges to supply energy.
                    <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
                </crnt_cond>
            </p>
                <p>
                <subj_hist> 
                    Sustainability focuses on the environmental, social, and economic costs associated with actions. 
                    However, in terms of getting people to adopt a movement, economic terms seem to be the most persuasive. 
                    Providing an incentive that is able to put the social and environmental externalities associated with the 
                    burning of fossil fuel into economic terms allows for a more fair comparison of energy generation techniques. 
                    The Daily Climate reported, <q>Coal plants place a disproportionate burden on poor and largely minority communities,
                    exposing residents to high levels of pollutants that affect public health</q>. It is easy to see that, without taking
                    the cost of externalities into account, people that compare things strictly economically will not change their 
                    ways and distributed burdens will continue to go largely ignored. 
                    <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
                </subj_hist>
                </p>
            
        </background>

        <purpose>
            <p>
                <scope type="what"> 
                    Providing an incentive that will allow for greater adoption of solar energy generation techniques 
                    will benefit all in the target area as well as surrounding communities. There are many advantages 
                    to going solar that span all facets of society.
                </scope>
                <!--attribute options: what, who, when, where-->
                
                <objective> Boston should provide a citywide financial incentive to people that
                    adopt photovoltaic-based energy production methods.
                    <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
                </objective>
                
                <goal> 
                    By using more photovoltaics, Bostonians would decrease their carbon footprint, 
                    increase consumer awareness, and start to mitigate the health concerns associated with 
                    air pollution from fossil fuel burning facilities. 
                    <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
                </goal>
            </p>
        </purpose>

        <approach>
            <!--attribute options: execution, action-->
            <p> 
                <execution> Understandably, there will be some push back to this proposal. 
                    This is due to the fact that to generate the necessary capital to supply a PV tax credit, 
                    some will have to be charged more than their current electricity rate. However, by increasing
                    the cost of energy generated from fossil fuels, Boston would be forcing people who contribute to 
                    the pollution of the environment pay for the cost of this externality. This price correction would 
                    not be large because the number of ratepayers using fossil fuel generated energy is so much greater
                    than those that would receive the benefit of this incentive that their rate would not increase greatly.
                    As more and more people go solar, the ratio of ratepayers funding the incentive to those benefiting 
                    would decrease. For this reason, there will be an obvious reason to join this program as early as possible. 
                    That being said, this also adds the constraint that this incentive program is to be reevaluated over 
                    time as not to eventually have an unfair burden on those that do not adopt this program.
                    <!--text here-->
                </execution>
            </p>
        
            <p>
                <action>
                    Immediately, a citywide incentive program should be brought to town council and be introduced 
                    to the public. As public meetings evaluate this proposal, a community-specific program will 
                    be hashed out that would incorporate the desires of the citizens and give lawmakers greater 
                    insight as to how smaller communities react to such energy credit programs.
                </action>
            </p>
        </approach>

        <feasibility>
            <!--attribute options: economic, social, environmental-->
            <p>Environmental</p>
            <p> 
                <environmental> 
                    Per unit area, solar panels can offset more carbon emission than a tree. 
                    This is the justification most solar developers use to clear-cut a wooded area 
                    to replace it with panels. However, if Boston were to adopt a greater solar incentive program, 
                    panels would be used on rooftops, bridges, and as parking overhangs. Since such a large portion
                    of Boston is covered with impermeable surfaces, panels would not be displacing any carbon 
                    sequestering organisms and would also deplete the solar radiation that is constantly being 
                    absorbed by the dark roofs and streets of Boston. 
                </environmental>
                <!--text here-->
            </p>
      
            <!--attribute options: economic, social, environmental-->
            <p>Social</p>
            <p> 
                <social>
                    There are many links associated with air pollution and mental health. 
                    NaturalNews outlines this issue by stating that "While previous studies have linked 
                    urban air pollution to type 2 diabetes and increased blood sugar levels in pregnant women, 
                    among other ailments, new research suggests that poor air quality might also be responsible 
                    for reducing children's IQs, affecting their ability to learn and access information”. 
                    By allowing residents to stop contributing to the pollution of their own air, Boston 
                    will be promoting greater mental health that disproportionately affects those living in 
                    poorer communities who bear the brunt of this pollution. The other health affects associated 
                    with air pollution would also start to be remediated by the reduction in energy demand from 
                    the grid. 
                    <!--text here-->
                </social>
            </p>
            <!--attribute options: economic, social, environmental-->
            <p>Economic</p>
            <p> 
                <economic>  
                    By allowing individual households to produce their own energy and sell the remainder back 
                    to the grid, Boston could help to decentralize wealth and help those living in poverty to 
                    overcome their current financial problems.  
                    <pb/>
                    Adopting solar will also prove beneficial to those in the large rental market of Boston. 
                    As landlords compete for tenants, a large group will be drawn to apartments and offices that
                    can boast a renewable energy connection. These landlords may also be able to pass along a 
                    portion of there electric savings to their tenants. 
                    <!--text here-->
             </economic> 
            </p>
        </feasibility>

        <conclu>
            <p>
                Boston is among the worlds most educated and diverse cities. Logic would indicate that such 
                a city should have an energy policy that reflects its communities. I propose that a 25% tax credit 
                be issued to Bostonians who adopt rooftop solar energy generation. This credit, partnered with 
                other government incentives will allow a wider range of society to save money, reduce pollution,
                and increase awareness through solar.  
                <!--text here-->
            </p>
        </conclu>

        <references>
            <citation n="" style="APA"> 
                Wilson, J. (2015, May 31). Why cities make people stupid: Air pollution significantly 
                reduces children's IQ, study finds . Natural News. Retrieved from 
                http://www.naturalnews.com/049903_air_pollution_city_life_intelligence.html
            </citation>
            
            <citation style="APA">
                Israel, B. (2012, November 16). Coal plants smothering communities of color, 
                report finds . The Daily Climate .
                Retrieved from http://www.dailyclimate.org/tdc-newsroom/2012/11/coal-power-injustice
            </citation>
        </references>
    </pub_init_proposal>


    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="w28">Sam Wagner</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" resp="#w28">
            <p>The first draft of this proposal looks very in depth at the cost/benefit relationship
                associated with the use of solar power in the city of Boston. Although the
                introduction does provide a good overview of the situation surrounding the proposed
                project, I don’t know if it makes the actual project itself completely clear.
                Consider ending your introduction with a decisive and direct statement of what needs
                to be done. The background section felt very informative but could maybe use a
                little bit of historical context about solar power used in cities elsewhere or in
                Boston in the past. I really appreciated the structured layout of the feasibility
                section of this proposal. I think that it addressed each subject in a very relevant
                manner. However, I think as far as ease of reading, maybe include a statement or
                something at the beginning of each readability section so that the reader knows and
                can appreciate the fact that you are touching on all three of these areas; social,
                environmental and economic.</p> <p>At times throughout the document the word choice becomes
                a bit repetitive. When this is the case, maybe consider breaking down your
                statements into smaller sentences to determine if that information is entirely
                relevant in that section or if it might work better in another section. Also if you
                are going to link back to previously stated information consider referencing that
                earlier statement. This will add purpose to your statements and make your argument
                more clear. </p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
