<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Draft of Individual Assignment for Project 2</title>
        <author xml:id="p22">Matt Parlon</author>
        <version n="num_of_version" date="2016-07-31"/>
    </docHead>

    <!--paste body of your template file here-->

    <pub_init_proposal>
        <cover_page>
            <title> Bringing Solar to Boston </title>
            <author> Matt Parlon </author>
            <submit_date> 8/15/2016 </submit_date>
            <audience> Mr. Marty Walsh </audience>
        </cover_page>

        <tbl_cont>
            <section n="1">Page 1: Introduction </section>
            <section n="2">Page 2: Background </section>
            <section n="3">Page 3: Purpose </section>
            <section n="4">Page 4: Approach </section>
            <section n="5">Page 5: Feasibility </section>
            <section n="6">Page 6: Conclusion </section>
        </tbl_cont>

        <intro type="abstract">
            <!--attribute options: ltr_int, exec_sum, abstract-->
            <p> As it stands, Massachusetts is one of the nations foremost clean energy friendly
                states. One would infer that Boston, the state capitol, would lead the way and set
                the example for the rest of the Massachusetts. Boston is a diverse, growing city and
                its energy policy should reflect that. By providing greater local incentives, Boston
                can put the new development in Boston to good use while aiding older areas populated
                by the less wealthy. <note type="peer" resp="#w28">You might consider rephrasing
                    this sentence, its a bit confusing and I think the wording is not quite getting
                    your point across. Also I would switch these last two sentences so that you are
                    ending your intro on a more broad statement.</note>By decentralizing the energy
                generation of Boston, the associated financial gain can be properly
                    distributed.<note type="peer" resp="w28">It is not quite clear by the end of
                    this abstract what exactly you are proposing. Maybe consider ending it with a
                    definitive statement on what your project is that you are proposing.</note>
            </p>
        </intro>

        <background>
            <p>
                <crnt_cond> Currently, there are several federal and state incentives associated
                    with meeting a portion of ones energy demand with solar energy. The Federal ITC
                    reimburses investors of photovoltaics with a tax credit equal to 30% of their
                    invested capital. In Massachusetts, there is a SREC (Solar Renewable Energy
                    Credit) that also provides money to counter the required upfront investment
                    associated with solar. Net metering allows generators of solar energy to sell
                    their excess energy back to the grid at a price that is slightly less than what
                    the grid charges to supply energy. <note type="peer" resp="#w28">If you are
                        looking to cut down on words, this information is all very interesting but
                        could probably be generalized in one sentence without all of the
                        specifics.</note>
                    <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
                </crnt_cond>
                <subj_hist> Sustainability focuses on the environmental, social, and economic costs
                    associated with actions. However, in terms of getting people to adopt a
                    movement, economic terms seem to be the most persuasive. Providing an incentive
                    that is able to put the social and environmental externalities associated with
                    the burning of fossil fuel into economic terms allows a more fair comparison of
                    energy generation techniques.<note type="peer" resp="#w28">I don't know if this
                        "subject history" section is really relevant history. It a very valid point
                        about cost benefit analysis but I think this section could maybe use a
                        little bit of historical reference to set the proposal moving
                        forward.</note>
                    <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
                </subj_hist>
            </p>
        </background>

        <purpose>
            <p>
                <scope type="what"> Providing an incentive that will allow for greater adoption of
                    solar energy generation techniques will benefit all in the target area as well
                    as surrounding communities. There are many advantages to going solar that span
                    all facets of society. </scope>
                <!--attribute options: what, who, when, where-->
                <objective> Boston should provide a citywide financial incentive to people that
                    adopt photovoltaic-based energy production
                    methods.<!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
                </objective>
                <goal> By using more photovoltaics, Bostonians would decrease their carbon
                    footprint, increase consumer awareness, and put a dollar value on the health
                    concerns associated with air pollution from fossil fuel burning facilities.
                    <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
                </goal>
            </p>
        </purpose>

        <approach type="execution">
            <!--attribute options: execution, action-->
            <p> Understandably, there will be some push back to this proposal. This is due to the
                fact that to generate the necessary capital to supply a PV tax credit, some will
                have to be charged more than their current electricity rate. However, by increasing
                the cost of energy generated from fossil fuels, Boston would be forcing people who
                contribute to the pollution of the environment pay for the cost of this externality.
                This price correction would not be large because the number of ratepayers using
                fossil fuels generated energy is so much greater than those that would receive the
                benefit of this incentive that their rate would not increase greatly. As more and
                more people go solar, the ratio of ratepayers funding the incentive to those
                benefiting would decrease. For this reason, there will be an obvious reason to join
                this program as early as possible. That being said, this also adds the constraint
                that this incentive program is to be reevaluated over time as not to eventually have
                an unfair burden on those that do not adopt this program. <!--text here-->
            </p>
        </approach>

        <approach type="action">
            <!--attribute options: execution, action-->
            <p>
                <note type="peer" resp="#w28">Formatting note: by seperating the information like
                    this there are now two approach sections in the report rather than being able to
                    combine "execution" and "action" into one subsection.</note>Immediately, a
                citywide incentive program should be brought to town council and be introduced to
                the public. As public meetings evaluate this proposal, a community-specific program
                will be hashed out that would incorporate the desires of the citizens and give
                lawmakers greater insight as to how smaller communities react to such energy credit
                programs.<!--text here-->
            </p>
        </approach>

        <feasibility type="environmental">
            <!--attribute options: economic, social, environmental-->
            <p> Solar panels offset more carbon than a tree can, using the same area. This is the
                justification most solar developers use to clear-cut a wooded area to replace it
                with panels. However, if Boston were to adopt a greater solar incentive program,
                panels would be used on rooftops, bridges, and as parking overhangs. Since such a
                large portion of Boston is covered with impermeable surfaces, panels would not be
                displacing any carbon sequestering organisms and would also deplete the solar
                radiation that is constantly being absorbed by the dark roofs and streets of Boston.
                <!--text here-->
            </p>
        </feasibility>

        <feasibility type="social">
            <!--attribute options: economic, social, environmental-->
            <p> There are many links associated with air pollution and mental health. By allowing
                residents to stop contributing to the pollution of their own air, Boston will be
                promoting greater mental <note type="peer" resp="#w28">Just mental health?</note>
                health that disproportionately affects those living in poorer communities who bear
                the brunt of this pollution. <note type="peer" resp="#w28">This may not be in the
                    scope of this assignment, but it might be good to also address the fact that
                    much of Boston's population is in rented properties and do not have any control
                    over the energy sources that their building owners chose to implement. How would
                    this tax effect them while they are powerless to fix it?</note><!--text here-->
            </p>
        </feasibility>

        <feasibility type="economic">
            <!--attribute options: economic, social, environmental-->
            <p> By allowing individual households to produce their own energy and sell the remainder
                back to the grid, Boston could help to decentralize wealth and help those living in
                poverty to overcome their current financial problems. <note type="peer" resp="#w28"
                    >Formatting note: all feasability sections should be seperated as different
                    paragraphs under one subtitle called feasability. context Note: Also, the jumps
                    between each of these sections seem a little bit random when you are reading
                    through, consider introducing each section a little bit to show the reader
                    clearly that you are looking at it from all three of these perspective.
                </note><!--text here-->
            </p>
        </feasibility>

        <conclu>
            <p>
                <!--text here-->
            </p>
        </conclu>

        <references>
            <citation n="" style="APA"> </citation>
        </references>
    </pub_init_proposal>


    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="w28">Sam Wagner</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" resp="#w28">
            <p>The first draft of this proposal looks very in depth at the cost/benefit relationship
                associated with the use of solar power in the city of Boston. Although the
                introduction does provide a good overview of the situation surrounding the proposed
                project, I don’t know if it makes the actual project itself completely clear.
                Consider ending your introduction with a decisive and direct statement of what needs
                to be done. The background section felt very informative but could maybe use a
                little bit of historical context about solar power used in cities elsewhere or in
                Boston in the past. I really appreciated the structured layout of the feasibility
                section of this proposal. I think that it addressed each subject in a very relevant
                manner. However, I think as far as ease of reading, maybe include a statement or
                something at the beginning of each readability section so that the reader knows and
                can appreciate the fact that you are touching on all three of these areas; social,
                environmental and economic.</p> <p>At times throughout the document the word choice becomes
                a bit repetitive. When this is the case, maybe consider breaking down your
                statements into smaller sentences to determine if that information is entirely
                relevant in that section or if it might work better in another section. Also if you
                are going to link back to previously stated information consider referencing that
                earlier statement. This will add purpose to your statements and make your argument
                more clear. </p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
