<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Modeling and Producing Genre</title>
        <author xml:id="s_23">Monica Salas</author>
        <version n="1" date="2016-08-01"/>
    </docHead>

    <cover_letter>

        <header>
            <name>Monica Salas</name>
            <contact_info>
                <!-- One or More Contact -->
                <contact type="address">48 Saint Stephen St. Boston, MA 02115</contact>
                <contact type="phone"> 508-335-8828 </contact>
                <contact type="email"> monicasalas114@gmail.com </contact>
            </contact_info>
        </header>

        <greeting>Dear Hiring Committee: </greeting>

        <intro_para>
            <intent type="purpose">I am writing to apply for the MotorSports development engineer
                position at A123 Systems Inc. listed in NUCareers. <note type="peer" resp="#s_25"
                    >Hiring committee might not know that NUCareers is, maybe say something
                    like"career services website" instead</note>
            </intent>
            <reason>I am thrilled to see progress being made into the future of clean energy in the
                automotive industry. I am also most driven in a work environment that keeps me on my
                toes with both business development work and engineering based problem
                solving.</reason>
            <proposition>I think my experience working for both well established engineering
                companies and fast paced start ups that are still establishing themselves gives me a
                unique set of skills that are useful in process development.</proposition>
        </intro_para>

        <para_background>
            <experience type="work">At my first co-op at Amphenol PCD, I was introduced to the types
                of standards that needed to be met to serve customers in the military and aerospace
                industries. I produced and followed standard operating procedures created by
                companies like Raytheon and Boeing in the process of developing and supplying
                quality electrical products for their assemblies. The rigorous standards implemented
                at this job taught me the importance of well organized and effective documentation
                of everything involved in an engineering company. It also taught me how necessary it
                was to work creatively within the bounds of these SOPs in order to produce quality
                end products. This job is also where I became accomplished using 3D modeling and
                rapid prototyping programs such as Pro-E/Creo and 3D printing.</experience>
        </para_background>

        <para_background>
            <experience type="work">In my experience working at Infinium, Inc., a material science
                start up, I learned all about process development in a research environment. At this
                company I worked on a small team to refine a process to create primary aluminum via
                electrochemical processes. I modelled in AutoCAD inventor and helped to build
                infrastructure for the developing process. I also performed material compatibility
                tests and post experiment analysis using x-ray diffraction, scanning electron
                microscopy, and data analysis in MatLab. </experience>
        </para_background>

        <para_background>
            <experience type="school">Aside from my work experience, I am a recent student at a
                University <note type="peer" resp="#s_25">"recent graduate from Northeastern
                    University which" might sound more impressive here</note>that emphasizes
                professional development and entrepreneurship. In my labs and classes, I have
                developed strong technical writing and communication skills, the ability to work
                effectively with teams of people, and resourceful problem solving
                skills.</experience>
        </para_background>

        <para_closing>
            <compatability>I believe I work best in a fast paced, energetic environment and think I
                would be able to integrate well into a team like A123 Systems'
                MotorSports.</compatability>
            <next_step>I would welcome the opportunity to further discuss the position and my
                qualifications in the near future. Thank you very much for your
                consideration!</next_step>
        </para_closing>

        <signature>
            <salutation>Sincerely,</salutation>
            <name>Monica Salas</name>
        </signature>

    </cover_letter>


    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="s_25"/>
        <report type="peer" resp="#s_25">
            <p>The peer review report is in response to a cover letter written to express interest
                for a development engineering job at A123 Systems. </p>
            <p>I believe this cover letter does a great job identifying why you are a great
                candidate for this role. Several examples and qualifications are offered which
                relate to specific points in the job description. However, one possible point of
                improvement would be stating how the job is a great fit for you. The sentences
                inside of the reason element state an interest in the general industry and general
                work environment of the company, so it might make sense to include information that
                might be more specific to this particular job.</p>
            <p>Moving on, I believe the first background paragraph is well written and does a great
                job of highlighting experience that very closely matches the job description. I
                believe that your second background paragraph should be more like the first in that
                it should highlight the most relevant experiences rather than describe exactly what
                you worked on. For example, your last sentence in that paragraph lists a several
                methods of analysis (“x-ray diffraction, scanning electron microscopy, and data
                analysis in MatLab”) which may not be useful to the company based on the job
                description and experience and education listed in the posting. It might make sense
                to add to this paragraph or replace this sentence completely with one that describes
                one of your qualifications that relates to the job opening.</p>
            <p>I believe you also do a great job connecting your skills school experience in your
                third background paragraph. However, placing myself as the hiring committee in this
                particular rhetorical situation, most of the information you provide in this
                paragraph seems to be pretty standard and generic, which would not make you stand
                out in the applicant pool, especially if they are from the same university. If
                possible, I would suggest adding more specifics that might separate your experience,
                or make it more technically relevant to the job description. Additionally, if you
                can add more information in your second background paragraph, you may be able to
                completely get rid of your third paragraph.</p>
            <p>Finally, I think your closing paragraph is very good the way it is. I noticed this in
                my writing as well, but it might make sense to add an optional “thank you” element
                inside of this paragraph, since this seems to be common in many cover letters.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
