<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Writing Project 2</title>
        <author xml:id="s25">Leo Stolov</author>
        <version n="1" date="2016-08-01"/>
    </docHead>

    <cover_letter>
        <header>
            <name>Leo Stolov</name>
            <contact_info>
                <!-- One or More Contact -->
                <contact type="address">606 Columbus Ave #3R Boston, MA 02118</contact>
                <contact type="phone"> 860-519-9771 </contact>
                <contact type="email"> stolov.l@husky.neu.edu </contact>
            </contact_info>
        </header>
        <greeting>Dear Joshua Elvander,</greeting>

        <intro_para>
            <intent type="Purpose">I am writing to express my interest in the mechanical engineering
                fall internship position, which I found through Northeastern's co-op
                network.</intent>
            <reason> I am approaching my fourth year as a BS/MS candidate for Mechanical Engineering
                with a concentration in Mechatronics and am eager to gain more hands-on experience
                in new industries.</reason>
            <proposition>I believe my previous experience and passion for automation and
                interdisciplinary work make me an ideal candidate for this role.</proposition>
        </intro_para>

        <para_background>
            <!-- One or More -->
            <experience type="work">During my time at Portal Instruments, another start up in the
                area, I worked on a complex electromechanical assembly.</experience>
            <experience type="work"> This project involved a lot of independent design, fabrication,
                and testing, which I believe is not unlike the work I would be doing at
                Piaggio.</experience>
            <experience type="work">At my last co-op at Bio-Rad, I worked mostly independently on a
                piece of automation equipment, which involved the integration of mechanical,
                electrical, and software concepts.</experience>
            <experience type="personal">In addition to my work experience, I also participate in
                AIAA, where I have begun to help with the mechanical design of an RC plane as well
                as the electrical and software implementation of several components.</experience>
        </para_background>

        <para_closing>
            <compatability> My previous supervisors have described me as a self motivated worker
                with an eagerness to learn, which I believe would make me a great fit for the start
                up environment of Piaggio.</compatability>
            <next_step>I would appreciate an opportunity to meet with you to discuss my
                qualifications in further detail. Thank you for your consideration, and I look
                forward to speaking with you soon.</next_step>
        </para_closing>

        <signature>
            <salutation>Sincerely,</salutation>
            <name>Leo Stolov</name>
        </signature>
    </cover_letter>

    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="peer_id_here"/>
        <report type="peer" resp="#peer_id_here">
            <p>Peer review report will appear here.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
