<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Lose Your Computer Security Insecurity</title>
        <author xml:id="s24">Oliver Scott</author>
        <version n="num_of_version" date="2016-07-31"/>
    </docHead>

    <blog_post>
        <background> Computer security, <misconceptions> the words somehow feel like they belong to
                two types of people: 1) Malicious computer hackers who can cause servers to melt
                worldwide with the casual swipe of their fingers and a sip of mountain dew. 2) The
                office IT worker who can transform you into a narcoleptic with a stained oversized
                white t-shirt and a one sided discussion about the merits of the Hutt's mafioso
                control of Tatooine's water supplies. </misconceptions> Consequentially, when the
            topic of computer security arises, the average computer user's eyes glaze over whilst
            simultaneously running away at Olympic gold medal speeds. <pb/> This is bad. We (almost)
            all use computers, and its our responsibility to help keep them safe. <analogy>Who's at
                fault if you get in an car accident when you're driving without a license. Who's at
                fault if you leave your door open every day and come home one day to find out you've
                been robbed? </analogy> A lot of your important stuff exists on a computer
            somewhere. <important_idea n="1"> What you might not know, is that avoiding having this
                stuff stolen is not hard nor time intensive, it can be as easy as putting on a
                seatbelt or locking your door.</important_idea><pb/>
            <question>So how do we make sure that our computers are secure?</question><pb/>We'll get
            to that shortly, but first let's understand why we are in a state of constant cyber
            threat. <roadmap> Better understanding <section_header>why there is
                    danger</section_header> will help us create a plan for <section_header>stopping
                    danger</section_header>. </roadmap><pb/>
            <section_header> Why There is Danger</section_header><pb/> If we negated threats
            stemming from the internet, the world wouldn't be devoid of cyber-danger, however the
            vast majority of problems would not exist. <scientific_principle n="1">There is nothing
                inherently scary about the internet, all it is, is the ability to transmit data
                between computers. <analogy>If we think of a computer as a person, the internet is
                    what gives it the ability to speak to any other person in the world. </analogy>
            </scientific_principle> The only issue with this, is that when the researchers who were
            designing what would one day be referred to as 'the internet' were working, they assumed
            that the world was this : <visual type="drawing" url="http://imgur.com/z8OdXVo"
                >Utopia</visual> when it is really sometimes closer to this : <visual type="drawing"
                url="http://imgur.com/Gj0E8SD">Dystopia</visual><pb/> Consequentially, all the
            security of the internet was not built into its underlying functionality at the time of
            its creation, but has been added in layers since then. While programmers do a great job
            of ensuring our data stays safe, <analogy>the situation is akin to a treadmill in which
                we must develop safety measures more quickly than bad guys can figure out how to
                subvert them.</analogy><pb/> While it is concerning to think of such a volatile
            battle for internet supremacy being waged of which you are victim to, as it happens you
            are not unable to fight in it. The largest issue here at present however, is the
            computer industry's failing at communicating to users how they should focus on defending
            themselves. For example, take this graphic : <visual type="other"
                url="http://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Beutler_Google_Security-practices-v6-640x471.png"
                >Ouch.</visual> Batting .200 isn't even good in baseball. Luckily the next section
            is going to help us to acquire the tools necessary to change that. </background>
        <answer>
            <section_header> Stopping Danger </section_header>
            <analogy>What if those "6 pack abs in 6 minutes" products actually worked? What if they
                were also free? You'd give it a go, right? Well, beefing up your security is kind of
                like those, except they work. </analogy>
            <visual type="photo" url="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/bVicgN12Pc0/maxresdefault.jpg">Your
                computer now.</visual><pb/> The situation described in the previous section may
            sound dire, however the fact of the matter is that <important_idea n="2"> there are a
                lot of tools already out there that you are either not using, or using incorrectly.
                You can change that for free, and a few hours of following
                instructions.</important_idea>
            <visual type="photo" url="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/bVicgN12Pc0/maxresdefault.jpg">Your
                computer in 4 hours.</visual><pb/>
            <roadmap>This workout plan has four categories: <section_header>1. Secure
                    Configuration</section_header>
                <section_header>2. Access control and Administrative Privilege
                    Management</section_header>
                <section_header>3. Patch Management</section_header>
                <section_header>4. Malware Protection</section_header>
            </roadmap>
            <visual type="other" url="http://imgur.com/dh7oJai"/>
            <section_header>1. Secure Configuration</section_header> This is our biggest concern, as
            reflected by the 'misc errors' category below. <visual type="other"
                url="http://imgur.com/5s0JKlx">Verizon 2015 Data Breach Report</visual><pb/>
            <analogy>If computer security were a house, and having a password is having a lock on
                your doors, secure configuration is having doors. Only have as many doors as you
                need. </analogy><pb/> 1. Any account on any electronic device (including default
            accounts) that isn't being used should be removed. Don't know why it's there? Remove it.
            <pb/>2. Don't use default passwords, swap them for a strong password. <pb/>3. Any
            applications you've had for years but haven't used; delete them. <pb/>4. The auto-run
            feature for USBs and other insertable media should be disabled. <pb/>5. Your computer
            has a firewall, turn it on. Got it? Good job. Now configure it to block unapproved
            connections by default. <pb/>
            <section_header>2. Access control and Administrative Privilege
                Management</section_header> This is having a registered you-know-what on your road,
            and telling your child to not take free candy from them. <pb/> 1. Give each account
            access to only what it NEEDS. You should have an admin account separate from your day to
            day account used to do computer maintenance. <pb/> 2. Admin accounts should only be used
            to perform legitimate admin activities, and should not be granted access to email or the
            internet. <pb/> 3. Change your admin password every few months. <pb/>4. Require
            passwords during log-in. <pb/><section_header>3. Patch Management</section_header><pb/>
            <analogy>This is making sure your house is being maintained. </analogy> Remember those
            good-guy programmers running on the treadmill? Well all that work they're doing is no
            good if you don't download the updates that they make to their code. <pb/> 1. Use only
            legally purchased so that you receive software updates. 2. Install these updates in a
            timely manner. Remember that scary story from 2014 about Heartbleed? <pb/>
            <visual type="drawing"
                url="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/d/dc/Heartbleed.svg/2000px-Heartbleed.svg.png"/>
            <pb/>An update solving this issue was made available within days of its update. A year
            later 33% of servers had failed to install this update. <important_idea>These servers
                are still vulnerable. </important_idea> 3. Remove software that is no longer being
            supported. <pb/>
            <section_header>4. Malware Protection</section_header> This is having an in house
            security team. <pb/> 1. Install anti-malware software on all computers that are capable
            of connecting to the internet. There are lots of free alternatives out there, I am
            currently using one called Sophos. <pb/>2. Configure software to scan all accessed files
            and web pages. <pb/> 3. Conduct a full scan of your computer every month. Going out for
            lunch for a few hours? Before leaving click the scan hard-drive button on your
            anti-malware program.<pb/>
            <conclusion> While even being aware of these steps isn't going to make you 100%
                impervious to the evil-doers of the internet, there is one last thing you've now got
                going for you. <visual type="comic" url="http://imgur.com/48SHE61">Sheep and
                    wolves</visual><pb/> As the old joke goes, you don't need to be faster than the
                bear, just faster than your friends. Even for an internet-evil-doer, stealing data
                can be difficult. Luckily for the internet-evil-doers, the average internet user
                isn't properly protected. There are plenty of unarmed sheep in the world, so they're
                much less likely to waste their time on you if you are vigilant with your
                protection.</conclusion>
        </answer>
        <pb/><sources>Wikipedia (yes wikipedia!) has as <ref type="source"
                url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/History_of_the_Internet">good a history of the
                internet as any.</ref> Lecture on the <ref type="source"
                url="http://www.inf.ed.ac.uk/teaching/courses/cs/1516/lects/Lecture02_CyberEssentials.pdf"
                >five step workout plan for computer security.</ref> Verizon's annual <ref
                type="supplement"
                url="http://www.verizonenterprise.com/verizon-insights-lab/dbir/2016/">data breach
                report.</ref>
        </sources>
    </blog_post>


    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="peer_id_here"/>
        <report type="peer" resp="#peer_id_here">
            <p>Peer review report will appear here.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
