<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Modeling and Producing Genre</title>
        <author xml:id="s_23">Monica Salas</author>
        <version n="1" date="2016-08-01"/>
    </docHead>

    <cover_letter>

        <header>
            <name>Monica Salas</name>
            <contact_info>
                <!-- One or More Contact -->
                <contact type="address">48 Saint Stephen St., Apt 4</contact>
                <contact type="address">Boston, MA 02115</contact>
                <contact type="phone"> 508-335-8828 </contact>
                <contact type="email"> monicasalas114@gmail.com </contact>
            </contact_info>
        </header>

        <greeting>Dear Hiring Committee: </greeting>

        <intro_para>
            <intent type="purpose">I am writing to apply for the MotorSports development engineer
                position at A123 Systems Inc. listed on Northeastern University’s job search
                website.</intent>
            <reason>I was excited to see a growing company invested in making progress into the
                future of clean energy in the automotive industry.</reason>
            <proposition>I have experience<note type="instructor" resp="#kgs">in this type of
                    position?</note> with startups similar to A123 and find that I am most driven in
                such an environment. </proposition>
        </intro_para>

        <para_background>
            <experience type="work">Working at Amphenol PCD, I was introduced to the types of
                standards mandated by military and aerospace industries. The rigorous standards
                implemented on us by ITAR and military arms suppliers taught me the importance of
                well-organized and effective documentation. This job is also where I became
                accomplished using <programs>Pro-E/Creo</programs> and implementing <skills>quality
                    control processes</skills>. </experience>
        </para_background>

        <para_background>
            <experience type="work">While working at Infinium, Inc., I worked on a small research
                team refining a process to create primary aluminum via electrolysis. I modelled in
                    <programs>AutoCAD Inventor</programs> and helped to <skills>build
                    infrastructure</skills> for the developing process. I also performed material
                compatibility tests and <skills>post experiment analysis using x-ray diffraction,
                    scanning electron microscopy, and data analysis</skills> in
                    <programs>MatLab.</programs>
            </experience>
        </para_background>

        <para_background>
            <experience type="school">Aside from my work experience, I am a recent student at
                Northeastern University. In my labs and classes, I have developed strong technical
                writing and communication skills, the ability to work effectively with teams of
                people, and resourceful problem solving skills. </experience>
        </para_background>

        <para_closing>
            <compatability>I believe I work best in a fast paced, energetic environment and think I
                would be able to integrate well into a team like A123 Systems' MotorSports. </compatability>
            <next_step>I would welcome the opportunity to further discuss the position and my
                qualifications in the near future. </next_step>
            <acknowledgment>Thank you very much for your consideration! </acknowledgment>
        </para_closing>

        <signature>
            <salutation>Sincerely,</salutation>
            <pb/>
            <pb/>
            <pb/>
            <name>Monica Salas</name>
        </signature>

    </cover_letter>


    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="s_25"/>
        <report type="peer" resp="#s_25">
            <p>The peer review report is in response to a cover letter written to express interest
                for a development engineering job at A123 Systems. </p>
            <p>I believe this cover letter does a great job identifying why you are a great
                candidate for this role. Several examples and qualifications are offered which
                relate to specific points in the job description. However, one possible point of
                improvement would be stating how the job is a great fit for you. The sentences
                inside of the reason element state an interest in the general industry and general
                work environment of the company, so it might make sense to include information that
                might be more specific to this particular job.</p>
            <p>Moving on, I believe the first background paragraph is well written and does a great
                job of highlighting experience that very closely matches the job description. I
                believe that your second background paragraph should be more like the first in that
                it should highlight the most relevant experiences rather than describe exactly what
                you worked on. For example, your last sentence in that paragraph lists a several
                methods of analysis (“x-ray diffraction, scanning electron microscopy, and data
                analysis in MatLab”) which may not be useful to the company based on the job
                description and experience and education listed in the posting. It might make sense
                to add to this paragraph or replace this sentence completely with one that describes
                one of your qualifications that relates to the job opening.</p>
            <p>I believe you also do a great job connecting your skills school experience in your
                third background paragraph. However, placing myself as the hiring committee in this
                particular rhetorical situation, most of the information you provide in this
                paragraph seems to be pretty standard and generic, which would not make you stand
                out in the applicant pool, especially if they are from the same university. If
                possible, I would suggest adding more specifics that might separate your experience,
                or make it more technically relevant to the job description. Additionally, if you
                can add more information in your second background paragraph, you may be able to
                completely get rid of your third paragraph.</p>
            <p>Finally, I think your closing paragraph is very good the way it is. I noticed this in
                my writing as well, but it might make sense to add an optional “thank you” element
                inside of this paragraph, since this seems to be common in many cover letters.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Your XML document is not valid--8 errors, though it looks like all of those are
                because you failed to update the element name for the last paragraph to
                closing_statements, according to your team's revision. The other issue here is that
                your revised version came in a few hours after the due date (8/9 by class time).
                Aside from those two issues, this is an excellent example of a cover letter. It is
                specific, both about the company to which you are applying and your own experience,
                while remaining personal. Well done.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
