<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Writing Project 2</title>
        <author xml:id="s25">Leo Stolov</author>
        <version n="1" date="2016-08-01"/>
    </docHead>

    <cover_letter>
        <header>
            <name>Leo Stolov</name>
            <contact_info>
                <!-- One or More Contact -->
                <contact type="address">606 Columbus Ave #3R Boston, MA 02118</contact>
                <contact type="phone"> 860-519-9771 </contact>
                <contact type="email"> stolov.l@husky.neu.edu </contact>
            </contact_info>
        </header>
        <greeting>Dear Joshua Elvander,</greeting>

        <intro_para>
            <intent type="purpose">I am writing to express my interest in the mechanical engineering
                fall internship position, which I found through Northeastern's co-op
                network.</intent>
            <reason> I am approaching my fourth year as a BS/MS candidate for Mechanical Engineering
                with a concentration in Mechatronics and am eager to gain more hands-on experience
                in new industries.</reason>
            <proposition>I believe my previous experience and passion for automation and
                interdisciplinary work make me an ideal candidate for this role.</proposition>
        </intro_para>

        <para_background>
            <experience type="work">During my time at Portal Instruments, another start up in the
                area, I worked on a <accomplishments>complex electromechanical assembly, which was
                    later used as a in human studies for a needle-free drug delivery
                    device.</accomplishments> This project involved a lot of independent
                    <skills>design, fabrication, and testing,</skills> which I believe is not unlike
                the work I would be doing at Piaggio. At my last co-op at Bio-Rad,
                    <accomplishments>I worked mostly independently on a piece of automation
                    equipment, meant to automate a complex manufacturing process of a DNA sequencing
                    consumable.</accomplishments> This involved the integration of
                    <skills>mechanical, electrical, and software disciplines</skills>. Specifically,
                this meant extensive experience with <skills>CAD design of precision parts,
                    wiring,</skills> and <programs>programming a TRIO motion
                controller.</programs></experience>
        </para_background>

        <para_background>
        <experience type="personal">In addition to my work experience, I also participate in
                AIAA, where I have begun to help with the <skills>mechanical design of an RC plane
                    as well as the electrical and software implementation of several
                    components.</skills> This involves more <skills>Solidworks design, as well as
                    learning how to read various sensors such as altimeters and gyroscopes using an
                    Arduino.</skills></experience>
       </para_background>

        <closing_statements>

            <compatability> My previous supervisors have described me as a self motivated worker
                with an eagerness to learn, which I believe would make me a great fit for the start
                up environment of Piaggio.</compatability>
            <next_step>I would appreciate an opportunity to meet with you to discuss my
                qualifications in further detail. </next_step>
            <acknowledgment>Thank you for your consideration, and I look forward to speaking with
                you soon.</acknowledgment>

        </closing_statements>

        <signature>
            <salutation>Sincerely,</salutation>
            <name>Leo Stolov</name>
        </signature>
    </cover_letter>

    <writers_memo> 1) What is going well? The cover letter is not too difficult of a document to
        write, and its seem to have a fairly decent flow at this point. I am pretty satisfied with
        my intro and closing paragraph. 2) What has been difficult so far? I have found it difficult
        to try to figure out what to include and not include about myself, as well as the level of
        detail I should be elaborating on my experiences. I have always had a challenging time
        talking about myself, so the background paragraph has probably been the most difficult.
        3)Where are you in your process? I have completed a draft which I would be ok with sending
        to the company if I had to, but I would like to add more information and possibly refine
        some of my vocabulary and sentence structure. 4) Specific areas/aspects of the draft (2-3)
        The background paragraph is the most important part of the document in my opinion, so I
        would like to focus on improving or adding upon it. Many, if not most of the cover letters
        we looked at had two paragraphs for this part so it might make sense to try to add one. </writers_memo>

    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="s23"/>
        <report type="peer" resp="#s23">
            <p>This cover letter conveys interest in a fall internship position at a engineering
                start up at Piaggio. The writer emphasises his experience in electromechanical
                assemblies and automation as well as his willingness and drive to learn through
                hands on work.</p>
            <p>I agree that your introductory and closing paragraphs are both very strong and
                probably don't need much editting. They work really well in conveying what you want
                and what your strengths are. The only recommendation I might make would be to
                mention the company name in your first sentence. This seems to be convention in
                cover letters, and it will clarify exactly what job you're writing this letter
                for.</p>
            <p>I also agree that your background paragraph(s) should be developed a little further.
                I think it would be worth it to dedicate a paragraph to each of your co-ops; or
                atleast one paragraph for both your co-ops and one for AIAA (which should probably
                be spelled out because I don't know what exactly it is). I think that between these
                three different experiences you've probably gained a lot of skills and made a lot of
                accomplishments. This is your opportunity to expand upon your experiences more than
                just listing what they were like in your resume. The manager you are writing to is
                definitely going to have experience with automation, design, electronics,
                software,etc. especially at a start up like Piaggo is. If you can talk about at
                least one major skill that you learned or one major accomplishment that you achieved
                at each co-op and in AIAA then it is probably a safe bet that the manager will have
                questions for you about it. It will be a method of selling your skills and
                qualifications in your cover letter, setting yourself apart from other applicants,
                as well as having some control/influence over the interview conversation before you
                even get there. If there are specific engineering/automation programs that you have
                learned to use, that would probably be helpful to mention as well, because it would
                be one less thing you would have to learn for a job at Piaggo.</p>
            <p>Overall, I think you have a great set up for a cover letter, and very effective
                introduction and closing paragraphs. With more details about your experience and
                qualifications I'd say you are all set. You followed and took advantage of most of
                the elements in our schema very effectively. Reading through your cover letter made
                me notice that we could probably have included more sub elements under "experience"
                to guide the writer through what to include in experience paragraphs. Maybe we can
                consider breaking down 'experience' into sub elements like 'skills' 'certifications'
                'accomplishments' 'projects, or something along those lines. </p>

        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
