<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Lose Your Computer Security Insecurity</title>
        <author xml:id="s24">Oliver Scott</author>
        <version n="num_of_version" date="2016-07-31"/>
    </docHead>

    <blog_post>
        <background> Computer security, <misconceptions> the words somehow feel like they belong to
                two types of people: 1) Malicious computer hackers who can cause servers to melt
                worldwide with the casual swipe of their fingers and a sip of mountain dew. 2) The
                office IT worker who can transform you into a narcoleptic with a stained oversized
                white t-shirt and a one sided discussion about the merits of the Hutt's mafioso
                control of Tatooine's water supplies. </misconceptions> Consequentially, when the
            topic of computer security arises, the average computer user's eyes glaze over whilst
            simultaneously running away at Olympic gold medal speeds. <pb/> This is bad. We (almost)
            use computers, and its our responsibility to help keep them safe. <analogy>Who's at
                fault if you get in an car accident when you're driving without a license. Who's at
                fault if you leave your door open every day and come home one day to find out you've
                been robbed? </analogy> As you likely know, a lot of your important stuff is on a
            computer somewhere. <important_idea n="1">What you might not know, is that avoiding
                having this stuff stolen is not hard nor time intensive, it can be as easy as
                putting on a seatbelt or locking your door.</important_idea><pb/>
            <question>So how do we make sure that our computers are secure?</question> We'll get to
            that shortly, but first let's understand why we are in a state of constant cyber threat.
                <roadmap> Better understanding <section_header>why there is danger</section_header>
                will help us create a plan for <section_header>stopping danger</section_header>. </roadmap><pb/>
            <section_header> Why There is Danger</section_header> If we negated threats stemming
            from the internet, the world wouldn't be devoid of cyber-danger, however the vast
            majority of problems would certainly not exist. <scientific_principle n="1">There is
                nothing inherently scary about the internet, all it is, is the ability to transmit
                data between computers. <analogy>If we think of a computer as a person, the internet
                    is what gives it the ability to speak to any other person in the world.
                </analogy>
            </scientific_principle> The only issue with this, is that when the researchers who were
            designing what would one day be referred to as 'the internet' were working, they assumed
            that the world was this : <visual type="drawing" url="http://imgur.com/z8OdXVo"
                >Utopia</visual> when it is really sometimes a bit closer to this : <visual
                type="drawing" url="http://imgur.com/Gj0E8SD">Dystopia</visual><pb/>
            Consequentially, all the security of the internet was not designed into its underlying
            functionality, but has been added in layers since then. While programmers do a great job
            of ensuring our data stays safe, <analogy>the situation is akin to a treadmill in which
                we must develop safety measures more quickly than bad guys can figure out how to
                subvert them.</analogy><important_idea n="2"/><analogy/><pb/> While it is concerning
            to think of such a volatile battle for internet supremacy being waged of which you are
            victim to, as it happens you are not unable to fight in it. The largest issue here at
            present however, is the computer industry's failing at communicating to users how they
            should focus on defending themselves. For example, take this graphic : <visual
                type="other"
                url="http://cdn.arstechnica.net/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Beutler_Google_Security-practices-v6-640x471.png"
                >Ouch.</visual> Batting .200 isn't even good in baseball. Luckily the next section
            is going to help us to acquire the tools necessary to change that. </background>
        <answer>
            <section_header> Stopping Danger </section_header>
            <analogy>What if those "6 pack abs in 6 minutes" products actually worked? What if they
                were also free? You'd give it a go, right? Well beefing up your security is kind of
                like that. </analogy>
            <visual type="photo" url="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/bVicgN12Pc0/maxresdefault.jpg">Your
                computer now.</visual><pb/> The situation described in the previous section may
            sound dire, however the fact of the matter is that there are a lot of tools already out
            there that you are either not using, or using incorrectly. You can change that for free,
            and a few hours of following instructions. <visual type="photo"
                url="https://i.ytimg.com/vi/bVicgN12Pc0/maxresdefault.jpg">Your computer in 4
                hours.</visual><pb/>
            <roadmap>This workout plan has five categories: <section_header>1. Secure
                    Configuration</section_header>
                <section_header>2. Boundary Firewalls and Internet Gateways</section_header>
                <section_header>3. Access control and Administrative Privilege
                    Management</section_header>
                <section_header>4. Patch Management</section_header>
                <section_header>5. Malware Protection</section_header>
            </roadmap>
            <section_header>1. Secure Configuration</section_header> This is our biggest concern.
                <analogy>If computer security were a house, and having a password is having a lock
                on your doors, secure configuration is having doors.</analogy> 1. Unnecessary user
            accounts should be removed or disabled. 2. Any default password for a user account
            should be changed to an alternative, strong password. 3. Unnecessary software should be
            removed or disabled. 4. The auto-run feature should be disabled. 5. A personal firewall
            (or equivalent) should be enabled on desktop PCs and laptops, and configured to disable
            (block) unapproved connections by default. <section_header>2. Boundary Firewalls and
                Internet Gateways</section_header> This is having a gate around your house.
                <section_header>3. Access control and Administrative Privilege
                Management</section_header> This is having a registered you-know-what on your road,
            and telling your child it's okay to take free candy. <section_header>4. Patch
                Management</section_header> This is making sure your house is being maintained. Bear
            in mind, in this world you live in a permanent hurricane, but you're the god/goddess of
            handymen/women. <section_header>5. Malware Protection</section_header> This is having an in house security team.
            <section_header/><pb/><fundamental_science_involved n="1"/><question_relevant_topic
                n="1"> </question_relevant_topic><important_idea n="2"> </important_idea>
            <important_idea n="3"/>
            <fundamental_science_involved n="2"/>
            <question_relevant_topic n="2"/>
            <important_idea n="3"/><pb/><analogy/>
            <fundamental_science_involved n="3"/><pb/><pb/><analogy/><pb/>
            <explanation n="1"><analogy/>
            </explanation><pb/><explanation n="2"/><pb/><explanation n="3"/>
            <conclusion> While even being aware of these steps isn't going to make you 100%
                impervious to the evil-doers of the internet, there is one last thing you've now got
                going for you. <visual type="comic" url="http://imgur.com/48SHE61">Sheep and
                    wolves</visual><pb/> As the old joke goes, you don't need to be faster than the
                bear, just faster than your friends. Even for an internet-evil-doer, stealing data
                can be difficult. Luckily for the internet-evil-doers, the average internet user
                isn't properly protected. There are plenty of unarmed sheep in the world, so they're
                much less likely to waste their time on you.</conclusion>
        </answer>
        <pb/><sources>Wikipedia (yes wikipedia!) has as <ref type="source"
                url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/History_of_the_Internet">good a history of the
                internet as any.</ref> Lecture on the <ref type="source"
                url="http://www.inf.ed.ac.uk/teaching/courses/cs/1516/lects/Lecture02_CyberEssentials.pdf"
                >five step workout plan for computer security.</ref> Verizon's annual <ref
                type="supplement"
                url="http://www.verizonenterprise.com/verizon-insights-lab/dbir/2016/">data breach
                report.</ref>
        </sources>
    </blog_post>


    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="peer_id_here"/>
        <report type="peer" resp="#peer_id_here">
            <p>Peer review report will appear here.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
