<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Project 2 - Djordje</title>
        <author xml:id="v_26">Djordje Vlajkovic</author>
        <version n="2" date="2016-08-09"/>
    </docHead>

    <pub_init_proposal>
        <cover_page>
            <title>Tennis Court Building Initiative</title>
            <author>Djordje Vlajkovic</author>
            <submit_date>8/9/2016</submit_date>
            <audience>Boston City Council</audience>
        </cover_page>

        <tbl_cont>
            <section n="1"> Introduction </section>
            <section n="2"> Background </section>
            <section n="3"> Purpose </section>
            <section n="4"> Approach </section>
            <section n="5"> Feasibility </section>
            <section n="6"> Conclusion </section>
            <section n="7"> References </section>
        </tbl_cont>

        <intro type="ltr_int">
            <p>In Boston, there are a variety of public areas where one can choose to participate in
                sports. But for some sports, it is more difficult to find a place to play, tennis
                being one of them. Because of the lack of courts in the city and crowdedness of the
                existing courts, many people are unable to have the opportunity to play. This leaves
                many limited options on when and where they can play. The premise of this
                    proposal<note type="instructor" resp="#kgs">you are missing a verb in this
                    sentence, probably "is"</note> to expand the number of tennis courts in the
                city, so that more individuals can have the opportunity to participate in the
                sport.</p>
        </intro>

        <background>
            <p>
                <crnt_cond> In today's Boston, there are a few places where someone can go out and
                    play a game of tennis<note type="instructor" resp="#kgs">do you have any
                        information on how many courts there are?</note>. But from the already
                    limited amounts of courts in the city and the courts that are owned by private
                    facilities, there are not many options for the public to choose from<note
                        type="instructor" resp="#kgs">again, some data would be helpful here, are
                        there particular neghborhoods that have more or less?</note>. For the courts
                    that are available to the public, they usually fill quickly and may be out of
                    the way for some. These factors make it difficult for people to go out with a
                    friend and play a game of tennis. </crnt_cond> With these kinds of existing
                issues, it seems unfair that the average person can't just go out and have a good
                time at the tennis courts without worrying about where or when to go. <subj_hist> In
                    the United States, tennis is a sport with smaller community that belongs to the
                    very talented or those who are reasonably wealthy enough to afford the necessary
                    equipment, lessons, and facilities that are usually required to play the sport.
                    But for those individuals who do not have the luxury of falling into those
                    categories, it leaves them from experiencing the sport. </subj_hist>
            </p>
        </background>

        <purpose>
            <p>What we hope to achieve at the end of this project is to give the community more
                opportunities to play tennis<note type="instructor" resp="#kgs">why tennis? why not
                    basketball? or squash or volleyball? This would seem to be an important part of
                    the purpose to me.</note>. Looking ahead at the scheduling for this project,
                    <scope type="when">the expected time table would probably be over the course of
                    a few months to half a year. If everything goes accordingly, the tennis courts
                    should be ready by spring of next year. </scope> In terms of an overall
                objective, <objective> we are insisting on is building four to six tennis court
                    sites throughout the Back Bay area<note type="instructor" resp="#kgs"/>why this
                    area?. These courts would all be nicely furnished and reflect a high standard in
                    condition. </objective> The benefits a project like this bring are: <goal> the
                    reduction of crowded courts throughout the city, uptick in the amount of
                    individuals playing tennis, convenience of location for many and increase in the
                    opportunities to lead a healthier lifestyle. </goal>
            </p>
        </purpose>

        <approach>
            <!--attribute options: execution, action-->
            <p>
                <action>The first step in the project would be getting the proposal approved by the
                    city council. Once the project is green lit, we will come up with a budget of
                    roughly $15 million to accommodate the tasks and resources that will be
                    necessary to the completion of these tennis courts. Once receiving approval on
                    the budget, the next phase would be to buy up areas around the city and get the
                    proper legal paperwork that will enable us to work without any issues. From
                    there, a construction company will be hired and begin work once all of the
                    necessary documentation has been set in order. After construction is wrapped up,
                    necessary precautions will be made to see that all safety regulations are met
                    and that all of the courts meet regulation sizes. </action>
            </p>
        </approach>

        <feasibility>
            <!--attribute options: economic, social, environmental-->
            <p>
                <environmental> One of the main obstacles to this project will be finding the right
                    areas to build these courts. The first thing to make sure of would be building
                    these courts away from other existing courts in the city<note type="instructor"
                        resp="#kgs">this begs the question, again, of why Back Bay?</note>. The
                    other parameters for location would be finding a place in the city where it
                    would be easily accessible for anyone. This means minimal traffic around the
                    area and multiple entrances and exits. The main obstacle that will come with
                    building these courts will be obtaining the necessary zoning and construction
                        permits<note type="instructor" resp="#kgs">The funding won't be an
                        issue?</note>. But if we can find the right area to build and meet all of
                    the requirements given by the city, this project will be possible.<note
                        type="instructor" resp="#kgs">this is a small point, but is possibility the
                        same thing as feasibility?</note>
                </environmental>
            </p>
        </feasibility>

        <conclu>
            <p> Building these courts will give people throughout the city<note type="instructor"
                    resp="#kgs">but especially in Back Bay</note> more chances to play tennis and
                introduce others to the sport. It will provide many with a more convenient locations
                and give people who may have lacked the opportunity before to play. This project
                will also give people another way to stay active and maintain a healthier lifestyle.
                Lastly it will lead to a resurgence in the popularity of tennis as a sport in
                Boston. Overall this opportunity will lead to renaissance for tennis within the
                community and give opportunities for many to play whenever.<note type="instructor"
                    resp="#kgs">why is this good for the city?</note>
            </p>
        </conclu>

        <references>
            <citation n="1" style="MLA">Lawrence, Merlisa. "Why Is American Tennis Dying?" Bleacher
                Report. N.p., 21 Nov. 2013. Web. 01 Aug. 2016.</citation>
            <citation n="2" style="MLA">Sopher, Philip. "Explaining the U.S. Tennis Slump." The
                Atlantic. Atlantic Media Company, 22 Aug. 2014. Web. 01 Aug. 2016.</citation>
            <citation n="3" style="MLA">"Tennis Court Construction Basics." Tennis Court and Play
                Court Construction Basics, Dimensions. N.p., n.d. Web. 07 Aug. 2016.</citation>
        </references>
    </pub_init_proposal>

    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="d13">Daniel Doherty</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" resp="#d13">
            <p>This proposal suggests that the sport of tennis is not easily accessible for many
                citizens of Boston as a result of a variety of economic, cultural and logistical
                factors that have resulted in the sport only being enjoyed by a select group of the
                population. It mainly focused on the logistical fact that there are not enough
                public courts in the city, which has prevented many people from having a chance to
                try the sport of tennis as there are no courts close enough to their neighborhoods
                and the ones that do exist are overcrowded.</p>
            <p>This proposal contains the necessary information and content of the genre but can be
                improved upon by the addition of additional details in the approach and feasibility
                sections. By adding detail to the expected costs of the project and which areas of
                the city would benefit most from the construction of tennis courts, the project
                would have more depth of analysis by highlighting the benefits the addition courts
                could provide. You state, "The other parameters for location would be finding a
                place in the city where it would be easily accessible by anyone, having minimal
                traffic around the area, and having it in a safer area." What specific areas in the
                city meet this criteria and why are these three things important to the success of
                the project. I believe some further discussion of this aspect of the project would
                greatly contribute to the strength of your argument.</p>
            <p>At certain times in the proposal, specifically in the introduction and background,
                the sentences do not flow well from one to another. Simply, there are many times
                when a sentence ends rather abruptly, and the next sentence starts with the word but
                or and, adding a qualifying statement for the sentence prior. By combining the
                sentences that relate to each other, the document will flow better and reduce
                unnecessary verbiage. Additionally, the sentences in this proposal are mostly
                passive statements, using phases like "probably would", "but if we" and so on. The
                genre of a proposal is at its most basic level a call to action, and using passive
                words weaken the argument by introducing some uncertainty into the situation. In the
                conclusion, you switch to using statements like "this project will" which gives the
                proposal a more powerful and convincing tone and I think you can use more of this
                throughout the document.</p>
            <p>One final suggestions is to perform some additional proofreading, specifically for
                grammar throughout the document. There are some sentences that word things
                awkwardly. This draft of a proposal is a strong start that could benefit with some
                additional information to expand upon the approach and benefits of implementation,
                and some editing to improve the flow of the proposal.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>There is a lot going well here. I think the topic and audience make sense for the
                genre. I think, on the whole, I would have liked to have seen a bit more
                justification for the specific proposal: why tennis and not some other sport? why
                Back Bay and not, perhaps, some less affluent neighborhoods? Pay close attention to
                the notes I added above in-text. Good work here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
