<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Writing Project 2 - Phase 2</title>
        <author xml:id="v26">Michael Van Wickle</author>
        <version n="1" date="2016-08-01"/>
    </docHead>

    <fsb_rpt>
        <!-- container element for writing project 2. Contains any number of pages. -->
        <page type="ttl">
            <title>Distributed Weather Data Collection System: Feasibility Report</title>
            <date>August 1st, 2016</date>
            <contributors>Michael Van Wickle</contributors>
        </page>

        <page type="tbl_contents">
            <sect n="1">Executive Summary</sect>
            <sect n="2">Preliminary Requirements Analysis</sect>
            <sect n="2" lvl="1">Application Overview</sect>
            <sect n="2" lvl="2">Objectives</sect>
            <!-- Check n values -->
            <sect n="3">Technical Feasibility</sect>
            <sect n="3" lvl="1">Overview</sect>
            <sect n="4">Success Criteria</sect>
            <sect n="5">Conclusion</sect>
            <sect n="5" lvl="1">Feasibility</sect>
            <sect n="5" lvl="1">Feasibility Conditions</sect>
            <sect n="5" lvl="1">Summary</sect>
            <!-- Intentionally leaving out Design, Report, Risk Analysis, and Financial (optional)?  -->
            <!-- Include "Cost" in table of contents since it's in the report below -->
        </page>

        <page type="exec_sum"> The system outlined in this study is a distributed method for the
            collection of weather-related data. The system consists of a network of
            micro-controllers with attached sensors to measure temperature and pressure. Associated
            with this system is a web application for the viewing and acquisition of collected data.
            The distributed nature of the system allows for a more granular view of weather data,
            allowing for better reporting and prediction of weather patterns. In addition, this
            system will attempt to be as open as possible as to effect the best possible analysis.
            Based on preliminary research, this project is feasible. </page>

        <page type="pre_req_ana">
            <app_ovr type="obj"> The primary functionality provided is a system that collects
                weather data, specifically temperature and pressure, in a highly distributed manner.
                Micro-controllers will host the sensors that directly collect data; they will also
                contain networking functionality in order to send data to a centralized database.
                The data will be exposed to the public via a web application. Features provided by
                the web application include direct download of the data and visualizations based on
                the data. </app_ovr>
        </page>

        <page type="fsb">
            <fsb_hlgt type="tcnl" n="1"> This project has two broad components, the sensor and the
                web applications. The sensor portion is composed of a micro-controller and multiple
                sensors. The micro-controller will also have some form of network connection and
                possibly some form of rudimentary data filtering mechanism. Network connectivity
                will be in the form of an ad-hoc network between all of the devices, with certain
                devices used as "exit nodes" which connect to the internet at large in order to
                upload to a central database and, by extension, the web application. Sensors to be
                included are for temperature (thermometer) and pressure (barometer). Data sent to
                the central database will be a timestamp, location data, and the data collected by
                the sensors. The web application is build on top of a database containing the data
                sent from the sensors. The two main features for the web application are data
                download and visualization creation. </fsb_hlgt>
        </page>

        <page type="sccs_crt">
            <req_sect> Sensors <req> Micro-Controller: The base platform, essentially a small
                    computer which provides power to all of the other components. It also may
                    contain some basic data filtering software in order to prune noise from the
                    collected data. </req>
                <req> Network Connectivity: The sensors will be connected via an ad-hoc network
                    model. In this model, most units will only be connected to other units.
                    Pre-programed into each unit, will be the routing data which provides a path to
                    a unit that has connection to the actual internet (an "exit node"). Thus, each
                    unit will push its data towards the unit that is "closer" to an "exit node"
                    until the data is pushed to the database. </req>
                <req> Temperature Sensor: A basic thermometer, this will collect the temperature at
                    an appropriate precision. </req>
                <req> Pressure Sensor: A barometer, this will collect pressure data at an
                    appropriate precision. </req>
                <req> Location Data: In order for the system to work, each sensor must have its own
                    location. This will be programmed in upon installation, likely in the form of a
                    latitude, longitude pair. </req>
            </req_sect>
            <!-- I think that req_sect can only be used once -->
            <req_sect> Web Application <req> User Interface: The user interface should provide easy
                    and intuitive access to all of the functionality provided. The interface should
                    be optimized for use on desktop computers of all screen sizes. It also should
                    have at least the basic ability to be used on mobile devices. </req>
                <req> Data Download: Data download is the ability to pull ranges of data and
                    possibly all data from the database. Also provided is the ability to download
                    data in many different formats. </req>
                <req> Visualizations: This feature will create various forms of visual
                    representations of the data. This includes map overlays of the data, animations
                    of the data, and various charts that show changes in the data over time. </req>
            </req_sect>
        </page>

        <page type="cost">
            <est type="fnc"> This sensors could use many commercial off the shelf products. For the
                micro-controller, an Arduino based chip could be used. These kinds of controllers
                are widely available and have the additional advantage of being open-source.The
                cheapest appropriate model would be rather expensive at fifteen to twenty dollars,
                but that price could go down as the boards are bought in bulk. Sensors provided by
                the Arduino project could also be used. A temperature sensor costs around one dollar
                and fifty cents and a pressure sensor costs around five dollars. Both of these
                prices, as with the chip, could go down with bulk purchases. The most expensive
                piece of equipment to buy would be network connectivity module, which would likely
                cost more than twenty dollars. Assuming a cost of twenty dollars for both the chip
                and the network module, this adds up to an overall cost of about forty seven dollars
                per unit. This price seems quite restrictive on the surface, but the price could
                decrease with bulk pricing and/or the possible development of specialized
                micro-controllers. </est>
            <est type="fnc"> The costs for the web application consist of payment to developers and
                hosting fees. </est>
        </page>

        <page type="conc">
            <fsb> Based on preliminary research, this project seems to be technologically feasible.
                From a practical perspective, these systems should be designed to be deployed in
                small segments, e.g., a neighborhood, as deploying in a entire city at one time
                would be fiscally and technically challenging. </fsb>
            <cond> The main hurdle to any actual implementation of this project is funding. A
                significant amount of the funding to this project would likely need to be public.
                The need for public funding necessitates a campaign in order to drum up general
                support for this project. </cond>
            <sum> This is a project that would provide more granular and open granular weather data.
                The described implementation is made of commercially available, common parts. This
                system is quite feasible in the current environment. </sum>
        </page>

    </fsb_rpt>

    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="m19"/>
        <report type="peer" resp="#m19">
            <p>For Project 2, Michael wrote a feasibility report for a distributed weather data
                collection system which he believes is feasible. This system consists of a network
                to measure temperature and pressure and a web application to collect and view the
                data. ere.</p>
            <p>A feasibility report would be written in response to the question of a project or
                idea being feasible, and these reports include logical, factual data to support
                their claims. Michael’s writing for Project 2 follows this genre, as shown by his
                explanation of his project, his supporting evidence, and his position that it is
                feasible. As an expert in this genre, Michael’s sentences are appropriate. They
                communicate facts of his weather data collection system in a direct manner, and they
                do not include emotional pleas to support his belief that his project is feasible.
                His word choices are appropriate as they deal with many technical aspects of his
                project. For example, he details system components like micro-controllers, data
                visualization, and exit nodes. One major missing piece is a section for risk
                analysis. This is important to a feasibility report so that any major concerns over
                the project can be addressed. This helps answer if a project is feasible despite
                possible complications. Another element that could be included is a design. Some
                type of diagram could show how the sensor network could communicate with a central
                database and eventually a web application. Also a report section could be added to
                detail how progress would be reported on the project. </p>
            <p>Overall, the structure of Michael’s feasibility report conforms to the schema that
                our group created. He mentioned in his peer review memo that he was concerned that
                he used too many idioms. However, I did not see this, and I believe that his
                language and sentences were appropriate. Michael also had questions about the
                distinction between the preliminary requirements and success criteria section. I
                think that his success criteria section was effective in showing the different
                components of his project. However, I think that to differentiate the preliminary
                requirements from it, he could add information for types rls (rules and regulations
                encountered) and synergy (how his project interacts with any existing systems).
                Lastly I think that he could add the missing elements referenced earlier in order to
                make his feasibility report more complete. </p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
