<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Project Proposal</title>
        <author xml:id="your_id_here">Samantha Wagner</author>
        <version n="1" date="2016-07-31"/>
    </docHead>

    <pub_init_proposal>
        <cover_page>
            <title>City Center Park Redesign</title>
            <author>JPP Egineering and Urban Planning</author>
            <submit_date>September 1st 2016</submit_date>
            <audience> Members of the board of trustees and residants of the city of Kirkland
                Washington </audience>
        </cover_page>

        <tbl_cont>
            <section n="1">Introduction</section>
            <section n="2">Background</section>
            <section n="3">Purpose</section>
            <section n="4">Action Plan</section>
            <section n="5">Feasibility</section>
            <section n="6">Conclusion</section>
        </tbl_cont>

        <intro type="abstract">
            <!--attribute options: ltr_int, exec_sum, abstract-->
            <p><!--text to be typed at the end here--></p>
        </intro>

        <background>
            <p>
                <crnt_cond> Located at 111 Waverly Way in Kirkland, City Center Park currently
                    serves as the city's second largest communal gathering space within city limits.
                    The large expanse of land has become overgrown with weeds and blackberry bushes.
                    <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
                </crnt_cond>
                <subj_hist> As the site of the former junior high school which burned down in 1987,
                    this land was left in disrepair for over a year before members of the local
                    neighborhoods banned together to bring purpose back to the land. Over the years
                    since the fire, different features have been added progressively. Starting with
                    the creation of the winding path up to a senic lookout point over Lake
                    Washington and then building a small play ground out of local recycled
                    materials. The potential of this space is obvious to those who live around
                    it.<!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
                </subj_hist>
            </p>
        </background>

        <purpose>
            <p>
                <scope type="when"> In the summer of 2017, the city of Kenmore hopes to begin
                    construction on the vacant lot turned community park in hopes of realizing its
                    value to the community and the organizations within it. </scope>
                <!--attribute options: what, who, when, where-->
                <scope type="who"> When completed this project will bring greatly added value to the
                    city and to its residence in many forms. </scope>
                <objective> The proposed project includes a multi-purpose turf sports feild with
                    small grandstand seating to serve as a practice area and play space for local
                    teams. It will include a ecofriendly play space by updating and reinforcing the
                    existing structure made out of local recycled materials. The existing lookout
                    point at the top of the park's hill will be enhanced with a sculptural totem
                    pole designed and carved by local artists and craftsman. All of which will be
                    surrounded by patches of community gardens for town residents to manage and
                    attend to. <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
                </objective>
            </p>
            <p>
                <goal> The goals of redesigning city center park are to: - Preserve, protect, and
                    improve parkland and recreational opportunities. - Anticipate the needs of the
                    changing community and structure programs and facilities accordingly. - Enhance
                    the city’s arts, cultural and historic assets. - Enrich the lives of residents.
                    - And build a healthier community. </goal>
            </p>
        </purpose>

        <approach type="action">
            <!--attribute options: execution, action-->
            <p> </p>
        </approach>

        <feasibility type="economic">
            <!--attribute options: economic, social, environmental-->
            <p> Economic: Over the past five years the city of Kirkland has set aside a small budget
                each year to be put towards city redevelopment and improvement projects. Although
                this fund will not cover the entire cost of the project, it along with a number of
                donations from members of the community and local companies will cover the
                relatively low costs of this project. Much of the groundwork for this park has
                already been laid over the past 20 to 30 years through the small neighborhood
                improvement projects that have taken place. The main cost for this improvement will
                be the leveling and placement of the multipurpose terf sports field. Otherwise art
                fixtures and building materials will be made of primarily donated or local recycled
                materials and repurposed for the park fixtures. Social: Community backing for this
                project has already... </p>
            <!-- would ideally like to be able to make this multiple paragraphs and/or have the ability to put in mulitple feasability sections in order to cover economic, social AND enviro aspects.-->
        </feasibility>

        <conclu>
            <p> Conclusion: <!--text here-->
            </p>
        </conclu>

        <references>
            <citation n="" style="MLA"> </citation>
        </references>
    </pub_init_proposal>

    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="peer_id_here"/>
        <report type="peer" resp="#peer_id_here">
            <p>Peer review report will appear here.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
