<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Project Proposal</title>
        <author xml:id="your_id_here">Samantha Wagner</author>
        <version n="1" date="2016-07-31"/>
    </docHead>

    <pub_init_proposal>
        <cover_page>
            <title>City Center Park Redesign</title>
            <author>JPP Egineering and Urban Planning</author>
            <submit_date>September 1st 2016</submit_date>
            <audience> To: Members of the Board of Trustees and residents of the city of Kirkland
                Washington </audience>
        </cover_page>

        <tbl_cont>
            <section n="1">Introduction</section>
            <section n="2">Background</section>
            <section n="3">Purpose</section>
            <section n="4">Action Plan</section>
            <section n="5">Feasibility</section>
            <section n="6">Conclusion</section>
        </tbl_cont>

        <intro type="abstract">
            <!--attribute options: ltr_int, exec_sum, abstract-->
            <p><!--text to be typed at the end here--></p>
        </intro>

        <background>
            <p>
                <crnt_cond> Located at 111 Waverly Way in Kirkland, City Center Park currently
                    serves as the city's second largest communal gathering space within city limits.
                    The large expanse of land has become overgrown with weeds and blackberry bushes.
                    <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
                </crnt_cond>
                <subj_hist> As the site of the former junior high school which burned down in 1987,
                    this land was left in disrepair for over a year before members of the local
                    neighborhoods banned together to bring purpose back to the land. Over the years
                    since the fire, different features have been added progressively. Starting with
                    the creation of the winding path up to a senic lookout point over Lake
                    Washington and then building a small play ground out of local recycled
                    materials. The potential of this space is obvious to those who live around
                    it.<!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
                </subj_hist>
            </p>
        </background>

        <purpose>
            <p>
                <scope type="when"> In the summer of 2017, the city of Kenmore hopes to begin
                    construction on the vacant lot turned community park in hopes of realizing its
                    value to the community and the organizations within it. </scope>
                <!--attribute options: what, who, when, where-->
                <scope type="who"> When completed this project will bring greatly added value to the
                    city and to its residence in many forms. </scope>
                <objective> The proposed project includes a multi-purpose turf sports feild with
                    small grandstand seating to serve as a practice area and play space for local
                    teams. It will include a ecofriendly play space by updating and reinforcing the
                    existing structure made out of local recycled materials. The existing lookout
                    point at the top of the park's hill will be enhanced with a sculptural totem
                    pole designed and carved by local artists and craftsman. All of which will be
                    surrounded by patches of community gardens for town residents to manage and
                    attend to. <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
                </objective>
            </p>
            <p>
                <goal> Goals:</goal>
            </p>
            <p>
                <goal>- Preserve, protect, and improve parkland and recreational
                    opportunities.</goal>
            </p>
            <p>
                <goal>- Anticipate the needs of the changing community and structure programs and
                    facilities accordingly.</goal>
            </p>
            <p>
                <goal>- Enhance the city’s arts, cultural and historic assets. </goal>
            </p>
            <p>
                <goal>- Enrich the lives of residents.</goal>
            </p>
            <p>
                <goal>- And build a healthier community. </goal>
            </p>
        </purpose>

        <approach>
            <!--attribute options: execution, action-->
            <p>
                <action>Our number one goal is to provide a safe and productive space that fully
                    utilizes all of the benefits that this land has to offer. Our proposed design
                    for City Center Park would maximize its usefulness to the community while
                    maintaining minimal costs to the city and its residence. The phases of this
                    project are broken up into four main catergories which can be constructed all at
                    once on in progression depending on finances and disruption to the surrounding
                    neighborhoods. The first, and most critical phase involves clearing the bramble
                    that covers this already well graded plot of land and removing any remaining
                    building debris and possibly hazardous waste that may remain on the site. The
                    second phase includes structurally fortifying and updating the existing recycled
                    play structure and surrounding picnic spaces. This phase can be followed by
                    either the addition of a new multipurpose terf feild and small grandstand area
                    or improvement of the senic lookout ridge above with the addition of several
                    plots for community gardens for local residence to use. </action></p>
        </approach>

        <feasibility>
            <!--attribute options: economic, social, environmental-->
            <p>
                <economic>Over the past five years the city of Kirkland has set aside a small budget
                    each year to be put towards city redevelopment and improvement projects.
                    Although this fund will not cover the entire cost of the project, it along with
                    a number of donations from members of the community and local companies will
                    cover the relatively low costs of this project. Much of the groundwork for this
                    park has already been laid over the past 20 to 30 years through the small
                    neighborhood improvement projects that have taken place. The main cost for this
                    improvement will be the leveling and placement of the multipurpose terf sports
                    field. Otherwise art fixtures and building materials will be made of primarily
                    donated or local recycled materials and repurposed for the park
                    fixtures.</economic></p>
            <p><social>Socially, this community space would add exponential value to the surrounding
                    properties and to the lives of those living within and around the city of
                    Kirkland. By removing any remaining structural debris from the old school and
                    reintroducing local plant life back to the land would help to not only improve
                    the local ecosystem and environment, it would help to stabilize the soft soils
                    and loose gravel that makes up the existing ridge at the edge of the park.
                </social></p>
        </feasibility>

        <conclu>
            <p> In conclusion, we believe that this park would add invaluably to the community. Our
                design proposal provides an efficient and practical response to a number of the
                problems called upon by local residents to be added or fixed. This space would
                provide a space for youth sports leagues to practice, for local organizations to
                meet, for children to play and for neighbors to gather. <!--text here-->
            </p>
        </conclu>

        <references>
            <citation n="" style="MLA"> </citation>
        </references>
    </pub_init_proposal>

    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="v_27"/>
        <report type="peer" resp="#v_27">
            <p> For project 2, Sam did a proposal for City Center Park Redesign in Kirkland,
                Washington. The proposal goes over the history and current state of the park, as
                well as what kind of redesigns should take place and how this improvement of the
                park would benefit the community of Kirkland. Overall from what I read I thought
                that there was strong foundation to the proposal and I felt like a lot of the points
                being made came across well. Starting off with the background, I found that it was
                very rich in detail and that a lot what was found in the subject history and current
                state fit extremely well. Where I think the Background can improve is within
                transitioning from fact to fact where you could write stuff between the elements to
                help the audience digest the information better. I also feel that you can cut down
                the subject history. For Purpose was somewhat confused by the, "hopes to begin
                construction on the vacant lot turned community park in hopes of realizing its value
                to the community", I think you clarify or reorganize that part it should be fine.
                For the goals element I think that you can just head the section with "Goals:"
                instead of "The goals of redesigning...", I think that it would look more
                professional. And with your last goal you should start it with an action word so
                there is a consistency with the other goals. I thought that your scope was strong
                and to the point and also liked how you choose to present you goals and how they
                were brief yet effective. For feasibility I thought that ideas were strong and the
                flow was good. I felt that everything in that section made sense and fit well within
                that element. I thought that your use of language throughout this proposal made
                sense by using a more professional tone with your audience and also using some more
                techincal language, but not too much that you may confuse the audience. Overall I
                think that you have a very strong foundation for this project and just need finish
                up the other sections.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
