<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Writing Project 3</title>
        <author xml:id="c12">Brent Christy</author>
        <version n="1" date="2016-08-15"/>
    </docHead>

    <pub_init_proposal>
        <cover_page>
            <title>Police Body Camera Requirement</title>
            <author>Brent Christy</author>
            <submit_date>August 15th, 2016</submit_date>
            <audience>Carl Graziano, Chief of Police</audience>
        </cover_page>
        <tbl_cont>
            <section>Introduction</section>
            <section>Background</section>
            <section>Purpose</section>
            <section>Approach</section>
            <section>Feasibility</section>
        </tbl_cont>
        <intro type="ltr_int">
            <p> Over the course of the past several years, there have been a large number of
                unfortunate situations involving police and their decision making throughout the
                United States. In some of the situations, the police made correct decisions in
                addressing a potentially violent situation. In other cases, there was blatant misuse
                of police power, which resulted in the death of innocent citizens. In many of these
                cases, it the end result is a 'he said, she said' situation. Witnesses of the event
                will tell what they saw and the police officer will give his account of the event as
                well. There is no way to tell which of these accounts is correct, and the benefit of
                the doubt has generally been given to the police officer versus the average citizen.
                There needs to be a definite way for the correct and accurate story to be told, and
                that can be done by requiring police body cameras for all members of the Scranton
                police force. </p>
        </intro>
        <background>
            <p>
                <crnt_cond> In the city of Scranton, there are currently no body cameras
                    implemented. The last public mention of adding body cameras to the police force
                    for the city of Scranton came in 2014 when an article was published in the Times
                    Tribune about the lack of budget for the cameras. </crnt_cond>
            </p>
            <p>
                <subj_hist> Due to a number of incidents in the past several years, more and more
                    departments are implementing body cameras with their squadrons. One of the most
                    progressive cities in recent times has been the city of Los Angeles. Just two
                    months ago in June, the city council unanimously approved an almost 70 million
                    dollar budget to have body cameras on 7,000 police officers by 2018. Since the
                    recent incidents in places like Ferguson and Baton Rouge, it is becoming more
                    and more necessary for footage of questionable police situations to be
                    available. This allows a correct representation of the incident without any
                    doubts. </subj_hist>
            </p>
        </background>
        <purpose>
            <p>
                <scope type="when">In the Winter 2017-18</scope>, <scope type="who">the city of
                    Scranton Police Department </scope><scope type="what">should begin to implement
                    body cameras on all active police officers.</scope>
                <objective>The proposed system of body cameras will include cameras for all active
                    police officers in the city. The system will provide assurance that correct
                    police procedures are being followed in all situations. It will ensure that all
                    police are operating with the public's safety in mind. </objective>
            </p>
        </purpose>
        <approach>
            <p>
                <execution>The initial plan for the system is to roll it out in several phases. The
                    first phase will be a test run for 15 police officers. The usefulness of the
                    cameras will be evaluated in different situations including court trials and
                    performance reviews. If the trial goes well, the program can be expanded to
                    other officers in waves. The entire police force could be outfitted with cameras
                    in two years. Each camera's battery would last a full 24 hour day and record to
                    an SD card. The camera will be impossible to turn off and the SD card will be
                    removable at the end of each day with the video stored for a week. If any
                    complaints arises, the video of the certain event can be saved. </execution>
            </p>
        </approach>
        <feasibility>
            <p>
                <economic> The main issue that has come up across police forces regarding body
                    cameras has been the lack of budget space to purchase cameras. In order for the
                    Los Angeles Police Department to implement their body cameras, they acquired a
                    budget of $70 million. This will provide cameras for about 9,000 officers.
                    Scranton Police Department has around 200 officers, so the cost of the program
                    should only be around $1.5 million. Despite the large cost, this is an important
                    program that will provide a safer environment for everyone in the city.
                    President Obama has mentioned on several occasions the need for body cameras and
                    the possibility of federal funding being provided to equip officers with them. </economic>
                <!-- should insert some social feasibility about effects of 
                body cams on public-->
            </p>
        </feasibility>
        <conclu>
            <p> Although Scranton is not a huge city with large records of police violence, body
                cameras are a necessity for all police. They provide two main purposes. They can
                ensure that police are handling situations appropriately and they can act as
                evidence in court cases where a defendant may be questioning the police's handling
                of the situation. Overall, the safety that the cameras will provide should outweigh
                the drawback of allocating funds to purchase the cameras. Many of the larger cities
                such as New York City and Los Angeles are implementing programs and it would be a
                good idea to get on the right side of this situation and acquire body cameras as
                soon as the budget will allow the city to. <!-- Conclusion needs some work -->
            </p>
        </conclu>
        <references>
            <citation style="MLA" n="1">
                <author n="1">Elinson, Zusha</author>. <title>"Los Angeles Approves $60 Million to
                    Outfit Police Force With Body Cameras."</title> WSJ. Wall Street Journal, n.d.
                Web. 15 Aug. 2016. </citation>
            <citation style="MLA" n="2">
                <author n="1">Kohut, Joseph</author>. <title>"Local Police Departments Mull Body
                    Cameras in Wake of Federal Funding Proposal."</title> Thetimes-tribune.com. The
                Times Tribune, n.d. Web. 15 Aug. 2016. </citation>
        </references>
    </pub_init_proposal>

    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="peer_id_here"/>
        <report type="peer" resp="#peer_id_here">
            <p>Peer review report will appear here.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
