<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Writing Project 3</title>
        <author xml:id="c12">Brent Christy</author>
        <version n="2" date="2016-08-20"/>
    </docHead>

    <pub_init_proposal>
        <cover_page>
            <title>Police Body Camera Requirement</title>
            <author>Brent Christy</author>
            <submit_date>August 20th, 2016</submit_date>
            <audience>Carl Graziano, Chief of Police</audience>
        </cover_page>
        <tbl_cont>
            <section>Introduction</section>
            <section>Background</section>
            <section>Purpose</section>
            <section>Approach</section>
            <section>Feasibility</section>
            <section>Conclusion</section>
        </tbl_cont>
        <intro type="ltr_int">
            <p> Over the course of the past several years, there have been a large number of
                unfortunate situations involving police and their decision making throughout the
                United States. In some of the situations, the police made correct decisions in
                addressing a potentially violent situation. In other cases, there was blatant misuse
                of police power, which resulted in the death of innocent citizens. In many of these
                cases, the end result is a 'he said, she said' situation. Witnesses of the event
                will tell what they saw and the police officer will give his account of the event as
                well. There is no way to tell which of these accounts is correct, and the benefit of
                the doubt has generally been given to the police officer versus the average citizen.
                There needs to be a definite way for the correct and accurate story to be told, and
                that can be done by requiring police body cameras for all members of the Scranton
                police force. In addition to keeping officers in check, the cameras have a mutual
                benefit to police departments where the cameras can be used for performance
                evaluations and as evidence in court cases. </p>
        </intro>
        <background>
            <p>
                <crnt_cond> In the city of Scranton, there are currently no body cameras
                    implemented. The last public mention of adding body cameras to the police force
                    for the city of Scranton came in 2014 when an article was published in the Times
                    Tribune about the lack of budget for the cameras (Kohut).</crnt_cond>
            </p>
            <p>
                <subj_hist> Due to a number of incidents in the past several years, more and more
                    departments are implementing body cameras with their squadrons. One of the most
                    progressive cities in recent times has been the city of Los Angeles. Just two
                    months ago in June, the city council unanimously approved an almost 70 million
                    dollar budget to have body cameras on 7,000 police officers by 2018. Since the
                    recent incidents in places like Ferguson and Baton Rouge, it is becoming more
                    and more necessary for footage of questionable police situations to be
                    available. This allows a correct representation of the incident without any
                    doubts. The neighboring city of Wilkes-Barre is the 18th on the list of most
                    violent crimes, and in many cases, police body cameras could be of use to depict
                    what happened in these situations (Seibel). </subj_hist>
            </p>
        </background>
        <purpose>
            <p>
                <scope type="when">In the Winter 2017-18</scope>, <scope type="who">the city of
                    Scranton Police Department </scope><scope type="what">should begin to implement
                    body cameras on all active police officers.</scope>
                <objective>The proposed system of body cameras will include cameras for all active
                    police officers in the city. The system will provide assurance that correct
                    police procedures are being followed in all situations. It will ensure that all
                    police are operating with the public's safety in mind. </objective>
            </p>
        </purpose>
        <approach>
            <p>
                <execution>The initial plan for the system is to roll it out in several phases. This
                    is how the city of Boston is planning on implementing their system and it seems
                    like it would be a good idea to follow suit (Ransom). The first phase will be a
                    test run for 15 police officers. The usefulness of the cameras will be evaluated
                    in different situations including court trials and performance reviews. If the
                    trial goes well, the program can be expanded to other officers in waves. The
                    entire police force could be outfitted with cameras in two years. Each camera's
                    battery would last a full 24 hour day and record to an SD card. The camera will
                    be impossible to turn off and the SD card will be removable at the end of each
                    day with the video stored for a week. If any complaints arises, the video of the
                    certain event can be saved. </execution>
            </p>
        </approach>
        <feasibility>
            <p>
                <economic> The main issue that has come up across police forces regarding body
                    cameras has been the lack of budget space to purchase cameras. In order for the
                    Los Angeles Police Department to implement their body cameras, they acquired a
                    budget of $70 million (Elinson). This will provide cameras for about 9,000 officers.
                    Scranton Police Department has around 200 officers, so the cost of the program
                    should only be around $1.5 million. Despite the large cost, this is an important
                    program that will provide a safer environment for everyone in the city.
                    President Obama has mentioned on several occasions the need for body cameras and
                    has requested federal funding to be provided in order to equip officers with
                    them (Dann). </economic>
            </p>
            <p>
                <social> Socially, this should be a welcomed change in the city of Scranton. Having
                    body cameras should help the citizens of the city feel safer. There is an
                    obvious concern of people not wanting to be video taped, especially privately,
                    but this should not cause a large concern due to the videos only being used as
                    evidence in court cases or in police reviews. The videos would not be released
                    publicly without people's identities being blurred out of the video. People
                    may also be concerned with thinking that police could review tapes to look for
                    illegal activities, but this would not be the case. Tapes would only be reviewed
                    if a crime has been committed in the eyes of an officer. </social>
            </p>
        </feasibility>
        <conclu>
            <p> Although Scranton is not a huge city with large records of police violence, body
                cameras are a necessity for all police. They provide two main purposes. They can
                ensure that police are handling situations appropriately and they can act as
                evidence in court cases where a defendant may be questioning the police's handling
                of the situation. Overall, the safety that the cameras will provide should outweigh
                the drawback of allocating funds to purchase the cameras. Many of the larger cities
                such as New York City and Los Angeles are implementing programs and it would be a
                good idea to get on the right side of this situation and acquire body cameras as
                soon as the budget will allow the city to. </p>
        </conclu>
        <references>
            <citation style="MLA">
                <author n="1">Dann, Carrie</author>, and <author n="2">Andrew Rafferty</author>.
                    <title>"Obama Requests $263 Million for Police Body Cameras, Training"</title>
                NBCNews.com. NBC News, n.d. Web. 20 Aug. 2016. </citation>
            <citation style="MLA" n="1">
                <author n="1">Elinson, Zusha</author>. <title>"Los Angeles Approves $60 Million to
                    Outfit Police Force With Body Cameras."</title> WSJ. Wall Street Journal, n.d.
                Web. 15 Aug. 2016. </citation>
            <citation style="MLA" n="2">
                <author n="1">Kohut, Joseph</author>. <title>"Local Police Departments Mull Body
                    Cameras in Wake of Federal Funding Proposal."</title> Thetimes-tribune.com. The
                Times Tribune, n.d. Web. 15 Aug. 2016. </citation>
            <citation style="MLA" n="3">
                <author n="1">Ransom, Jan</author>. <title>"Deal Reached on Body Cameras for Boston
                    Police."</title> BostonGlobe.com. The Boston Globe, n.d. Web. 19 Aug. 2016. </citation>
            <citation style="MLA">
                <author n="1">Seibel, Jacob</author>. <title>"Deadly 2013 Lands Wilkes-Barre on
                    'murder Capital' List."</title> Thetimes-tribune.com. The Times Tribune, n.d.
                Web. 20 Aug. 2016. </citation>
        </references>
    </pub_init_proposal>

    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="s23"/>
        <report type="peer" resp="#s23">
            <p>This particular proposal sounds a lot like a plea from the public for the city of
                Scranton to make changes in its law enforcement. Public initiative proposals are a
                means of communicating with government officials (or in this case police officials)
                the desires of the community, therefore yes, it makes sense to use this genre for
                the particular rhetorical situation. Language and word level choice are very
                appropriate for any adult reader, which is important for this genre since anyone
                could be reading it. However, I feel like you may be a little too factual for the
                genre. It is good to be professional and have irrefutable arguments in your proposal
                because that is what makes your proposal legitimate. In your background section I
                would recommend adding some personal notes about how body cameras could be of
                particular benefit to Scranton though since you’re trying to convince this
                particular department. Even if the purpose is for Scranton to take preventative
                measures and basically “get with the times” and follow the lead of other cities in
                the nation. You could also mention how it would instill a greater feeling of safety
                in the community and trust in police officers. Considering your audience is
                particularly important when you’re addressing your purpose as well. I think you
                might be thinking mostly about how body camera’s will affect the general public, but
                your audience is the police chief. I think you should refocus your purpose to also
                primarily state the benefit body cameras would serve to police officers in the
                “purpose” section. This would reposition your focus a little more strategically.
                Also, I like that you outline your scope very clearly, but I wonder if putting such
                a specific date on this proposal is hindering your argument. It might sound more
                persuasive and realistic if you give loose deadlines to support your plan to
                implement body cameras in phases. Instead you could say that these cameras will be
                implemented over a 2-3 year range so that there is flexibility in finding the funds
                for this. Despite your concerns, I think you use the schema very well and have a
                really strong conclusion. I wouldn’t recommend changing anything in your conclusion
                and instead adjust your background and purpose sections to reflect more on what is
                in your conclusion. You should absolutely mention that the safety benefits should
                outweigh the costs earlier in your proposal and talk about how it isn’t something
                that needs to be done immediately, but it is something that should be on the chief’s
                mind because it is important. You can also mention earlier that it would be
                beneficial for Scranton to follow to lead of cities like New York and LA because
                they have a successful model for what could be really important preventative
                measures in Scranton. </p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
