<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Writing Project 3</title>
        <author xml:id="d13">Daniel Doherty</author>
        <version n="1" date="2016-08-15"/>
    </docHead>

    <blog_post> Root element for Science Blog genre <!-- Global Elements-->
        <!-- Optional elements that can go anywhere -->
        <!-- "n" attribute used to number potentially repeated elements. Optional. -->
        <section_header>’background’ and ‘answer’ are best broken into modular digestible sections
            consisting of several paragraphs. ‘section_header’ should be titled in a way such that
            the following paragraphs either work in concert to make the point specified by
            ‘section_header’, or answer a question put forth by ‘section_header’. </section_header>
        <visual type="" url="">Visuals are any variety of in line imagery used to break up long
            lengths of text, and/or aid in the understanding of a topic. Comics, pictures and
            graphics are a few of the possible visuals that can be
            used.<!-- Types can be: Photo, Comic, Drawing, Animation,
                Quoted Text, Other --></visual>
        <analogy>Analogies should be used to better illustrate important and difficult to understand
            topics put forth by the other elements.</analogy>
        <list type="">A multipurpose list element.
            <!-- Types can be: "Generic": A generic list of any related yet separate items. 
                Can also be used for breaking down procedural orders, an example of this would be 
                notating the steps of a mathematical proof.  "Roadmap": A roadmap is a list in which 
                several ‘section_headers’ that build upon one another to drive home an important point 
                are specified before diving into each section independently. This allows the reader to 
                understand the purpose of a section in context to avoid getting lost in its details. 
                Text should agree with ‘section_headers’ used later on. --></list>
        <technical_principle n="">Fundamental theory and concepts involved (such as gravity, matter
            and energy, fluid dynamics, acid-base reactions, etc.). Required in both "background"
            and "answer," must come before "specific_topic" in "answer"</technical_principle>
        <misconception n="">Lists any common misconceptions the public has about the topic, or
            includes quoted material from the community that highlights the existing (false) notions
            about the answer</misconception>
        <pb>Paragraph break</pb>
        <ref type="" url="">Hyperlink around a phrase that directs to a source or resource, can be
            found throughout the post depending on author's preference
            <!-- Types can be "source" or "supplement" for source material or supplemental material --></ref>
        <important_idea n="">Major points of interest relating to the topic.</important_idea>
        <!-- Structure -->
        <!-- Fitting the genre model, Background is followed by Answer, followed by Sources -->
        <!-- Elements within each parent element can occur in any order, though the listed order is
            standard. Typically, each element is its own paragraph, but can be combined in interest
            of brevity. -->
        <!-- Unless otherwise noted, all following elements are required -->
        <background>
            <section_header>Solar Energy</section_header> The Space Industry was the first to use
            solar technology in a practical method and greatly improved the existing technology at
            the time. Solar energy is now a rapidly expanding sector in the energy industry as
            improvements to technology and government subsidies have made solar energy more
            economical and competitive with traditional fossil fuels. As a result, more homeowners
            and businesses are implementing solar power as a clean energy alternative to fossil
            fuels. This is almost always seen in the form of solar panels, which are installed on
            the roofs of buildings or in large fields as these positions are exposed to the sun at
            all times during the day. The sunlight shines on the panels, and electricity is
            generated. This is the extent of knowledge that most people have about solar energy, but
            how does this generate electricity? <technical_principle>The Photovoltaic Effect was
                first observed by Edmund Berquerel in 1839 and greatly expanded upon by Albert
                Einstein in 1905. In short, the photovoltaic effect is the direct conversion of
                light into electricity.</technical_principle> However, this conversion can only
            occur when certain materials are exposed to sunlight, they release electrons and
            generate small amounts of electrical current. If this current can be effectively
            harnessed, it can be used as a means of energy production. <question> How do solar
                panels generate electricity?</question>
        </background>
        <answer>
            <specific_topic n="1">A solar panel is made up a many individual photovoltaic cells. A
                photovoltaic cell has a design similar to a common battery, containing both positive
                and negative charges, that when aligned properly can generate electricity. However,
                a photovoltaic cell relies on the use of a thin wafer made of a semiconductor,
                usually silicon. The semiconductor wafer is specially treated to form an electric
                field, with a positive charge on one side, and a negative charge on the other. These
                individual cells are grouped together in groups of 12 to form a module, similar to a
                12 V battery. These modules are then combined to form an a single solar panel
                commonly seen on rooftops.</specific_topic>
            <technical_principle>A semiconductor is a material that has the conductivity, or the
                ability to carry an electrical current, between that of a good conductor, such as
                metal, and that of an insulator such as rubber. Semiconductors are used as they can be altered and controlled quite easily to perform any electrical result required. Common metals heat up too quickly and conduct electricity to well, making it hard to use them in modern electronics. <analogy>Just as we were told as children not to stand near metal during a lightning storm, utilzing a metal conductor in a solar panel would </analogy></technical_principle>
            <explanation n="">An in-depth reply to the question proposed in the “background”
                section. Typically, the author will use common vernacular and devices such as
                analogies and visuals in order to clearly convey concepts to readers.</explanation>
            <conclusion>A conclusion that sums up what was just explained. It acts as a concise
                response to the question asked in the “background” section </conclusion>
        </answer>
        <sources> Contains sources the author used to answer the question <citation style="">A
                citation for the source written in the style the author decides to use (ex. MLA, APA
                etc.)<!-- Optional sub-element --></citation>
        </sources>
    </blog_post>
    <!-- root element for P3 here -->

    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="peer_id_here"/>
        <report type="peer" resp="#peer_id_here">
            <p>Peer review report will appear here.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
