<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Writing Project 3</title>
        <author xml:id="d13">Daniel Doherty</author>
        <version n="1" date="2016-08-15"/>
    </docHead>
    
    <blog_post>
      
        <background>
            <section_header>How is does solar energy work?</section_header> 
            <question>How does sunlight shining on a solar panel generate electricity?</question>
            <misconception></misconception>
            The Space Industry was the first to use
            solar technology in a practical method and greatly improved the existing technology at
            the time. Solar energy is now a rapidly expanding sector in the energy industry as
            improvements to technology and government subsidies have made solar energy more
            economical and competitive with traditional fossil fuels. As a result, more homeowners
            and businesses are implementing solar power as a clean energy alternative to fossil
            fuels. This is almost always seen in the form of solar panels, which are installed on
            the roofs of buildings or in large fields as these positions are exposed to the sun at
            all times during the day. The sunlight shines on the panels, and electricity is
            generated. This is the extent of knowledge that most people have about solar energy, but
            how does this generate electricity? <technical_principle>The Photovoltaic Effect was
                first observed by Edmund Berquerel in 1839 and greatly expanded upon by Albert
                Einstein in 1905. In short, the photovoltaic effect is the direct conversion of
                light into electricity.</technical_principle> However, this conversion can only
            occur when certain materials are exposed to sunlight, they release electrons and
            generate small amounts of electrical current. If this current can be effectively
            harnessed, it can be used as a means of energy production. <question> How do solar
                panels generate electricity?</question>
        </background>
        <answer>
            <specific_topic n="1"><note type="peer" resp="#v26">Schema error here</note>A solar panel is made up a many individual photovoltaic cells. A
                photovoltaic cell has a design similar to a common battery, containing both positive
                and negative charges, that when aligned properly can generate electricity. However,
                a photovoltaic cell relies on the use of a thin wafer made of a semiconductor,
                usually silicon. The semiconductor wafer is specially treated to form an electric
                field, with a positive charge on one side, and a negative charge on the other. These
                individual cells are grouped together in groups of 12 to form a module, similar to a
                12 V battery. These modules are then combined to form an a single solar panel
                commonly seen on rooftops.</specific_topic>
            <technical_principle>A semiconductor is a material that has the conductivity, or the
                ability to carry an electrical current, between that of a good conductor, such as
                metal, and that of an insulator such as rubber. Semiconductors are used as they can
                be altered and controlled quite easily to perform any electrical result required.
                Common metals heat up too quickly and conduct electricity to well, making it hard to
                use them in modern electronics. <analogy>Just as we were told as children not to
<<<<<<< HEAD
                    stand near metal during a lightning storm, utilizing a metal conductor in a
                    solar panel is just as dangerous. The solar panels would overheat as there would
                    be no resistance to the electrical current, and the panels would likely catch
                    fire</analogy></technical_principle>
            <explanation n="">Sunlight is made up of photons, atomic sized particles that radiate
                from the sun. When sunlight shines on the solar panels, the individual photons
                strike the silicon and transfer their energy to the electrons of the silicon, and
                knocks them off the silicon atoms. By forming an electrical circuit on the positive and negative sides of the cell, these electrons can be captured in the form of an electrical current. This current can then be transferred out of the cell and used for electricity. Solar panels have an efficiency of about 22%, meaning that only 22% of the electrons knocked loosed by the photon are captured in the form of an electrical current. The remaining energy is usually lost to heat.
            <analogy>A photon can be thought of as the white (cue) ball in the game of pool, the electrons as the remaining stripes and solids, and the pockets as the means of capturing the electrical current. Just after racking the balls (electrons), they are "stuck" in that position and will not move unless a force acts upon them. When the cue ball (photon) smacks into them during the break, the energy is transferred to the other balls and they are knocked free of their initial position. A good pool player may hit a few of the balls into the pockets, but most will remain on the table. The balls (electrons) that fall into the pockets represent the 22% efficiency of the panels, as a majority of the balls still remain on the table.</analogy></explanation>
=======
                    stand near metal during a lightning storm, utilzing<note type="peer"
                        resp="#v26">utilizing is spelled wrong</note> a metal conductor in a solar
                    panel would <note type="peer" resp="#v26">This sentence has no ending</note></analogy></technical_principle>
            <explanation n=""><note type="peer" resp="#v26">Template code should be replaced</note>An in-depth reply to the question proposed in the “background”
                section. Typically, the author will use common vernacular and devices such as
                analogies and visuals in order to clearly convey concepts to readers.</explanation>
>>>>>>> origin/master
            <conclusion>A conclusion that sums up what was just explained. It acts as a concise
                response to the question asked in the “background” section </conclusion>
        </answer>
        <sources><note type="peer" resp="#v26"></note> Contains sources the author used to answer the question <citation style="">A
                citation for the source written in the style the author decides to use (ex. MLA, APA
                etc.)<!-- Optional sub-element --></citation>
        </sources>
    </blog_post>
    <!-- root element for P3 here -->

    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="v26"/>
        <report type="peer" resp="#v26">
            <p>
                Dan wrote a Science Blog composition based on the question: "How do solar panels
                generate electricity?". He starts with an outline on the history and technical
                aspects of solar panels which is followed up by the actual answer. 
            </p>
            <p>
                The rhetorical situation here is clear, a question is being answered. I would
                imagine an audience of scientifically literate, curious people. This genre is
                appropriate for this situation, as answering a question or explaining some
                scientific principle is the reason for this genre's existence. As this genre is
                meant to make complex scientific problems more understandable, Dan's word choice and
                sentence structure are more or less sound. There are some syntactical problems such
                as the last sentence in the answer just ending. An aspect of the genre that Dan does
                not take up is the visual aid. An example of where a visual aid could come in handy
                could be to better illustrate the photoelectric effect. There is an analogy but
                there is potential for more. As I discussed previously (the last three sentences),
                using the rhetorical devices of visual aids and analogies would assist in making
                this piece more successful. As I will discuss later on, conforming more towards the
                schema would also help the piece by making it more digestible.
            </p>
            <p>
                The schema outlined by group 1 is not particularly well conformed to in this
                composition. For instance, the first element in the answer, a "specific_topic"
                element, raises a schema error. As far as I can tell this is because a
                "specific_topic" element must be preceded by a "technical_principle" element. Also a
                problem with this composition is the code left over from the template file. All of
                this code should be removed and replaced with one's own. Lastly, the "sources"
                element/section of the blog was left entirely untouched.
            </p>
            <p>
                In terms of rhetorical situation and response, Dan's piece reflects research done by
                group one quite well. However in terms of schema conformity, it could use some work.
                My main piece of advice is to get rid of all the boilerplate XML that comes with the
                template. Simply doing this will, in my opinion, enhance readability. A corollary to
                this advice is to clean up schema errors. Finally, adding such devices as visual
                aids and analogies would help in conforming to the genre. 
            </p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
