<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Writing Project 3</title>
        <author xml:id="d13">Daniel Doherty</author>
        <version n="1" date="2016-08-15"/>
    </docHead>

    <blog_post>
        <background>
            <section_header>How is does solar energy work?</section_header>
            <question>How does sunlight shining on a solar panel generate electricity?</question>
            <misconception>This answer is much more complicated than it first appears, as the act of
                sunlight shining on a panel does not create electricity out of nothing. To
                understand how a solar panel works, there are certain laws of nature that must be
                made clear.</misconception>
            <technical_principle>One of the fundamental theories of the universe is the
                    <important_idea>Conservation of Energy.</important_idea></technical_principle>
        </background>
        <answer>
            <section_header>The Conservation of Energy</section_header>
            <technical_principle n="1">The theory of the Conservation of Mass states that
                    <important_idea>energy cannot be created or destroyed, only
                    transformed.</important_idea> Therefore, in the case of solar panels, the
                electricity (energy) generated by the panels is not magically created from nothing
                when the sun shines. The electricity generated is thus a transformation of the only
                other energy source available, light. An easier way to think of this concept is to
                imagine baking a cake. <visual type="photo" url="http"/>
                <analogy>All of the ingredients required to make a cake; the eggs, flour, milk etc.
                    can be thought of as a type of energy source. They all exist initially and once
                    they are mixed together to form the batter, none of the initial ingredients have
                    been created or destroyed. The eggs, milk and flour are all still in the bowl,
                    just mixed together. Nothing has been lost. The oven facilitates the
                    transformation of the batter into the final product of a cake, or the second
                    form of energy.</analogy>The solar panels are simply a method of facilitating
                this transformation of energy, much like the oven transforms the mixture of
                ingredients into the final form of a cake.</technical_principle>
            <section_header>So how do solar panels facilitate this energy
                transformation?</section_header>
            <technical_principle>A solar panel is made up of many individual
                    <important_idea>photovoltaic cells.</important_idea>A photovoltaic cell has a
                design similar to a common battery, containing both positive and negative charges,
                that when aligned properly can release electricity. However, a photovoltaic cell
                relies on the use of a thin wafer made of a semiconductor, usually silicon. The
                semiconductor wafer is specially treated to form an electric field, with a positive
                charge on one side, and a negative charge on the other. These individual cells are
                grouped together in groups of 12 to form a module, similar to a 12 V battery. These
                modules are then combined to form an a single solar panel commonly seen on
                rooftops.</technical_principle>
            <specific_topic n="1"><note type="peer" resp="#v26">Schema error
                here</note></specific_topic>
            <technical_principle>A semiconductor is a material that has the conductivity, or the
                ability to carry an electrical current, between that of a good conductor, such as
                metal, and that of an insulator such as rubber. Semiconductors are used as they can
                be altered and controlled quite easily to perform any electrical result required.
                Common metals heat up too quickly and conduct electricity to well, making it hard to
                use them in modern electronics. <analogy>Just as we were told as children not to
                    stand near metal during a lightning storm, utilizing a metal conductor in a
                    solar panel is just as dangerous. The solar panels would overheat as there would
                    be no resistance to the electrical current, and the panels would likely catch
                    fire</analogy></technical_principle>
            <section_header>So how do photovoltaic cells work?</section_header>
            <technical_principle>Sunlight is made up of photons, atomic sized particles that radiate
                from the sun.</technical_principle>
            <explanation>When sunlight shines on the solar panels, the individual photons strike the
                silicon and transfer their energy to the electrons of the silicon, knocking them
                loose from the silicon atoms. By forming an electrical field<note type="peer"
                    resp="#d13"> Explain how this happens</note> on the positive and negative sides
                of the cell, these electrons can be captured in the form of an electrical current.
                This current can then be transferred out of the cell and used for electricity.
                    <analogy>A photon can be thought of as the white (cue) ball in the game of pool,
                    and the electrons as the remaining stripes and solids. Just after racking the
                    balls (electrons), they are "stuck" in that position and will not move unless a
                    force acts upon them. <visual type="photo" url="http"/> When the cue ball
                    (photon) smacks into the other balls during the break, the energy is transferred
                    to the other balls and they are knocked free of their initial
                    position.</analogy> These loose electrons are now free and their combined
                negative charges form an electrical current that can be directed by the electrical
                field created by the photovoltaic cells. The electric field directs this current to
                a node, which transfers it out of the individual photovoltaic cells and converts it
                to an alternating current (AC) form of electricity, which is able to be used on the
                grid.</explanation>
            <section_header>How much energy can be generated by solar panels?</section_header>
            <technical_principle>Solar panels have a notoriously low <important_idea>energy
                    efficiency.</important_idea>Solar panels have an average efficiency of about
                22%, meaning that only 22% of the electrons knocked loosed by the photon are
                captured in the form of an electrical current. The remaining energy is usually lost
                to heat. The effectiveness of a solar panel is thus determined by how well the
                electric field created by the semiconductor can direct the electrical current to the
                node which transfers the electricity out of the photovoltaic cells.<analogy>Going
                    back to the pool example: A good pool player may hit a few of the
                balls from the break into the pockets, but most will remain on the table. The balls (electrons)
                that fall into the pockets represent the 22% efficiency of the panels, as a majority
                of the balls still remain on the table.</analogy></technical_principle>
            <conclusion>A conclusion that sums up what was just explained. It acts as a concise
                response to the question asked in the “background” section </conclusion>
        </answer>
        <sources><note type="peer" resp="#v26"/> Contains sources the author used to answer the
            question <citation style="">A citation for the source written in the style the author
                decides to use (ex. MLA, APA etc.)<!-- Optional sub-element --></citation>
        </sources>
    </blog_post>
    <!-- root element for P3 here -->

    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="v26"/>
        <report type="peer" resp="#v26">
            <p> Dan wrote a Science Blog composition based on the question: "How do solar panels
                generate electricity?". He starts with an outline on the history and technical
                aspects of solar panels which is followed up by the actual answer. </p>
            <p> The rhetorical situation here is clear, a question is being answered. I would
                imagine an audience of scientifically literate, curious people. This genre is
                appropriate for this situation, as answering a question or explaining some
                scientific principle is the reason for this genre's existence. As this genre is
                meant to make complex scientific problems more understandable, Dan's word choice and
                sentence structure are more or less sound. There are some syntactical problems such
                as the last sentence in the answer just ending. An aspect of the genre that Dan does
                not take up is the visual aid. An example of where a visual aid could come in handy
                could be to better illustrate the photoelectric effect. There is an analogy but
                there is potential for more. As I discussed previously (the last three sentences),
                using the rhetorical devices of visual aids and analogies would assist in making
                this piece more successful. As I will discuss later on, conforming more towards the
                schema would also help the piece by making it more digestible. </p>
            <p> The schema outlined by group 1 is not particularly well conformed to in this
                composition. For instance, the first element in the answer, a "specific_topic"
                element, raises a schema error. As far as I can tell this is because a
                "specific_topic" element must be preceded by a "technical_principle" element. Also a
                problem with this composition is the code left over from the template file. All of
                this code should be removed and replaced with one's own. Lastly, the "sources"
                element/section of the blog was left entirely untouched. </p>
            <p> In terms of rhetorical situation and response, Dan's piece reflects research done by
                group one quite well. However in terms of schema conformity, it could use some work.
                My main piece of advice is to get rid of all the boilerplate XML that comes with the
                template. Simply doing this will, in my opinion, enhance readability. A corollary to
                this advice is to clean up schema errors. Finally, adding such devices as visual
                aids and analogies would help in conforming to the genre. </p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
