<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
 <?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>WP3: Cover Letter</title>
        <author xml:id="g14">Ben Gincley</author>
        <version n="1" date="2016-08-11"/>
    </docHead>
    <cover_letter>
        <header>
            <name>Benjamin Gincley</name>
            <contact_info>
                <!-- One or More Contact -->
                <contact type="address">700 Columbus Ave, Boston, MA 02120</contact>
                <contact type="phone"> 1-800-666-5555 </contact>
                <contact type="email"> gincley.b@husky.neu.edu </contact>
            </contact_info>
        </header>
        <greeting>Hello,</greeting>
        <intro_para>
            <intent type="purpose">I am very interested applying for the Foundry Operations Co-op at
                Ginkgo BioWorks.</intent>
            <intent type="connection">Last year, I had spoken with representatives of the company at
                a Northeastern University Biotechnology career event, and had proceeded through to a
                phone interview with a member of the company thereafter, but was deferred due to
                lack of experience at the time (as it would have been my first co-op).</intent>
            <reason>I am still extremely interested in the type of work that Ginkgo is doing, and
                the doors it will unlock for further biotechnological innovation,</reason> and
                <proposition>I believe that an opportunity to work at Ginkgo in Spring 2017 would
                allow for me to both make a noticeable contribution to the team and work being done,
                as well as provide a unique and powerful learning and skill-development experience
                as I strive to further develop my competency in this field.</proposition>
        </intro_para>
        <para_background>
            <!-- One or More -->
            <experience type="school">Through my Bioengineering coursework, with a concentration in
                Cell and Tissue Engineering, I have gained an understanding of genetics, tissue
                mechanics, proteomics, and cellular engineering, and continue to pursue
                opportunities to learn more about the science and find creative ways to apply this
                knowledge.</experience> <note type="peer" resp="#v_27">For this school experience sentence you can
                split it up into two sentences just because there needs to be a break so that it does not feel cluttered
                to the reader. I would suggest breaking it after cellular engineering.</note>
            <experience type="personal">While on campus, I have volunteered my time in two research
                labs, <skills>developing and executing mechanical engineering experiments</skills>
                in the Bubble Imaging Lab and <skills>learning cell culture/passaging, transfection,
                    and biological assay techniques</skills> in the Addiction Sciences Lab, which I
                continue to be involved with. When not doing research, I serve as a mentor with
                multiple organizations on campus, further developing <skills>strong interpersonal
                    and leadership skills that enable my ability to lead groups and harness
                    initiative.</skills></experience>
        </para_background>
        <para_background>
            <experience type="work">At my first co-op, I gained experience in a neurobiological
                research setting at Duke Universtiy, gaining proficiency with
                    <programs>MatLab</programs> and familiarity with <programs>python</programs> to
                    <accomplishments>develop an automated animal behavior training
                    paradigm</accomplishments> and <accomplishments>conduct comprehensive
                    analysis</accomplishments> of both behavioral and <skills>calcium
                    imaging</skills> experiments. Throughout this experience, I gained <skills>
                    skill and experience with both digesting and writing technical
                    documentation,</skills> as well as developed ways to <skills>abstract simple
                    meaning and explanation of technical concepts.</skills> At the end of my co-op,
                    <accomplishments>I gave an hour-long comprehensive presentation of my work with
                    both animal behavior and calcium imaging to the entire lab in a lab
                    meeting.</accomplishments></experience>
        </para_background>
        <closing_statements>
            <compatability>I believe that my relevant experience, extreme interest in the work being
                done/potential applications of the technological paradigm being developed at Ginkgo,
                and personal qualities would make this a great fit.</compatability> 
            <note type="peer" resp="#v_27">I feel that you could give an addition sentence or two if it be in your
            closing statements or experience section, where you can give some background on how your skills and 
            experiences translate well to position that you are applying to.</note>
            <pb/>
            <next_step>I eagerly await your call at 1-800-666-5555 so that we can discuss possible
                next steps and answer questions about moving forward.</next_step>
        </closing_statements>
        <signature>
            <salutation>Best regards,</salutation>
            <name>Benjamin Gincley</name>
        </signature>
    </cover_letter>
    <docReview>
        <writers_memo>I am mostly finished with the bulk of the process, just looking for any tips
            or advice regarding content or format. The situation here is my application to a
            Boston-based biotech company, and presented is my cover letter to be sent with a resume
            to garner an interview with the company. The simple structure of the genre has been easy
        to work with, and everything is by and large well-defined, making the template easy to
        follow. The only difficulty has been the tagging of body content, as some situations are not
        clearly "work," "personal," or "school," but I suppose in reality it's up to the writer's
        discretion to decide which tag fits best, and overall it's relatively inconsequential. I
        would mainly like focus to be on the order of the paragraphs/content presented (I have moved
        the order around a few times), as well as if any of the information seems extraneous of not
        directly relevant. For reference: The position is working at a biotech company that uses
        genetic engineering to take natural principles and engineer novel chemicals/substances such
        as flavors and scents (right now) for commercial use, using principles of bioengineering and
        scaling to commercialize discoveries made in the lab. It is a small-ish spinoff from MIT
        consisting mostly of engineers. Last year when I was phone interviewed, it was with an
        engineering/recruitment staff, not an HR-background person. I assume an
        engineering-background individual will likely do the hiring again this year. </writers_memo>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="v_27"/>
        <report type="peer" resp="#v_27">
            <p>For Ben's project he is writing a cover letter to Ginkgo BioWorks in hopes of landing a Foundry Operations Co-op position. 
            Throughout the cover letter he discusses his background in school, work and personal life, where he brings up many of his 
            skills and accomplishments that he has gained and why he would be a strong choice for the position. I can tell from reading your 
            letter that you have an understanding of the rhetorical situation and audience that you are targeting. Which means that you know that
            you are apply for a position in which you hope to get an interview and your audience is someone within an engineering/recruitment staff. What really impressed 
            me in your draft was the seamless transition from element to element. What I think could be improved in your letter is your argument 
            as to why you would be the best candidate for the position. I found that you were able to state all of your skills, experiences, 
            and accomplishments well, but you did not engage as much into the actual position and how/why you would fit in there. I would say that 
            the way that you have structured your background paragraphs seem to be good. It looks like you made it a point to transition from
            your academic experience to your work experience using your personal experience as a mechanism to get from one to the other which 
            I appreciated. I did not find any of information that you included to be extraneous and I found that by including all of these achievements 
            and going into detail with them that you gave off a stronger image of yourself to the employers. Overall I think that your draft was
            very well constructed and that there are only a few adjustments that should make to improve it.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
