<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Project 3: Cover Letter</title>
        <author xml:id="h15">Tammy Huynh</author>
        <version n="1" date="2016-08-14"/>
    </docHead>

    <!-- root element for P3 here -->
    <cover_letter>
        <header>
            <name>Tammy Huynh</name>
            <contact_info>
                <!-- One or More Contact -->
                <contact type="address">11 Example St. Boston, MA 02115</contact>
                <contact type="phone"> 111-111-1111 </contact>
                <contact type="email"> huynh.ta@husky.neu.edu </contact>
                <contact type="website">examplesite.com</contact>
            </contact_info>
        </header>
        <greeting>Hello Filament Games,</greeting>
        <intro_para>
            <intent type="purpose">I am interested in applying for the Unity Programmer position
            </intent>that <intent type="connection"> I discovered while browsing your site. </intent>
            <reason>Your company takes a fun, unique approach to education</reason> that
                <proposition>I would love to be a part of it.</proposition>
        </intro_para>
        <para_background>
            <experience type="work">I currently work at Northeastern University’s ReGame VR Lab,
                which leverages video games for motor rehabilitation. Here, I develop Unity games in
                C# for two platforms: the Microsoft Surface tablet and another that uses the
                Microsoft Kinect.</experience>
        </para_background>
        <para_background>
            <experience type="school">From my coursework towards a BA in Computer Engineering at
                Northeastern University, I have developed strong skills in design patterns and
                algorithms and an interest in multiplayer networked games, procedural generation,
                and 3D modeling. My personal projects highlighting these principles and topics can
                be viewed at examplesite.com.</experience>
            <experience type="personal">My personal projects highlighting these principles and
                topics can be viewed at examplesite.com.</experience>
        </para_background>
        <para_background>
            <experience type="work">Additionally, I have two years of development experience at
                Novartis Pharmaceuticals and ChoiceStream, where I collaborated with developers,
                designers, managers, and other professionals in various fields to create internal
                web applications. At these companies, I applied universal standards of debugging,
                testing, automation, documentation, and version control. These opportunities taught
                me to follow a fast schedule of daily stand-ups and weekly sprints and appreciate
                flexible, collective design.</experience>
        </para_background>
        <closing_statements>
            <compatability>Filament Games is a great example of how video games can enrich our
                lives. Thus, as an individual with a passion for games, </compatability>
            <next_step> I would love to meet to see how I can become a part of this community. Thank
                you for your time and consideration!</next_step>
        </closing_statements>
        <signature>
            <salutation>Sincerely,</salutation>
            <name>Tammy Huynh</name>
        </signature>
    </cover_letter>
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="m20">Chi Mo</reviewer>
        <report type="peer" resp="#m20">
            <p>From reading the cover letter, the writer wants to apply a game programming job in
                Filament Games. The cover letter shows that the writer had met most of the
                requirement and would fit well for the job position. The rhetorical situation is
                appropriate for the cover letter and the whole cover letter looks well organized and
                clear. I think the writer did well in demonstrate the school, work and personal
                experience in the background paragraph. After reading the job description, I can see
                that the writer really fits the position well. The word-level is pretty good since
                the person who will read the cover letter is an expert of all those computer
                engineering works. The question from her self-review about the <proposition/>, I
                think it fits the element meaning, I used the element in the same way. I don’t think
                the writer needs to add anything to the background but I think she can add something
                to make the reader feel that she really wants the job and did the research on the
                company at the beginning of the cover letter or at the end of it. Also, the writer
                can add some other skills such as communication skills which can show she would be a
                good in team working. Other than the content in the cover letter, I think some of
                the schema are not used. Most of the schema uses fine but I think it would be more
                clearly if the writer can put the background paragraph “in pieces” by schema, such
                as <programs/>
                <skills/>
                <accomplishments/>. </p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
