<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>The Production and Revision of (Disciplinary) Genres</title>
        <author xml:id="l18">Daniel Lieman</author>
        <version n="1" date="2016-08-22"/>
    </docHead>
    
    <!-- root element for P3 here --> 
    <fsb_rpt>
        <page type="ttl">
            <title>Feasibility of a Voting Machine Test Suite</title>
            <contributors>Daniel Lieman</contributors>
            <date>8/16/2016</date>
        </page>
        <page type="tbl_contents">
            <sect n="1" lvl="1"> Executive Summary </sect>
            <sect n="2" lvl="1"> Preliminary Requirements Analysis </sect>
            <sect n="3" lvl="1"> Feasibility </sect>
            <sect n="4" lvl="1"> Success Criteria </sect>
            <sect n="5" lvl="1"> Cost Estimates </sect>
            <sect n="6" lvl="1"> Risk Analysis </sect>
            <sect n="7" lvl="1"> Conclusion </sect>
        </page>
        <page type="exec_sum">
            In the course of the 2016 elections, certain candidates have expressed concern about voter fraud.  Although voting machines are 
            currently built according to voluntary certifications and tested by accredited laboratories, these processes do not take into account
            the social and administrative factors involved in running a voting precinct.  Therefore, a field testing suite has been proposed to get
            a fuller understanding of the entire voting architecture. <pb/>
            For reasons explained in the following report, it is currently infeasible for the Election Assistance Commission to move forward with this 
            project.  
        </page>
        <page type="pre_req_ana">
            <app_ovr type="obj">There have been various demonstrations of weaknesses in the security of current voting systems, primarily in labs.  
                The Election Assistance Commission has the opportunity to demonstrate the security or lack thereof of voting systems in the field.  
                To that end, a set of tools and procedures could be developed to test various polling locations nationwide.
            </app_ovr>
            <app_ovr type="rls">Depending upon how the suite is designed to be used, its implementation will likely require extensive cooperation 
            from state governments where the suite is used.  It may also require legislation from congress.
            </app_ovr>  
        </page>
        <page type="fsb">
            <fsb_hlgt type="tcnl">The testing suite will need to work with many different voting machines.  Beyond a basic plan, there is
            uncertainty on whether any work can be reused between them.  Also, the suite will need to be flexible enough to incorporate new machines
            as they are produced.  Beyond these problems, the development of the suite should be possible with standard computer security techniques.</fsb_hlgt>
            <fsb_hlgt type="suits">There will likely be legality problems with testing the security at the actual polling places and times.  The
            only way around this is likely a change in laws passed at the federal and possibly even state levels.  Due to the current gridlock in congress
            and the varying makeups of state governments, it is very unlikely that the EAC will be able to deploy the testing suite with any sort
            of uniformity nationwide.</fsb_hlgt>
            <fsb_hlgt type="econ">The EAC likely does not have the financial flexibility to support this project.  With its budget of ten million dollars already 
            being used for other important and required functions, and with congress unlikely to allocate more money in the foreseeable future, it is
            highly unlikely the EAC will be able to find the money for a new major project.  As it is the EAC is only capable of supporting about 30 full time 
            equivalent workers</fsb_hlgt>
        </page>
        <page type="sccs_crt"> 
            <req_sect>Versatility 
                <req>The test suite must be compatible with all currently used voting machines</req> 
                <req>The test suite must be adaptable to the different types of locations and setups of polling places</req></req_sect>
            <req_sect>Adaptability
                <req>The testing suite must be flexible enough to adapt to new types of voting equipment</req>                
            </req_sect>
            <req_sect>Reporting
                <req>The results of the security tests must clearly describe any vulnerabilities so they can be monitored and fixed</req>
            </req_sect>
        </page>
        <page type="cost"><est type="inst">If the EAC goes forward with this project, I do not foresee any major capital costs.  Instead,
        the major cost will be labor.  Some of this work can likely be handled by existing employees.  This could have a negative impact on their 
        other responsibilities. </est> <est type="fnc">It is unlikely that existing workers can handle the increase in tasks by themselves, so new full
        and part time workers will need to be hired.  This could cost a significant amount of money depending on wage rate and how many people end up
        being hired.</est> </page>
        <page type="rsk_ana">The major risk of using a testing suite on the actual election infrastructure is that a bad actor could use the tools
        to commit election fraud.  This could be mitigated by redoing all the polls in locations that were tested.  There are major downsides to that 
        solution though, as it would be very burdensome on governmental resources and would almost certainly decrease final voter turnout.</page>
        <page type="conc"><fsb>In this researcher's opinion, a field based testing suite would be highly infeasable.  There would be major
            obsticals in legality, coordination, and monetary cost.  In return there would be a minimal improvement over current labratory and
            specification based testing.</fsb><cond>If a large amount of political will to complete this testing program manifests 
            itself uniformly across the United States, the EAC could move forward with this project.</cond><sum>I reccomend scrapping
            this project and looking into other ways to improve current testing.</sum>
        </page>
    </fsb_rpt>
    
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="peer_id_here"/>
        <report type="peer" resp="#peer_id_here">
            <p>Peer review report will appear here.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>    
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>