    <?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
    <?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
    <!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
    <DOC>
        <docHead>
            <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
            <title>Mass Ave. Bike Lane Improvement</title>
            <author xml:id="m21">Chris Murphy</author>
            <version n="2" date="2016-08-13"/>
            <!--note that the date must be YYYY-MM-DD for the document to be valid-->
        </docHead>
        
        <pub_init_proposal>
            <cover_page>
                <title>Mass Ave. Bike Lane Improvement</title>
                <author> Chris Murphy</author>
                <submit_date> </submit_date>
                <audience>
                   To the City of Boston and Massachusetts Department of Transportation
                </audience>
            </cover_page>
            
            <tbl_cont>
                    <section n="1">Introduction</section>
                    <section n="2">Background</section>
                    <section n="3">Purpose</section>
                    <section n="4">Action Plan</section>
                    <section n="5">Feasibility</section>
                    <section n="6">Conclusion</section>
                
            </tbl_cont>
            
            <intro type="abstract"><!--attribute options: ltr_int, exec_sum, abstract-->
                <p>Boston is a city well known for its traffic congestion and bad drivers. 
                    In an effort to beat the congestion and go green, many people have turned
                    to biking as an alternative method of transportation in the city. While 
                    Boston has become increasingly bike friendly over the years, there are 
                    still many problem areas, the two most prominent being Commonwealth Avenue 
                    and Massachusetts Avenue. These two roadways account for largest contributions 
                    to bike accident numbers in the city. Although Commonwealth Ave. has a higher
                    total number of accidents, Mass Ave. has the most potential to increase the
                    safety of bike travel through upgrades to the roadway. </p>
            </intro>
            
            <background>
                <p>
                    <crnt_cond>
                        From the Huntington Ave. intersection to the Charles River Bridge is the 
                        most problematic section of Mass Ave. This stretch of road is characterized
                        by poor road conditions, dark areas, and random sharrows, or shared bike/car lanes. 
                    </crnt_cond>
                    <subj_hist>
                        The vast majority of Boston bike infrastructure has been installed very recently, 
                        with most improvements taking place within the last decade. Since 2008, over 90 miles 
                        of bike lanes and markings have been put in place. An additional 3600 public bike 
                        parking spots have also been installed in the same time frame. It is clear that the 
                        city is still undergoing the process of becoming bike friendly and the improvements 
                        to Mass Ave. would be the next logical step in this process. 
                    </subj_hist>
                </p>
            </background>
            
            <purpose>
                <p>
                    <scope type="who"> The city of Boston must give funding to the Massachusetts Department 
                        of Transportation (MassDOT) to organize the construction necessary to improve bike 
                        safety on the highlighted stretch of Mass Ave. When completed, the improved bike lanes 
                        will increase travel safety and efficiency while satisfying the demands of Boston bike 
                        advocate groups. </scope>
                    <objective>The proposed project would include repaving most sections of Mass Ave, 
                        followed by creating clear markings for the bike lanes. It would also include reclaiming 
                        the areas around the Huntington Ave. and Boylston St. intersections, where mismanaged 
                        construction has left concrete barriers indefinitely blocking the bike lanes. Lastly, 
                        there would be lighting upgrades along the stretch from Newbury St. to the Charles River Bridge.
                    </objective>
         
                </p>
            </purpose>
            
            <approach type="">  <!--attribute options: execution, action-->
                <p>
                    To implement the changes, the first step that must be taken is having the MassDOT 
                    hire out a private construction company to take on the upgrades. From there, a plan
                    must be created to carry out the construction process with minimal disruption to 
                    daily traffic flows. Ideally, the ripping, paving, and repainting process could be
                    completed along the 1.2-mile stretch within 2 weeks of night work. Since the 
                    installation/upgrade of streetlights on the sidewalks is a more intensive but much 
                    less disruptive process, it could take closer to a full month to complete.   <!--text here-->
                </p>
            </approach>
            
            <feasibility type="">  <!--attribute options: economic, social, environmental-->
                <p>
                    The two main obstacles in the process are costs and disruptions to traffic flow. 
                    The latter problem could be best mostly resolved by limiting work to night shifts
                    and if necessary, weekends. Since the department of transportation already has allotted
                    budgets for roadwork and improvements, the funding problem is mostly a matter of securing 
                    those funds through petitions and demonstrations as to why the Mass Ave. upgrade is a pertinent 
                    problem. 
                </p>
            </feasibility>
            
            <conclu>
                <p>
                    Performing these upgrades will increase both the usability and safety of bike travel along a 
                    major city road. Indirect affects of the construction would hopefully be an increase in bike 
                    users and decrease in traffic congestion. Overall, the changes will leader to improved transportation 
                    in the city of Boston.  
                </p>
            </conclu>
            
            <references>
                <citation n="" style=""> </citation>
            </references>
        </pub_init_proposal>
        
        <docReview>
            <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
            <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
                <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
            </report>
        </docReview>
   
    
    
    
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="peer_id_here"/>
        <report type="peer" resp="#peer_id_here">
            <p>Peer review report will appear here.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>