<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Project 3</title>
        <author xml:id="m20">Chi Mo</author>
        <version n="2" date="2016-08-22"/>
    </docHead>

    <cover_letter>
        <header>
            <name>Chi Mo</name>
            <contact_info>
                <contact type="address">1025 Hancock St, Apt 8G</contact>
                <contact type="address">Quincy, MA, 02169</contact>
                <contact type="phone"> 857-222-0943 </contact>
                <contact type="email"> moira0501@gmail.com </contact>
            </contact_info>
        </header>
        <greeting>Hello Mr.Morrissey,</greeting>
        <intro_para>
            <intent type="purpose">I am interested in the Software Engineering job at EMC
                Corporation.</intent>
            <intent type="connection"></intent> I became interested in the job, after searching the
            job position on NEU COOL. <reason>I have enjoyed my past work at EMC in the position of
                ADS testing in Hopkinton, </reason> and <proposition>I think I will fit well with
                EMC's culture and bring all the necessary abilities to go above and beyond my job
                requirements.</proposition>
        </intro_para>
        <para_background>
            <experience type="work">I bring previous experience with <programs>Python</programs>
                from my work at EMC in spring 2016 for my second co-op. As I mentioned before, I worked at Advanced
                Design Services group and I coded in <programs>Python</programs> to
                    <accomplishments>test the newest servers and equipments.</accomplishments> Our
                group, ADS, is a sub-team in DFx which stands for Design For X and my boss Dick
                Miller is the manager of the team. In this co-op, I had <accomplishments>developed a
                    loop testing in Cumulus platform and it had been used by ADS to Qual Testware
                    and will be used for Debug. </accomplishments>I also earned a
                    <certifications>Bronze Award</certifications> because of this.
                    <accomplishments>In processing of developing the test sequence, I took the
                    initiative to contact and work with the Cumulus SW Dev team in Shanghai to
                    compelete it. </accomplishments> Besides the developing of the loop,
                    <accomplishments>I also developed the test for POST analyzer for
                    Infinity/Arcus.</accomplishments> In the last month of my co-op, my role was
                changed from a developer to a QA. <accomplishments>I did the SQA job to release the
                    tests for Infinity/Arcus by running tests on all the Warthogs and fixing the
                    software or potiential hardware problem. </accomplishments> Besides the work, I
                had attend drating class and IPMI class while I was working at EMC. I also attended
                the 3D priting workshop which was held in UMASS Lowell. I really enjoyed working in
                EMC before and after the Dell deal.</experience>
            <experience type="work">I had my first co-op in Harvard School of Public Health in spring 2015
                as IT services. In this co-op, I <accomplishments>troubleshot users’ software
                    problems and demonstrated strong custom service skills</accomplishments> and
                    <accomplishments>collaborated with team to manage helpdesk responsibilities and
                    customer issues</accomplishments>.</experience>
            <experience type="school">Aside from my work experience, I learned
                    <programs>C++</programs>, <programs>Java</programs>, <programs>C</programs>, and <programs>XML</programs>
                from my courses at Northeastern University.</experience>
        </para_background>
        <closing_statements>
            <compatability>I think I will fit in well with the culture of EMC Corporation and this
                job position. </compatability>
            <next_step>I hope you will call me at 857-222-0943 so that we can discuss the next step
                in the hiring process. I look forward to working for this company again. Thank you
                very much for your consideration!</next_step>
        </closing_statements>
        <signature>
            <salutation>Yours sincerely,</salutation>
            <name>Chi Mo</name>
        </signature>
    </cover_letter>

    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="h15"/>
        <report type="peer" resp="h15">
            <p>Chi’s genre is a cover letter for a Software Engineering position at EMC, a company
                for which she previously worked as an ADS tester. The object of the piece is to
                emphasize her interests and abilities relating to the job and to get an interview or
                get to the next steps of the hiring process. </p>
            <p> Chi does a good job in bringing in her previous experience from her co-ops,
                especially her previous EMC position. Potentially, she should go more in depth with
                her previous position at EMC and emphasize that she has already been a part of the
                community and flourished. Adding something like, “I look forward to working for this
                company again” will grab their attention and reiterate her involvement.
                Additionally, it would be good if she mentions her nontechnical abilities, such as
                working in a team and meeting stressful deadlines since those are important
                qualities in a candidate. I also recommend explaining any personal projects that
                relates to the skills needed for the position to show that she has a passion for
                that type of work. If not, then she can list some of her main technical interests or
                focus areas that tie in. Other than that, rewording some sentences and fixing some
                grammar would help the flow of the piece (I put some recommendations in). </p>
            <p> Overall, cover letters accompany resumes, so I think she should focus on emphasizing
                what isn’t included on her resume – that is strong personal traits and technical
                interests. Lastly, cover letters let candidates go more in depth in projects to show
                the company that they have a strong understanding in their studies, so that would
                also be good to look into. </p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
