<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Project 3 Cover Letter</title>
        <author xml:id="m19">Your name here</author>
        <version n="1" date="2016-08-14"/>
    </docHead>

    <!-- root element for P3 here -->
    <cover_letter>
        <header>
            <name>Sydnee Mizuno</name>
            <contact_info>
                <!-- One or More Contact -->
                <contact type="address">894 Huntington Ave</contact>
                <contact type="address">Boston, MA 02115</contact>
                <contact type="phone">916-212-5495</contact>
                <contact type="email">mizuno.s@husky.neu.edu</contact>
            </contact_info>
        </header>
        <greeting>Dear Mr. Doe,</greeting>
        <intro_para>
            <intent type="purpose">I am writing to apply for the electrical engineering position at
                iRobot that was posted on Northeastern University's co-op search site.</intent>
            <reason> I am currently a fourth-year student in electrical engineering,</reason>
                and<proposition> I am very interested in gaining more experience with robotic
                systems. Given my previous experience and interest in this field, I think that I
                would be a good fit for this position.</proposition>
        </intro_para>

        <para_background>
            <experience type="work">At my previous co-op with Corindus Vascular Robotics, I worked
                in the Research and Development lab on a medical robot that assisted with
                percutaneous coronary intervention procedures.<programs> Using C#, I wrote code for
                    the state machine that controlled the embedded robotic system. I also programmed
                    the robot's display and communication modules with Serious SHIPTide, and I
                    extensively used CANCapture for debugging. To test the functionality of existing
                    code, I also wrote unit tests with NUnit.</programs>
                <skills> In addition to writing code, I was involved with software verification
                    testing. This included writing test protocols to meet various system
                    requirements and using those protocols to physically test the robot. I also
                    developed Windows applications to assist with automated reliability testing.
                    Throughout this work, I collaborated closely with other members of the software
                    team to meet our goals. This included participating in daily stand-up meetings
                    to discuss completed tasks, items in progress, and future work.</skills>
            </experience>
        </para_background>

        <para_background>
            <experience type="school">In addition to my work experience, I have developed many
                technical and communication skills through my classes and labs at
                    Northeastern.<skills> In my Electronics class, I worked with op-amps, diodes,
                    BJTs, and MOSFETS.</skills><programs> In my Embedded Design class, I wrote C
                    programs in Linux to run on an embedded processor. I also used Simulink to
                    program a Zedboard's FPGA and control a robotic arm.</programs><skills>I wrote
                    technical reports detailing the projects in these classes, and I worked
                    effectively with lab partners.</skills></experience>
            <experience type="work"> While taking classes, I also worked in Northeastern's SMILE
                lab, which focuses on machine learning and computer vision. I collaborated with a
                team to gather images for a Kinship Recognition project.</experience>
        </para_background>

        <closing_statements>
            <compatability>I think that with my strong interpersonal skills and past experience, I
                would integrate well within iRobot's innovative environment.</compatability>
            <next_step>I would be excited to meet with you and discuss the position in more detail
                soon.</next_step>
            <acknowledgment> Thank you for your consideration.</acknowledgment>
        </closing_statements>
        <signature>
            <salutation>Sincerely,</salutation>
            <name>Sydnee Mizuno</name>
        </signature>
    </cover_letter>
    <!-- Writer' Memo -->
    <!-- I think that I'm far in the process of writing a cover letter. My rheterorical situation is responding to a job position. 
         I think that my experience is detailed and helps expand what's listed on my resume. Sometimes it can be difficult to condense all of the
         work experience into concise paragraphs. I would like the reviewer to look at the "school experience" and "compatibility."-->
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="peer_id_here"/>
        <report type="peer" resp="#peer_id_here">
            <p>Peer review report will appear here.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
