<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>WP3 </title>
        <author xml:id="p22">Matt Parlon</author>
        <version n="1" date="2016-08-11"/>
    </docHead>
    <!-- root element for P3 here -->
    <cover_letter>
        <header>
            <name>Matt Parlon</name>
            <contact_info>
                <!-- One or More Contact -->
                <contact type="address">116 Hemenway St. Apt.3E</contact>
                <contact type="phone"> 617-319-5868 </contact>
                <contact type="email"> parlon.m@husky.neu.edu </contact>
            </contact_info>
        </header>
        <greeting>Hello Jane Doe,</greeting>
        <intro_para>
            <intent type="purpose">I am interested in the Analyst position within the Ameresco Project Management team.</intent>
            <intent type="connection"><!-- Optional --> During my time at BlueWave Capital, I recieved some exposure to Ameresco's 
            work and was immediately impressed. </intent> After evaluating Ameresco's development history and continual production of quality work
            , I became interested in this position.
            <reason><!-- Optional --> I have enjoyed my past work with Solar Project Development in
                the past</reason> and <proposition>I think I will fit well with Ameresco's challenging culture
                    and bring all the necessary abilities to go above and beyond my job requirements.
                </proposition>
        </intro_para>
        <para_background>
            <!-- One or More -->
            <experience type="work">Throughout my three co-ops at Northeastern University, I was able to hone my 
                <programs>AutoCAD and Excel</programs> 
                skills in a manner that increased the efficiency of my work as well as that of my peers'.
                <programs>Excel</programs> proved to be increasingly useful <accomplishments>as I recognized areas of inneficiency within my previous companies' workflow</accomplishments>  and 
                <accomplishments>was able to develop macros to automate previously manual processes.</accomplishments> </experience>
            
            <experience type="school">
                At Northeastern, I gained <skills>technical communication</skills> 
                skills from my work within the Sustainable Energy Systems minor. Through various projects within the
                graduate classes associated with this program I was able to utilize the knowledge gained in my earlier classes as well as on my co-ops
                to work towards unique solutions to proposed issues regarding the leglislative, economic, and environmental issues assocated with 
                solar energy.
                </experience>
            <experience type="school">
                My final project at Northeastern allowed me to improve my <skills>ability to communicate effectively with various specialists</skills> 
                to work toward a common goal. My capstone project to design a potable water distribution system as well as energy generation facility in Haiti 
                let me communicate with environmental and electric specialists as I filled the role of solar development specialist.
            </experience>
            
            
        </para_background>
        <closing_statements>
            <compatability>I believe my skills and passion for renewable energy will help me to fit in well with a Ameresco team and
            have a positive impact on the Project Management Team.</compatability><pb/>
            <next_step>Please call me at 617-319-5868 to discuss the possibility of continuing to the interview phase of the hiring process.</next_step>
        </closing_statements>
        <signature>
            <salutation>Sincerely,</salutation>
            <name>Matt Parlon</name>
        </signature>
    </cover_letter>
    
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="peer_id_here"/>
        <report type="peer" resp="#peer_id_here">
            <p>Peer review report will appear here.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>