<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Writing Project Three </title>
        <author xml:id="p22">Matt Parlon</author>
        <version n="3" date="2016-08-20"/>
    </docHead>
    <!-- root element for P3 here -->
    <cover_letter>
        <header>
            <name>Matt Parlon</name>
            <contact_info>
                <!-- One or More Contact -->
                <contact type="address">116 Hemenway St. Apt.3E</contact>
                <contact type="phone"> 617-319-5868 </contact>
                <contact type="email"> parlon.m@husky.neu.edu </contact>
            </contact_info>
        </header>
        <greeting>Hello,<note type="peer">If you don't know who its going to say "Hiring
                Committee"</note></greeting>
        <intro_para>
            <intent type="purpose">I am interested in the Analyst position within the Ameresco
                Project Management team.</intent>
            <intent type="connection"><!-- Optional --> During my time at BlueWave Capital, I
                recieved some exposure to Ameresco submittals and was immediately impressed by the
                quality of work. <note type="peer">was immediately impressed with... their work
                    ethic? their project difficulty or varety or impact?</note>
            </intent> After evaluating Ameresco's development history and continual production of
            quality projects, I became interested in persuing<note type="instructor" resp="#kgs"
                >pursuing</note> a role on their project management team. <note type="peer">maybe
                say you became increasingly interested in the company, because right now you haven't
                really mentioned anything position specific or specific to the management team. If
                you make it clear you are impressed with the work of the management group then I
                think it would make sense to say you are interested in the position
                specifically.</note>
            <reason><!-- Optional --> I have enjoyed my work with Solar Project Development in the
                past</reason> and <proposition>I think I will fit well with Ameresco's challenging
                culture and contribute to your goal of expanding sustainable energy generation.<note
                    type="instructor" resp="#kgs">good specificity here</note>
            </proposition>
        </intro_para>
        <para_background>
            <!-- One or More -->
            <experience type="work">Throughout my three co-ops at Northeastern University, I was
                able to hone my <programs>AutoCAD and Excel</programs> skills in a manner that
                increased the efficiency of my work as well as that of my peers'.
                    <programs>Excel</programs> proved to be increasingly useful <accomplishments>as
                    I recognized areas of inneficiency within my previous companies'
                    workflow</accomplishments> and <accomplishments>was able to develop macros to
                    automate previously manual processes.</accomplishments>
            </experience>
            <experience type="school"> At Northeastern, I gained <note type="peer">cosider: "I
                    gained valuable technical communication skills"</note><skills>technical
                    communication</skills> skills from my work within the Sustainable Energy Systems
                minor. Through various projects within the graduate classes associated with this
                program I was able to utilize the knowledge gained in my earlier classes as well as
                on my co-ops to work towards unique solutions to proposed issues. Advanced classes
                within this minor evaluated the leglislative, economic, and environmental issues
                assocated with solar energy.<note type="peer">This is a very long sentence, consider
                    breaking it down for clarity.</note>
            </experience>
            <experience type="school"> My capstone project<note type="peer">If by final project you
                    are reffering to capstone, make sure you talk about it in presenent tense if you
                    plan to send this letter out prior to graduation. Otherwise this sentence makes
                    it sound like you are already done with school.</note> at Northeastern will
                allow me to improve my <skills>ability to communicate effectively with various
                    specialists</skills> working towards a common goal. Our project goal, to design
                a potable water distribution system as well as an energy generation facility in
                Haiti, will give me the opportunity to<note type="peer">consider rewording from "let
                    you" to "required you to" or something a little less flimsy. It will help make
                    it clear you learned valuable information from these people rather than just
                    chitchatted or something!</note> communicate with environmental and electric
                specialists as I fill the role of solar development specialist. </experience>
        </para_background>
        <closing_statements>
            <compatability>I believe my skills and passion for renewable energy will help me to fit
                in well with the<note type="peer">change "a" to "the", you want to fit in with the
                    company as a whole</note> Ameresco team and have a positive impact on the
                Project Management Team.</compatability>
            <pb/>
            <next_step>Please reach out to me at the contacts listed above to discuss the
                possibility of an interview. I look forward to hearing from you. <note type="peer"
                    >Consider rewording, sounds a bit robotic and unfeeling. Maybe also saying that
                    you look forward to hearing back from them so that they know you are genuinely
                    interested in them!</note></next_step>
        </closing_statements>
        <signature>
            <salutation>Sincerely,</salutation>
            <name>Matt Parlon</name>
        </signature>
    </cover_letter>

    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="w28"/>
        <report type="peer" resp="#w28">
            <p>For writing project three Matt wrote a cover letter to Ameresco applying for an
                analyst position within their project management team. His letter very clearly
                addresses his privious experience with the company, his reasons for being interested
                in the position, and his qualifications for holding the position. Overall I think
                that this is a very solid cover letter that could most definitely warrent a follow
                up interview. It is very technical in nature and gives simple logical reasons for
                why he would be an appropriate candidate. One thing that I think he could improve on
                however is his choice of language. Some of his statements can be a bit too dry, as
                seen in his next steps sentence. It is important to remember that although a cover
                letter is an introduction for why you think you should get the position, your resume
                will highlight many of the academic and experience related reasons for why you are
                qualified. I have been told by employers in the past that these letters should also
                be able to highlight your character and your personal interests to show them that
                you would fit with their company culture. Consider speaking more specifically to
                what you know and like about the company, rather than keeping it broad, as well as
                including some level of personal connection to show why you like this thing that
                they do or service that they provide. Also, in your writers memo you mentioned
                wanting to show the benfits of having a technical engineering background as a member
                of the management team. I think that this could be a good thing to tie your personal
                interests to the position. Consider adding a short second background paragraph
                discussing how your experience with your capstone team allowed you to learn a lot
                about managing a team and how that is much easier to do if you understand the
                technical aspects of what all of your team members are working on. For this reason
                you would be able to bring those valuable communication and planning skills when
                working with engineers and technical professionals into the management team at
                Ameresco. This helps wrap up your background with a tie back to the company and
                leaves them thinking about how awesome of an addition you would be to their
                management team specifically! </p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>This is a solid cover letter; you do a nice job balancing general achievements wiht
                specifics that are relevant to the job at hand. See notes above for minor
                corrections.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
