<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Public Initiative Proposal</title>
        <author xml:id="s23">Monica Salas</author>
        <version n="1" date="2016-08-16"/>
    </docHead>

    <pub_init_proposal>
        <cover_page>
            <title>WRTA Redesign</title>
            <author>Monica Salas</author>
            <submit_date>August 30th 2016</submit_date>
            <audience> To: The City of Worcester’s Executive Office of Economic Development
            </audience>
        </cover_page>

        <tbl_cont>
            <section n="1">Introduction</section>
            <section n="2">Background</section>
            <section n="3">Purpose</section>
            <section n="4">Approach</section>
            <section n="5">Feasibility</section>
            <section n="6">Conclusion</section>
            <section n="7">References</section>
        </tbl_cont>

        <intro type="exec_sum">
            <!--attribute options: ltr_int, exec_sum, abstract-->
            <p>Over the past several years, the city of Worcester, MA has invested several millions
                of dollars into improving the city. Federal and state money has been dedicated to
                cleaning up parks and neighborhoods, reconstructing the entire down town area and
                Union Station, establishing community centers and helping create jobs for the
                citizens of Worcester. Despite all the work going into these projects, public
                transportation has been completely overlooked. How does the city expect to increase
                employment if half of it’s population doesn’t have a good way to get to work?
                Worcester has long been a city dependent on cars since so much of it’s work force
                resides in suburbs and neighboring towns. Most people know that the WRTA (Worcester
                Regional Transit Authority) exists, but they don’t know how to use it. This is
                because of the small amount and obscurity of bus stops and schedules and completely
                inconvenient routes. Implementing something like Boston’s MBTA is not realistic in a
                city like Worcester, however major reorganization and improvements to the WRTA could
                provide huge benefits in driving economic growth in Worcester, as well as making it
                much more pleasant place to live. Rerouting existing routes to reach major
                residential areas (especially low income neighborhoods) and heavy commercialized
                areas, adding busses and bus stops, making public transportation more affordable and
                accessible to students and young adults, and providing more rigorous training for
                bus drivers would dramatically turn around the state of Worcester’s public
                transportation. All this could be achieved with predetermined yearly milestones
                being funded by the city’s federal grant under the Community Development Block Grant
                Program. </p>
        </intro>

        <background>
            <p>
                <crnt_cond> As of right now, only 55% of all jobs in Worcester have access to public
                    transportation routes; and only 6% of people who reside in suburbs (where rent
                    and mortgages are more affordable) have public transportation available to their
                    work within 90 minutes (5). On top of this, Worcester Public Schools have
                    consistently cut school bus services for students to get to school every day. In
                    past years, Worcester Public Schools has charged students hundreds of dollars to
                    be able to take a school bus to school, and have even suspended bus
                    transportation for students in high school or who live within 2 miles of their
                    schools. Considering the level of financial diversity in Worcester and how harsh
                    winters can be in the Northeast, these scenarios pose a clear need for more
                    accessible public transportation in Worcester. Currently, most developments in
                    transportation in Worcester have been via intercity busses like PeterPan and
                    Greyhound busses that go to Providence and New York, Amtrak trains to Boston,
                    and planes coming in through the now open Worcester Airport(1). All these modes
                    of transportation open routes to bring more people to Worcester, but don’t
                    provide any way for people to get around the city. Most bus routes currently
                    just connect downtown Worcester to major shopping centers in the Greater
                    Worcester Area and two universities in the area, not to residential or even more
                    widely commercialized areas.
                    <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
                </crnt_cond>
                <subj_hist> The WRTA is, at best, inconvenient to use. This is a major barrier in
                    the economic growth of the city because of how difficult it is for anyone to get
                    around to be able to get to work or even get anyone within the city to spend
                    money (2). Worcester is rich in resources for anyone who has the luxury of
                    owning a car, but remains segregated to the lower income population and
                    inaccessible to outsiders (4). Aside from this, the existing transportation
                    facilities are difficult to find, dingy and unsafe looking, unadvertised, and
                    generally inaccessible (1).
                    <!-- can include <q> element(s) for quoted material -->
                </subj_hist>
            </p>
        </background>

        <purpose>
            <p>
                <scope type="what">Even with all the money that Worcester is putting into developing
                    the city and giving it a much needed ‘face lift’, all the progress will reach a
                    glass ceiling without improvements made to the transportation system. </scope>
                <!--attribute options: what, who, when, where-->
                <objective>Economic growth will only be stimulated from an improved transportation
                    system, despite the capital costs of investing in transportation. Better bus
                    routes could increase accessibility for students to get to school every day, and
                    make the city more accessible for visitors. If money could be spared to make the
                    initial capital investments in a better bus system for the WRTA, then this would
                    be a massive stimulus for the city of Worcester.</objective>
            </p>
        </purpose>

        <approach>
            <!--attribute options: execution, action-->
            <p>
                <execution>Worcester is a recipient of a $3.8 million annual grant funding from the
                    United States Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) called the
                    Community Development Block Grant Program (CDBG). Each year it submits a request
                    for proposals to investigate ideas for how this money could be spend to benefit
                    low and moderate income persons, eliminate slums or blight, or meet urgent needs
                    of the city (3). The transportation system addresses all three of these types of
                    needs that the grant funding is intended for. With a team of financial
                    representatives of the city, officials from the Worcester WRTA, and contractors
                    invested in building infrastructure in the city, a 5 year plan could be made to
                    invest 15-30% of this grant funding annually into the reworking of the WRTA.
                    Milestones could be predetermined based on priority areas in the city and
                    necessary development of Worcester Transit Authority. Milestones each year will
                    include buying new energy efficient busses to serve the city, construct safe,
                    well lit, strategically placed bus stops, advertise bus travel within Worcester
                    and it’s surrounding towns, subsidize transportation services for students,
                    reorganize routes that reach into more suburban areas, and hire more well
                    qualified drivers and officials for the WRTA.</execution></p>
        </approach>

        <feasibility>
            <!--attribute options: economic, social, environmental-->
            <p>
                <economic>Improving Worcester’s public transportation system is less of a question
                    of if it will get done, and more of a question of when and and how. The city’s
                    economic boom that it is experiencing right now will stagnate without improved
                    transportation services. Now that Worcester has achieved so much federal funding
                    for city development and has gained momentum in the community’s investment in
                    the city, it is a perfect time to make a major overhaul like transportation
                    within the city. The funding exists and the need is evident. Planning would
                    require input from financial professionals and zoning committees in order to
                    figure out the best to invest in the WRTA and where there is most need for
                    public transportation. This initial set up would be the biggest capital
                    investment, however most of the costs could be covered by the CDBG grant and
                    could be spread out over several years. The only lasting costs would be salaries
                    for the increase in WRTA drivers and employees and maintenance to buses and new
                    infrastructure. The hope would be that these long term costs will be
                    insignificant compared to the financial benefits the city would gain by becoming
                    more accessible to outsiders and making work more possible for residents. If
                    needed, there are many big businesses and organizations that could benefit from
                    public transportation in the city. Big business owners and surrounding towns
                    could be willing to invest in a public transportation system that could bring
                    people to their business and make their own communities more accessible.
                </economic></p>
        </feasibility>

        <conclu>
            <p> Investing in public transportation within Worcester would be investing in the future
                growth of Worcester. It would make holding a job more possible for low and middle
                income populations and increase accessibilities to commercial and residential areas
                of the city. It would also make it possible for kids to miss less school, thus
                boosting education and providing a break for the Worcester Public schools who take
                sole responsibility for getting their students to school every day. It would also
                benefit surrounding towns that are considered “bedroom towns” to Worcester.
                <!--text here-->
            </p>
        </conclu>

        <references>
            <citation n="1" style="MLA"> "Groundbreaking Ceremony for WRTA Transportation Hub | City
                of Worcester, MA." Groundbreaking Ceremony for WRTA Transportation Hub | City of
                Worcester, MA. N.p., n.d. Web. 15 Aug. 2016.</citation>
            <citation n="2" style="MLA">"GoLocalWorcester | Politics | Grace Ross: How to Solve
                Worcester’s Public Transportation Problems." GoLocalWorcester Main. N.p., n.d. Web.
                15 Aug. 2016.</citation>
            <citation n="3" style="MLA"> "GoLocalWorcester | News | Worcester’s Public
                Transportation 2nd Worst in NE." GoLocalWorcester Main. N.p., n.d. Web. 15 Aug.
                2016.</citation>
            <citation n="4" style="MLA">"GoLocalWorcester | News | Worcester’s Public Transportation
                Critical to Economic Growth." GoLocalWorcester Main. N.p., n.d. Web. 15 Aug.
                2016.</citation>
            <citation n="5" style="MLA">CDBG Request Document</citation>
        </references>
    </pub_init_proposal>


    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="peer_id_here"/>
        <report type="peer" resp="#peer_id_here">
            <p>Peer review report will appear here.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
