<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>WP3 Edutainment Blog Post</title>
        <author xml:id="s25">Leo Stolov</author>
        <version n="1" date="2016-08-13"/>
    </docHead>

    <blog_post>
        <background>
            <section_header>Why are bacteria shaped the way they are?</section_header>
            <question>Question</question>
            <misconception>misconception</misconception>
            <important_idea>But to understand exactly the reason for these weird shapes one first
                has to understand something about the world of bacteria, specifically the fluid the
                fluid they move in. The first step is to understand the Reynolds number.
            </important_idea>
        </background>
        <answer>
            <section_header>What is the Reynolds number?</section_header>
            <technical_principle n="1">Mathematically, the Reynolds number can be expressed like
                this: <visual type="other"
                    url="http://ffden-2.phys.uaf.edu/104_2012_web_projects/Daniela_Wilner/Images/ReynoldsNumber.png"
                /> The Reynolds number (Re in the equation above) is defined as the ratio of
                inertial forces to viscous forces. What does that mean? Well the first thing that
                should be noted is that it is a ratio. It has no units attached. The Reynolds number
                can be 46, it can 46,000. It’s just a number. But it is a very useful number,
                especially for engineers. Engineers use the Reynolds number to characterize how a
                fluid (liquid or gas) flows. It tells engineers when to use certain equations for
                certain situations, and when not to use them. </technical_principle>
            <section_header>What does the Reynolds number depend on?</section_header>
            <technical_principle n="2">Here’s the breakdown: ρ is density of the fluid, V is
                velocity, D is diameter, or the size of the volume of the fluid is flowing in, μ is
                viscosity which is a fluid's resistance to movement <analogy>(molasses is much more
                    viscous than water).</analogy>
            </technical_principle>
            <analogy>Let's take a person swimming in water.
            <visual type="drawing"
                url="http://www.how-to-draw-funny-cartoons.com/image-files/cartoon-swimmer-007.jpg"
            />
               
            </analogy>
            
            
        </answer>
        <sources/>
    </blog_post>

    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="peer_id_here"/>
        <report type="peer" resp="#peer_id_here">
            <p>Peer review report will appear here.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
