<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>WP3 Edutainment Blog Post</title>
        <author xml:id="s25">Leo Stolov</author>
        <version n="1" date="2016-08-18"/>
    </docHead>

    <blog_post>
        <title>Traveling at the microscopic level</title>
        <background>
            <question>How is it that bacteria travel from one place to another?</question>
            <misconception>To many, the answer may seem trivial, since motion is a problem solved by
                nature time and time again, when in reality, there are many concepts at play which
                complicate this problem. To truly understand the mechanisms for travel and why they
                are the way they are requires an understanding about microscopic things like
                bacteria, specifically the world they live in.</misconception>
            <technical_principle>The first step is to understand the <important_idea>Reynolds
                    number.</important_idea>
            </technical_principle>
        </background>
        <answer>
            <section_header>What is the Reynolds number?</section_header>
            <technical_principle n="1">Mathematically, the Reynolds number can be expressed like
                this: <visual type="other"
                    url="http://ffden-2.phys.uaf.edu/104_2012_web_projects/Daniela_Wilner/Images/ReynoldsNumber.png"
                /> The Reynolds number (Re in the equation above) is defined as the ratio of
                inertial forces to viscous forces. What does that mean? Well the first thing that
                should be noted is that it is a ratio. It has no units attached. The Reynolds number
                can be 46, it can 46 million. It’s just a number. But it is a very useful number,
                especially for engineers. Engineers use the Reynolds number to characterize how a
                fluid (liquid or gas) flows. It characterizes the flow of a liquid, allowing
                engineers to make certain assumptions and what equations to use. </technical_principle>
            <section_header>What does the Reynolds number depend on?</section_header>
            <technical_principle n="2">Here’s the breakdown: ρ is density of the fluid, V is
                velocity, D is diameter, or the size of the volume being analyzed, and μ is
                viscosity, which is a fluid's resistance to movement <analogy>(molasses is much more
                    viscous than water).</analogy>
            </technical_principle>
            <section_header>So what is low for a Reynolds number?</section_header>
            <analogy>Let's take a person swimming in water. Let's call him Pichael Melps. <visual
                    type="drawing"
                    url="http://www.how-to-draw-funny-cartoons.com/image-files/cartoon-swimmer-007.jpg"
                />Pichael swims at an average speed of 2 mph or .894 m/s in water which has a
                density of 1000 kg/m^3 and a viscosity of about 10^-3 Pa*s. We can approximate
                Pichael's size, or diameter, as 1.5 ft or .457 m. Put these numbers into the
                equation and we get a Reynolds number of about 409000. Now, lets take a look at an
                E. coli cell. <visual type="drawing"
                    url="http://hyperphysics.phy-astr.gsu.edu/hbase/biology/imgbio/cellprokaryote6.gif"
                />A typical cell might be 2 μm or 2*10^-6 m and travel in water at a speed of 30
                μm/s or 3*10^-7 m/s. In this case your Reynolds number would be 0.00006 . That's
                several magnitudes smaller than Pichael's situation. If Pichael wanted to experience
                the same Reynold's number as an E. coli cell he would have to move at a speed of
                about 1.3*10^-10 m/s. If he were to move at that speed for a whole year he would
                travel a staggering 4 millimeters.</analogy>
            <section_header>What does this tell us?</section_header>
            <important_idea>It tells us fluid flow has different properties at this level. It tells
                us life is different at low Reynolds numbers. </important_idea><technical_principle
                n="3">To understand this further we have to go back to the definition of Reynolds
                number: the ratio of inertial forces to viscous forces. The lower your Reynolds
                number, the lower your inertia is compared to the viscous forces of the fluid around
                you.</technical_principle>
            <analogy>What does this mean? Imagine you get in the water and push Pichael. He will
                move while he’s being pushed, and then inertia will carry him so he floats a little
                bit farther away from you. Do the same in molasses, and he’ll stop almost
                immediately once the force of your push stops acting on him. <technical_principle
                    n="4">His movement in the molasses only depends on a current force acting on
                    him, not on the forces acting on him before. In this case, his movement is not
                    dependent on time. It is said to be <important_idea>time
                        invariant.</important_idea>
                </technical_principle>
            </analogy>
            <section_header>Scallop Theorem </section_header>
            <specific_topic>This concept is the cornerstone of Scallop Theorem, a theorem developed
                by physicist Edward Mills Purcell in his paper &quot;Life at low Reynolds
                number.&quot;</specific_topic><technical_principle n="5">”. It states that to travel
                at low Reynolds number a swimmer has to move or deform in a way that is not
                reciprocal. </technical_principle>
            <analogy>. A great example of this is, of course, the scallop. A scallop travels in
                water by slowly opening its shell to take in water, and quickly squirting it out to
                propel itself. <visual type="drawing"
                    url="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/4/40/Scallop_jump.svg"
                    /><technical_principle n="6">While this works great in a scallop’s environment,
                    it would be useless at low Reynolds numbers, due to the fact that the movement
                    is reciprocal. Since motion at low Reynolds flow is time invariant, the fact
                    that the scallop opened and closed its shell slowly and quickly does not matter.
                    In this case, the scallop would simply move one way when the shell opens, and
                    move right back to the same spot when it closes.
                </technical_principle></analogy>
            <section_header>How does this apply to microorganisms?</section_header>
            <explanation>Due to these constraints, bacteria have developed interesting ways to move
                around. The most common of these methods is the use of flagella, which are whip-like
                appendages connected to the main cell body by a hook.<visual type="drawing"
                    url="http://i.imgur.com/hDHJp6l.jpg"/> The hook is connected to a biological
                motor, which spins the flagella. The spinning of these typically helical flagella
                works since it is not reciprocal; it is different when done in forward or in
                reverse. <visual type="drawing" url="http://i.imgur.com/l2bQzNs.png"/> The use of
                flagella is fairly common in the world of bacteria. E coli. use flagella. <visual
                    type="photo"
                    url="http://knowledgeinsider.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/e-coli-streptococci.jpg"
                /> So does Helicobacter pylori, a bacterium found in the stomach. <visual
                    type="photo"
                    url="http://userfiles.steadyhealth.com/userfiles/4540/articles/H.pylori.gif"/>
                Other bacteria such as the Spirochaete have a spiral shape and move by whole-body
                undulations. Their spiral shape allow their movement to be non-reciprocal. <visual
                    type="photo"
                    url="https://microbewiki.kenyon.edu/images/thumb/f/f4/Figure1.png/400px-Figure1.png"
                />
            </explanation>
            <section_header>Conclusion</section_header>
            <conclusion>Given their microscopic size, it's quite fascinating to see such developed
                forms of movement. A naturally occurring rotating element and motor are certainly
                surprising characteristics to find in puny bacteria since these are things that
                cultured humans like Pichael need lots of brainpower and resources to create.
                Nevertheless, it makes sense, since these traits were the response to a completely
                different set of rules on the microscopic level. </conclusion><visual type="comic"
                url="https://s-media-cache-ak0.pinimg.com/564x/cb/32/6c/cb326c2a1112a7ed8b9484651ae3a3e6.jpg"
            />
        </answer>
        <sources>
            <section_header>Sources</section_header>I highly recommend reading <ref type="source"
                url="http://www.uam.es/personal_pdi/ciencias/agrait/nico_archivos/docencia/fisica%20de%20fluidos/Life%20at%20Low%20Reynolds%20Number,%20EM%20Purcell%201973.htm"
                > Life at Low Reynolds Number </ref> for a more in depth look at this topic. <ref
                type="source" url="http://www.damtp.cam.ac.uk/user/lauga/papers/114.pdf">This
                paper</ref> on bacterial hydrodynamics provides a closer look on bacteria mechanism
            for movement, especially the use of rotating flagella. Additionally, <ref type="source"
                url="https://www.amherst.edu/users/D/ndarnton/extra/hydrodynamics">this post</ref>
            on hydrodynamics has great analogies and examples relevant to the Reynolds number.
        </sources>
    </blog_post>

    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="d13"/>
        <report type="peer" resp="#d13">
            <p>For project 3 Leo composed an edutainment blog about the movement of bacteria and the
                challenges of moving anything at a microscopic level. He focuses on three main
                scientific topics, the Reynolds number, Microscopic movement and how bacteria
                overcome their difficult environment to move around. He begins with an explanation
                of the Reynolds number and how it is calculated and then discusses what happens to
                the Reynolds number at a microscopic level before focusing on the movement of
                bacteria.</p>
            <p>This blog post is well thought out and fits well with the schema created by group 1.
                In particular, the visuals are very effective aides alongside the explanation of
                complex scientific and engineering concepts. The explanation of the Reynolds number
                was easy to understand and I believe that your intended audience will be able to
                grasp the concepts outlined in this blog post. All the required technical
                information is explained well, and the intended audience of the high school educated
                population will be able to comprehend it.</p>
            <p>As mentioned in you writer's memo, I do believe you have yet to decide on what the
                main topic of this blog post should be. The title of the post is "How do bacteria
                move", but this is only addressed very briefly at the end of the post. This post
                could equally be about the principle of the Reynolds number in general, what happens
                to movement at a microscopic level or how bacteria overcome the challenges of their
                environment, specifically related to movement. I think you have all the content
                necessary to pursue any one of these three topics, the post would just need to be
                edited to use that information to focus on the answer to the main question. Of the
                three topics, I believe you will have the most success by focusing on movement at
                the microscopic level. The information about the Reynolds number would serve as a
                good lead in to the microscopic environment and the challenges it presents. In
                particular, the idea that no movement is possible at the Reynolds numbers seen at
                microscopic levels is theoretically impossible as it would be inherently reversible
                should be expanded upon. By establishing the conditions of movement at the
                microscopic level, you could then explain how nature has found ways to overcome
                these challenges(the scallops or flagella).</p>
            <p>Overall, I believe this post is very well constructed and has a good balance of
                scientific information and the analogies and pictures that help explain the complex
                topics. The post adheres very well to the schema created by group one and is both
                educational and interesting to read. My main advice is to make minor changes
                throughout the piece that focuses the information towards answering one main
                question, rather than three at once.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
