<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Automated Magnet Based Anti-Drone System Feasibility Report</title>
        <author xml:id="s24">Oliver Scott</author>
        <version n="1" date="2016-08-20"/>
    </docHead>
    <!-- root element for P3 here -->
    <fsb_rpt>
        <page type="ttl">
            <title>Automated Magnet Based Anti-Drone System</title>
            <subTitle>Automating drone movements with target based optical tracking</subTitle>
            <contributors>Oliver Scott, Nate Winn, Tanner Lindemer, Robert Daigle, Robert Peterson,
                Robert LeBel</contributors>
            <date>August 16th 2016</date>
        </page>
        <page type="tbl_contents">
            <sect lvl="1" n="1">Executive Summary</sect>
            <sect lvl="1" n="2">Preliminary Analysis</sect>
            <sect lvl="2" n="1">Tracking</sect>
            <sect lvl="2" n="2">Target Acquisition</sect>
            <sect lvl="2" n="3">Regulations</sect>
            <sect lvl="1" n="3">Feasibility</sect>
            <sect lvl="1" n="4"> Success Criteria
                <note type="peer">should be n="4"</note>Success Criteria</sect>
            <sect lvl="2" n="1">Hardware Design</sect>
            <sect lvl="2" n="2">Automated Flight</sect>
            <sect lvl="2" n="3">Target Acquisition</sect>
            <sect lvl="1" n="5">Cost</sect>
            <sect lvl="1" n="6">Report <note type="peer"> Are you going to include the conclusion in
                    the table of contents?</note></sect>
            <sect lvl="1" n="7">Risk Analysis</sect>
            <sect lvl="1" n="8">Conclusion</sect>
        </page>
        <page type="exec_sum"><background>The proliferation of single board computers has greatly
                reduced the cost and complexity of drone development. As a result, an exponential
                number of drones are taking to the skies each year, outpacing the FAA and local
                authorities' ability to regulate them. The difficulty of regulating aerial vehicles
                compounded with the ability of pilots to navigate their drones from remote locations
                exposes serious vulnerabilities with maintaining privacy, safety and
                security.</background>
            <pb/><report_purpose>This report will investigate a novel way to police drones using an
                anti-drone system.</report_purpose><fsb.approach> The approach proposed surveys an
                anti-drone that would autonomously track and capture a target drone using
                electromagnets.</fsb.approach>
            <key_findings>The project carries a high number of developmental difficulties -- chiefly
                due to the fact research is being performed in tandem with engineering -- making
                predicting success highly difficult. Even with these risks in consideration however, the
                design remains feasible enough to develop as a worthwhile proof of concept. </key_findings>
        </page>
        <page type="prelim_ana">
            <app_ovr type="obj" title="Tracking">The anti-drone will be able to takeoff from a given
                location while being operated by a pilot. Once the target is in frame and
                recognized, the drone should be capable of autonomously moving above the target. </app_ovr>
            <app_ovr type="obj" title="Target Acquisition">Once the anti-drone is in position,
                electromagnets will be deployed to neutralize the target. At this point the pilot
                can resume control and navigate the anti-drone to a position which releasing the
                disabled drone will not jeopardize the public or property. </app_ovr>
            <app_ovr type="rls" title="Regulations">The FAA has been regularly advancing regulations
                on drone usage. The most up to date rules can be found at:
                    <ref>https://www.faa.gov/uas/media/Part_107_Summary.pdf</ref>. Relevant to our
                project are the weight constraints (55lb), licensing requirements and flight
                regulations (Cannot be operated indoors, drone must be visible from pilot's location
                and drone cannot fly over individuals not involved in its development). </app_ovr>
        </page>

        <page type="fsb">
            <fsb_hlgt type="econ">This project has been allotted a budget of $1,000. <note
                    type="peer">Glad you included budget, it puts alot of the project in
                    perspective</note> Although it is possible to appeal for additional funding,
                there do not exist products on the market that could directly address our goals even
                with blank check funding. It is worth noting that many equal and more advanced DIY
                projects have achieved success on smaller budgets. </fsb_hlgt>
            <fsb_hlgt type="tcnl">The project can be broken down into four stages. 1) Determine
                necessary equipment to assemble a quad-copter drone with an attached camera. 2)
                Develop long range object tracking software for stationary targets. 3) Develop long
                range object tracking software for moving targets. 4) Develop and attach the magnet
                capturing system. 5) Accommodate object tracking and automated capture for
                stationary targets. 5) Develop tracking and capture of moving targets. <pb/>1) In
                order to allow for ample time to tackle the advances in research put forth by our
                project, it is vital to minimize the amount of time dedicated to "reinventing the
                wheel". With this in mind, the minimal quad-copter style frame is justified rather
                as opposed to investing in the more difficult to control (although more steady) hex
                or octo-copter designs. Additionally, by using a frame kit time can be saved by
                avoiding the difficult build and tuning process inherent to a custom frame.
                Similarly, the choice of the Pixy CMUcam5 for our camera system allows all object
                detection to be automated. This not only frees up time for the software development
                team -- allowing them to focus on other goals -- but it also justifies the use of
                the Raspberry Pi 3b -- which has a less complex set of barriers than the more
                powerful SOCs on the market. <pb/>2) The data being output from the Pixy should
                allow for object identification and location. Determining motor commands in order to
                move toward an identified object is straightforward in a low-variable environment,
                however the movement of our anti-drone and the frame size of the Pixy (risking the
                visual loss of the target) pose significant issues. This will likely need to be
                accommodated by slow movements and a mobile camera. <pb/>3) The chief concerns for
                the magnetic system are the weight that it will add to the drone and issues that EMF
                interference might cause. A Faraday cage might be able to offset the EMF
                interference, however time intensive tests must be performed in order to determine
                its viability. <pb/>4) In order to descend upon the target, it is highly probable
                that a second downward facing camera will need to be added. This poses issues with
                kinematics, as movements must be made much more precise in order to preserve
                downward visuals of the target drone. Additionally, the acquisition of the target
                must be performed in a way that does not damage the anti-drone, and does not cause
                an irreconcilable weight increase. <pb/>5) The processes described above are made
                significantly more challenging due to both objects being in movement. Developing
                mobile tracking algorithms would be an achievement without the capture in
                consideration. </fsb_hlgt>
            <fsb_hlgt type="lgl">Lastly, acquiring the FAA required license and executing the above
                processes should be of no great impediment. </fsb_hlgt>
        </page>


        <page type="sccs_crt">
            <req_sect>Hardware Design <req>The anti-drone must be capable of flying and must be
                    tuned such that moderate gusts of wind and sudden weight gains do not cause the
                    vehicle to malfunction. </req>
                <req>A flying time of roughly 10 minutes is to be expected. </req></req_sect>
            <req_sect>Automated Flight <req>The anti-drone should be capable of autonomously
                    following a test drone. No required target acquisition times are being
                    considered for this project, however it is worth noting that a perfected system
                    should be able to identify and capture a target drone under time
                    constraints.</req></req_sect>
            <req_sect>Drone Acquisition <req>The anti-drone should be able to make contact with at
                    least a 5lb target drone. After acquisition, the drone should be able to fly at
                    least 100 yards with the target drone in tow before releasing it.
                </req></req_sect>
        </page>

        <page type="cost">
            <est type="fnc"> Pixy motion sensor : $69.00</est>
            <est type="fnc"> 1400 mAh LiPo Battery Pack: $28.99 </est>
            <est type="fnc"> Carbon Fiber Frame Kit: $98 </est>
            <est type="fnc"> Flip32 Flight Controller </est>
            <est type="fnc"> Connectors and Cables : $50 </est>
            <est type="fnc"> Supplementary Components (Power cables, connectors, etc.): $86.95 </est>
            <est type="fnc"> Misc (Shipping, tax, nuts and bolts etc.): $120 </est>
            <est type="fnc"> Total : $469</est>
        </page>

        <page type="rpt"> All stages of this process will be monitored and developed with the help
            of Dr. Bahram Shafai. <tmln date="2016-09-02">Kit drone fully assembled (but un-tuned)
                with with stage 1 of parts added. Stage 1 parts: Pixy, Raspberry Pi3, Flip32 flight
                controller, power distribution components. </tmln>
            <tmln date="2016-09-04"> Drone Assembly </tmln>
            <tmln date="2016-09-18"> Establish WiFi Control and Tuning </tmln>
            <tmln date="2016-09-18"> Independent Subsystem API Dev. </tmln>
            <tmln date="2016-09-25"> Faraday cage testing.</tmln>
            <tmln date="2016-10-02"> Finalize capture Method.</tmln>
            <tmln date="2016-10-09"> Stationary Object Tracking. </tmln>
            <tmln date="2016-10-16"> Hardware Design Finalization. </tmln>
            <tmln date="2016-11-06"> Independent Capture System Working. </tmln>
            <tmln date="2016-11-06"> Mobile Object Tracking. </tmln>
            <tmln date="2016-11-27"> Mobile Tracking and Acquisition. </tmln>
            <tmln date="2016-12-24"> Organize Capstone Report. </tmln>
            <tmln date="2016-12-11"> Capstone presentation week</tmln>
        </page>

        <page type="rsk_ana"> The project lends itself to many potential developmental issues. <pb/>
            <img url="http://i.imgur.com/EI8HSAk.png"/>
            <pb/>These risks can be mitigated as follows : Severe Crash : Maintain a low cost of
            components. Less than half of the proposed expenditures relate to the on-board systems.
            Replacing these components is trivial. <pb/> Connectivity Issues : Time spent solving
            connectivity issues is offset by our choosing devices that are well supported and are
            known for their ease of development. <pb/> Unworkable EMF : Should the electromagnet not
            be a viable solution, other alternatives of capture can be investigated. <pb/> System
            Compatibility: Preliminary analysis has been performed to verify all components are
            compatible. <pb/> Processor Overwork : Using the Pixy to perform image analysis off of
            the Raspberry Pi heavily reduces the workload expected of the Pi. <pb/>Time frame :
            Weekly assessments of development must be in place to ensure the workload keeps pace.
            Given our project tackles two new ares (tracking and capture) of drone technology, the
            goal of capture can be left incomplete without having the entire project be deemed a
            failure. <pb/>Under-budgeting : We have received notice that an additional $200 can
            likely be made available should our project run over budget. </page>

        <page type="conc">
            <fsb>To meet the goals set by our capstone design, not only does the project require
                well executed engineering, but it also contains a research aspect. The engineering
                portion is represented by the leveraging of existing tools, whereas the research
                portion is represented by the development of tracking and capture algorithms. Due to
                the inherent uncertainty of research, not only is it impossible to accurately
                predict the time frame for the development process, but it also obfuscates what is
                realistic.</fsb>
            <cond>Technical difficulties are accentuated by the limited time frame allotted. The
                goals presented are in the realm of possibility, however budgeting time is of
                paramount importance. Minimizing time spent on "reinventing the wheel" will allow us
                to focus on the unique aspects of our project, however even with proper time
                management it seems reasonable to doubt that the full manifestation of tracking and
                development will be functional before December 4th. </cond> Fortunately, assessment
            of the current achievements in drone technology establishes that an autonomous tracking
            system for moving objects in three dimensional space can be considered a satisfactory
            achievement on its own. The team should prioritize the tracking system, and reevaluate
            at a later date to determine if time allows to develop and integrate the capture
            mechanisms. </page>

    </fsb_rpt>


    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="b11"/>
        <report type="peer" resp="#b11">
            <p>Oliver is writing a feasibility study for developing an anti-drone system in order to
                combat the speedy rise of commercial drones because of the percieved risks to safety
                and security, and also the slowness of regulation to adapt to technology. </p>
            <p>So firstly, I have to hand it to the author and say that this is a really cool idea.
                His preliminary document mentioned that he has worked with this as part of his
                capstone, and I think it lends itself really well to the genre of the Feasibility
                Study. He mentioned that he wanted to avoid being redundant in the document, I
                definitely understand that because it is easy to do so here. Oliver does a really
                good job avoiding this and it makes the document fun to read, which feasibility
                studies are often not. I noted a few things I thought were discrepancies in the
                table of contents, but otherwise the present content matches the genre very well, at
                least from my understanding of it. </p>

            <p> That being said I think this specific feasibility study would benefit greatly from a
                risk analysis chart and an image/design of the proposed system. I think detailing
                what you believe the final result may look like, even if you don't have the full
                picture yet, would help support the "pick-up and read" idea of feasibility studies.
                It would support the simplicity of the document, and as you know everyone loves
                pictures. </p>

            <p> Oliver asked for a critique of his use of "pre_req_ana and succ_crit", but I think
                they are being used very appropriately. I think he avoids being redundant where it
                is very easy to do and successfully separated the paradigm of thinking between the
                two. The "What will we have to do" vs "what will make / break this project" My one
                thought might be to include more regulatory thoughts relating to the permitting of
                the anti-drone device and how you might run into legal trouble, but that could also
                be included in a risk analysis table. </p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
