<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Automated Magnet Based Anti-Drone System Feasibility Report</title>
        <author xml:id="s24">Oliver Scott</author>
        <version n="1" date="2016-08-20"/>
    </docHead>
    <!-- root element for P3 here -->
    <fsb_rpt>
        <page type="ttl">
            <title>Automated Magnet Based Anti-Drone System</title>
            <subTitle>Automating drone movements with target based optical tracking</subTitle>
            <contributors>Oliver Scott, Nate Winn, Tanner Lindemer, Robert Daigle, Robert Peterson,
                Robert LeBel</contributors>
            <date>August 16th 2016</date>
        </page>
        <page type="tbl_contents">
            <sect lvl="1" n="1">Executive Summary</sect>
            <sect lvl="1" n="2">Preliminary Analysis</sect>
            <sect lvl="2" n="1">Tracking</sect>
            <sect lvl="2" n="2">Target Acquisition</sect>
            <sect lvl="2" n="3">Regulations</sect>
            <sect lvl="1" n="3">Feasibility</sect>
            <sect lvl="1" n="3">
                <note type="peer">should be n="4"</note>Success Criteria</sect>
            <sect lvl="2" n="1">Hardware Design</sect>
            <sect lvl="2" n="2">Automated Flight</sect>
            <sect lvl="2" n="3">Target Acquisition</sect>
            <sect lvl="1" n="4">Cost</sect>
            <sect lvl="1" n="5">Report <note type="peer"> Are you going to include the conclusion in
                    the table of contents?</note></sect>
        </page>
        <page type="exec_sum"><background>The proliferation of single board computers has greatly
                reduced the cost and complexity of drone development. As a result, an exponential
                number of drones are taking to the skies each year, outpacing the FAA and local
                authorities' ability to regulate them. The difficulty of regulating aerial vehicles
                compounded with the ability of pilots to navigate their drones from remote locations
                exposes a serious vulnerability with maintaining privacy, safety and
                security.</background>
            <pb/><report_purpose>This report will investigate a novel way to police drones using an
                anti-drone system.</report_purpose><fsb.approach> The approach discussed below
                surveys an anti-drone that would autonomously track and capture a target drone using
                electromagnets.</fsb.approach>
            <key_findings>The report highlights many potential difficulties in development --
                chiefly that research is being performed in tandem with engineering -- making
                predicting success highly difficult, however the design remains feasible enough to
                develop as a proof of concept. </key_findings>
        </page>
        <page type="prelim_ana">
            <app_ovr type="obj" title="Tracking">The anti-drone will be able to takeoff from a given
                location while being operated by a pilot. Once the target is in frame and
                recognized, the drone should be capable of autonomously moving above of the target. </app_ovr>
            <app_ovr type="obj" title="Target Acquisition">Once the anti-drone is in position,
                electromagnets will be deployed to neutralize the target. At this point the pilot
                can resume control and navigate the anti-drone to a position in which the disabled
                drone can be dropped. </app_ovr>
            <app_ovr type="rls" title="Regulations">The FAA has regularly been advancing their
                regulations on drone usage. The most up to date rules can be found at:
                    <ref>https://www.faa.gov/uas/media/Part_107_Summary.pdf</ref>. Relevant to our
                project are the weight constraints (55lb), licensing requirements and flight
                regulations (Cannot be operated indoors, drone must be visible from pilot's location
                and drone cannot fly over individuals not involved in its development). </app_ovr>
        </page>

        <page type="fsb">
            <fsb_hlgt type="econ">This project has been allotted a budget of $1,000. <note
                    type="peer">Glad you included budget, it puts alot of the project in
                    perspective</note> Although it is possible to appeal for additional funding,
                there do not exist products on the market that could directly address our goals even
                with ample funding. It is worth noting that many equal and more advanced DIY
                projects have achieved success on smaller budgets. </fsb_hlgt>
            <fsb_hlgt type="tcnl">The project can be broken down into four stages. 1) Determine
                necessary equipment to assemble a quad-copter drone and camera configuration. 2)
                Enable long range object tracking for stationary targets. 3) Develop and attach the
                magnet capturing system. 4) Accommodate short range object tracking and automated
                capturing for stationary targets. 5) Develop tracking and capture of moving targets.
                <pb/>1) In order to allow for ample time to tackle the advances in research put
                forth by our project, it is vital to minimize the amount of time dedicated to drone
                construction. As a result a quad-copter style frame makes more sense than investing
                in the more difficult to control (although more steady) hex or octo-copter designs.
                By using a frame kit, time will be saved by not having to build and tune one from
                scratch, and being able to modify it provides obvious benefits that buying a
                stock-copter does not. Similarly, the choice of the Pixy CMUcam5 for camera allows
                all object detection to be automated. This not only frees up the time of the
                software developers, allowing them to focus on other goals, but it also justifies
                the use of the Raspberry Pi 3b -- which has a less complex set of barriers than its
                more powerful SOC counterparts. <pb/>2) The data being fed from the Pixy should
                allow for object identification and location. Determining motor commands in order to
                move toward an identified object is straightforward in a low-variable environment,
                however the movement of our anti-drone and the frame size of the Pixy (risking the
                visual loss of the target) pose significant issues. This will likely need to be
                accommodated by slow movements and an adjustable camera. <pb/>3) The chief concerns
                for the magnetic system is the weight that it would add to the drone and issues that
                EMI might cause. A Faraday cage might be a working alternative, however testing will
                need to be performed to determine the possibility of this option. <pb/>4) In order
                to descend upon the target, it is very likely that a second camera will need to be
                added facing downward. The issues with kinematics in this step are that movement
                must be much more fine in order to ensure visual of the target drone is not lost.
                Additionally the acquisition of the target must be performed in a way that does not
                damage the anti-drone, and does not cause an irreconcilable weight increase. <pb/>5)
                The processes described above are made significantly more challenging when both
                objects are moving. It is realistic that this would be a project in
                itself.</fsb_hlgt>
            <fsb_hlgt type="lgl">Acquiring a license and executing the above processes should be of
                no great impediment. </fsb_hlgt>
        </page>


        <page type="sccs_crt">
            <req_sect>Hardware Design <req>The anti-drone must be capable of flying and be of proper
                    tuning such that moderate gusts of wind and sudden weight gains do not cause the
                    vehicle to malfunction. </req>
                <req>A flying time of roughly 10 minutes is to be expected. </req></req_sect>
            <req_sect>Automated Flight <req>The anti-drone should be capable of the anti-drone can
                    autonomously navigate to and follow a test drone. Before deployment in the real
                    world, a time requirement should be instantiated such that the drone could react
                    quickly to a threat, however as this report details a research project, there is
                    no time expectation in effect. </req></req_sect>
            <req_sect>Drone Acquisition <req>The anti-drone should be able to make contact with at
                    least a 10lb target drone. Theoretically it should be able to disable the target
                    drone, however there is no way of guaranteeing that the magnets will be capable
                    of this in all circumstances. After acquisition, the drone should be able to fly
                    at least 100 yards with the target drone in tow before releasing it.
                </req></req_sect>
        </page>

        <page type="cost">
            <est type="fnc"> Pixy motion sensor : $69.00</est>
            <est type="fnc"> 1400 mAh LiPo Battery Pack: $28.99 </est>
            <est type="fnc"> Carbon Fiber Frame Kit: $98 </est>
            <est type="fnc"> Flip32 Flight Controller </est>
            <est type="fnc"> Connectors and Cables : $50 </est>
            <est type="fnc"> Supplementary Components (Power cables, connectors, etc.): $86.95 </est>
            <est type="fnc"> Misc (Shipping, tax, nuts and bolts etc.): $120 </est>
            <est type="fnc"> Total : $469</est>
        </page>

        <page type="rpt"> All stages of this process will be monitored and developed with the help
            of Dr. Bahram Shafai. <tmln date="2016-09-02">Kit drone fully assembled (but un-tuned)
                with with stage 1 of parts added. Stage 1 parts: Pixy, Raspberry Pi3, Flip32 flight
                controller, power distribution components. </tmln>
            <tmln date="2016-09-04"> Drone Assembly </tmln>
            <tmln date="2016-09-18"> Establish WiFi Control and Tuning </tmln>
            <tmln date="2016-09-18"> Independent Subsystem API Dev. </tmln>
            <tmln date="2016-09-25"> Faraday cage testing.</tmln>
            <tmln date="2016-10-02"> Finalize capture Method.</tmln>
            <tmln date="2016-10-09"> Stationary Object Tracking. </tmln>
            <tmln date="2016-10-16"> Hardware Design Finalization. </tmln>
            <tmln date="2016-11-06"> Independent Capture System Working. </tmln>
            <tmln date="2016-11-06"> Mobile Object Tracking. </tmln>
            <tmln date="2016-11-27"> Mobile Tracking and Acquisition. </tmln>
            <tmln date="2016-12-24"> Organize Capstone Report. </tmln>
            <tmln date="2016-12-11"> Capstone presentation week</tmln>
            <visual type="other" url="http://i.imgur.com/femCoTp.png">Team Based Visual
                Timeline</visual>
        </page>

        <page type="rsk_ana"> The primary risks posed to this project are assessed as follows:
                <visual type="other" url="http://i.imgur.com/EI8HSAk.png"/>
            <pb/>These risks can be mitigated as follows : Severe Crash : Maintain a low cost of
            components. Only of the expenditures proposed are attributed to on-board systems.
            Replacing these is trivial. The largest consequence of any broken components would be
            the downtime in development. <pb/> Connectivity Issues : Time spent solving these issues
            is offset by our choice of devices that are well known for easy development
            environments. <pb/> Unworkable EMF : Should the electromagnet not be a viable solution,
            other alternatives of capture can be investigated. <pb/> System Compatibility:
            Preliminary analysis has been performed to verify all components are compatible. <pb/>
            Processor Overwork : Using the Pixy to perform image analysis off of the Raspberry Pi
            heavily reduces the workload expected of the controls program. Time frame : Weekly
            assessments of development must be in place to ensure the workload keeps pace. Given our
            project tackles two new ares (tracking and capture) of drone technology, the goal of
            capture can be left incomplete without having the entire project be deemed a failure.
            Under-budgeting : We have received notice that an additional $200 can likely be made
        available to us should our project run over budget. </page>

        <page type="conc">
            <fsb>In order to accomplish the mission put forth by our capstone design, not only does
                our project require well executed engineering, but it will also contain an aspect of
                research. The engineering portion is represented by the leveraging of existing
                tools, and the research portion is represented in our tracking and capture
                technology. Due to the uncertainty of research, not only is it impossible to
                accurately predict the development process, but it also obfuscates what is
                realistic.</fsb>
            <cond>The primary point of difficulty will be the limited time we have to develop our
                product. There is no doubt that what we seek to do is possible, however budgeting
                time is of the greatest order of importance. Minimizing time spent on "reinventing
                the wheel" will allow us to focus on the unique aspects of our project, however even
                then it still seems doubtful that the project will be functioning at peak
                performance come December. </cond> It is reasonable to expect the tracking
            capabilities of two moving objects can be completed by December, however the team will
            need to reevaluate at a later and better informed date if time allows for the capturing
            capabilities to be integrated. </page>

    </fsb_rpt>


    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="b11"/>
        <report type="peer" resp="#b11">
            <p>Oliver is writing a feasibility study for developing an anti-drone system in order to
                combat the speedy rise of commercial drones because of the percieved risks to safety
                and security, and also the slowness of regulation to adapt to technology. </p>
            <p>So firstly, I have to hand it to the author and say that this is a really cool idea.
                His preliminary document mentioned that he has worked with this as part of his
                capstone, and I think it lends itself really well to the genre of the Feasibility
                Study. He mentioned that he wanted to avoid being redundant in the document, I
                definitely understand that because it is easy to do so here. Oliver does a really
                good job avoiding this and it makes the document fun to read, which feasibility
                studies are often not. I noted a few things I thought were discrepancies in the
                table of contents, but otherwise the present content matches the genre very well, at
                least from my understanding of it. </p>

            <p> That being said I think this specific feasibility study would benefit greatly from a
                risk analysis chart and an image/design of the proposed system. I think detailing
                what you believe the final result may look like, even if you don't have the full
                picture yet, would help support the "pick-up and read" idea of feasibility studies.
                It would support the simplicity of the document, and as you know everyone loves
                pictures. </p>

            <p> Oliver asked for a critique of his use of "pre_req_ana and succ_crit", but I think
                they are being used very appropriately. I think he avoids being redundant where it
                is very easy to do and successfully separated the paradigm of thinking between the
                two. The "What will we have to do" vs "what will make / break this project" My one
                thought might be to include more regulatory thoughts relating to the permitting of
                the anti-drone device and how you might run into legal trouble, but that could also
                be included in a risk analysis table. </p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
