<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>WP3 Edutainment Blog Post</title>
        <author xml:id="s25">Leo Stolov</author>
        <version n="1" date="2016-08-13"/>
    </docHead>

    <blog_post>
        <background>
            <section_header>Why are bacteria shaped the way they are?</section_header>
            <question>What is responsible for bacteria to develop into weird shapes?</question>
            <misconception>Could be for food or protection, which might be part of it, but none seem
                to be the main driving factor.</misconception>
            <important_idea>But to understand exactly the reason for these weird shapes one first
                has to understand something about the world of bacteria, specifically the fluid the
                fluid they move in. The first step is to understand the Reynolds number.
            </important_idea>
        </background>
        <answer>
            <section_header>What is the Reynolds number?</section_header>
            <technical_principle n="1">Mathematically, the Reynolds number can be expressed like
                this: <visual type="other"
                    url="http://ffden-2.phys.uaf.edu/104_2012_web_projects/Daniela_Wilner/Images/ReynoldsNumber.png"
                /> The Reynolds number (Re in the equation above) is defined as the ratio of
                inertial forces to viscous forces. What does that mean? Well the first thing that
                should be noted is that it is a ratio. It has no units attached. The Reynolds number
                can be 46, it can 46 million. It’s just a number. But it is a very useful number,
                especially for engineers. Engineers use the Reynolds number to characterize how a
                fluid (liquid or gas) flows. It tells engineers when to use certain equations for
                certain situations, and when not to use them. </technical_principle>
            <section_header>What does the Reynolds number depend on?</section_header>
            <technical_principle n="2">Here’s the breakdown: ρ is density of the fluid, V is
                velocity, D is diameter, or the size of the volume being analyzed, and μ is
                viscosity, which is a fluid's resistance to movement <analogy>(molasses is much more
                    viscous than water).</analogy>
            </technical_principle>
            <section_header>So what is low for a Reynolds number?</section_header>
            <analogy>Let's take a person swimming in water. Let's call him Arnold. <visual
                    type="drawing"
                    url="http://www.how-to-draw-funny-cartoons.com/image-files/cartoon-swimmer-007.jpg"
                />Arnold swims at an average speed of 2 mph or .894 m/s in water which has a density
                of 1000 kg/m^3 and a viscosity of about 10^-3 Pa*s. We can approximate Arnolds size,
                or diameter, as 1.5 ft or .457 m. Put these numbers into the equation and we get a
                Reynolds number of about 409000. Now, lets take a look at an E. Coli cell. <visual
                    type="drawing"
                    url="http://hyperphysics.phy-astr.gsu.edu/hbase/biology/imgbio/cellprokaryote6.gif"
                />A typical cell might be 2 μm or 2*10^-6 m and travel in water at a speed of 30
                μm/s or 3*10^-7 m/s. In this case your Reynolds number would be 0.00006 . That's
                several magnitudes smaller than Arnold's situation. If Arnold wanted to experience
                the same Reynold's number as an E. Coli cell he would have to move at a speed of
                about 1.3*10^-10 m/s. If he were to move at that speed for a whole year he would
                travel a staggering 4 millimeters.</analogy>
            <section_header>What does this tell us?</section_header>
            <important_idea>It tells us fluid flow has different properties at this level. It tells
                us life is different at low Reynolds numbers. </important_idea>
            <analogy>What does this mean? Imagine you get in the water and push Arnold. He will move
                while he’s being pushed, and then inertia will carry him so he floats a little bit
                farther away from you. Do the same in molasses, and he’ll stop almost immediately
                once the force of your push stops acting on him. <technical_principle n="3">His
                    movement in the water only depends on a current force acting on him, not on the
                    forces acting on him before. . In this case, his movement is not dependent on
                    time. It is said to be time invariant. </technical_principle>
            </analogy>
            <section_header>Scallops Theorem </section_header>
            <specific_topic>This concept is the cornerstone of Scallop Theorem, a theorem developed
                by physicist Edward Mills Purcell in his paper “Life at low Reynolds
                number”.</specific_topic><technical_principle n="4">”. It states that to travel at
                low Reynolds number a swimmer has to move or deform in a way that is not reciprocal. </technical_principle>
            <analogy>. A great example of this is, of course, the scallop. A scallop travels in
                water by slowly opening its shell to take in water, and quickly squirting it out to
                propel itself. <visual type="drawing"
                    url="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/4/40/Scallop_jump.svg"
                    /><technical_principle n="5">While this works great in a Scallop’s environment,
                    it would be useless at low Reynolds numbers, since the motion is reciprocal.
                    Since motion at low Reynolds flow is time invariant, the fact that the scallop
                    opened and closed its shell slowly and quickly does not matter. In this case,
                    the scallop would simply move one way when the shell opens, and move right back
                    to the same spot when it closes. </technical_principle></analogy>
        </answer>
        <sources/>
    </blog_post>

    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="peer_id_here"/>
        <report type="peer" resp="#peer_id_here">
            <p>Peer review report will appear here.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
