<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Cover Letter - Djordje</title>
        <author xml:id="v_27">Djordje Vlajkovic</author>
        <version n="1" date="2016-08-11"/>
    </docHead>

    <cover_letter>
        <header>
            <name>Djordje Vlajkovic</name>
            <contact_info>
                <!-- One or More Contact -->
                <contact type="address">1050 Main Street, Melrose MA 02176</contact>
                <contact type="phone"> 857-285-8415 </contact>
                <contact type="email"> vlajkovic.d@husky.neu.edu </contact>
            </contact_info>
        </header>
        <greeting>Hello hiring committee,</greeting>
        <intro_para>
            <intent type="purpose">I am applying for the open lead engineering position in your
                development department at GE Aviation.</intent> I have been looking for a job lately
            and when I saw that you were hiring for this position, I immediately had to put in my
            application. <intent type="connection">After showing up to a seminar hosted by one of
                your employees, I found some open positions at your company and when I saw this
                position open I knew where I want to apply to.</intent><note type="peer"
                xml:id="g14">In this paragraph, try to use stronger action verbs: "attending" vs.
                "showing up to," "became interested in" vs. "found," etc. Rephrase "I have been
                looking for a job lately" -- if you weren't, you wouldn't be applying.</note>
            <reason>Considering my background and qualifications, I think that I would be a perfect
                fit for the position</reason> and <proposition>if you hire me I will translate well
                into the culture of the company and excel at every turn.</proposition><note
                type="peer" xml:id="g14">rephrase "if you hire me" to "if I am accepted I feel that
                I will translate well," etc.</note>
        </intro_para>
        <para_background>
            <!-- One or More -->
            <experience type="work">In my previous work experience, I've with GE Aviation in a
                business and manufacturing capacity. From that experience I've worked within
                    <programs>Solidworks and DWB</programs> to design and review parts of the
                engine. I've also worked with customers in a business manners, fulfill their needs
                and making sure necessary arrangements are made to satisfy their experience. I am
                also experienced in the<programs>Microsoft Office Programs such as Excel, Powerpoint
                    and Word.</programs> Through my experiences I have been able to acquire a lot of
                knowledge and skills that have enabled me to succeed at my previous positions. Some
                of my achievements over the years include <accomplishments>reducing inventory by
                    over a quarter million dollars, creating engine shipments to multiple nations,
                    identifying and incorporating process drawings to thousands of parts and
                    designing apparatuses for fully automated production cells.</accomplishments>
                From my experiences I've been able to attain many beneficial traits while also
                helping the individuals around me.</experience>
            <experience type="personal">Outside of work I also have many other skills that I
                practiced or learned in my spare time. One such skill that I've acquired over the
                years has been coding in languages such as <programs>C++, Matlab, and Python
                </programs> where I've developed many programs and in turn strengthen my ability to
                comprehend and write within those languages. I also come from a diverse background
                from which I capable of speaking languages like <languages>Serbian, Bosnian,
                    Croatian, and Montenegrin</languages>.</experience>
            <experience type="school">I received a bachelor's degree in Mechanical Engineering at
                Northeastern University. From there I have developed a strong understanding in math
                and sciences and have learned all of the necessary information that the field of
                Mechanical Engineering would require. From my classes in school I am capable of
                    <skills>understanding the mechanics and principles with components like
                    turbines, compressors and combustors</skills>.</experience>
        </para_background>
        <closing_statements>
            <compatability>Hopefully you can see from what I have written<note type="peer"
                    xml:id="g14">Rephrase this</note> that I would be right for the position. I am a
                very easy person to get along with and communicate well with my co-workers. I am
                very respectful of others views and can conform to the environment that I am placed
                in.</compatability>
            <pb/>
            <next_step>I hope that you find my application to your liking,<note type="peer"
                    xml:id="">Again, rephrase - you didn't write this to match their "liking,"
                    you're writing this to get an interview</note> and if you need to reach me for
                an interview and need to acquire any additional information my phone number is
                857-285-8415 and my email address is vlajkovic.d@husky.neu.edu.<note type="peer"
                    xml:id="g14">They WILL reach out for an interview, rephrase this so it isn't a
                    passive gesture.</note> I appreciate the time you took to go through my
                application and thank you for your consideration.</next_step>
        </closing_statements>
        <signature>
            <salutation>Sincerely,</salutation>
            <name>Djordje Vlajkovic</name>
        </signature>
    </cover_letter>

    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="g14"/>
        <report type="peer" resp="#g14">
            <p>In summary, this document represents the situation where Djordje is applying for a
                lead engineering position in a GE Aviation development program, wherein he outlines
                which aspects of his experience, skills, character, and interest would make him a
                competitive candidate for the open position.</p>
            <p>I'll list some typos/minor suggestions as I come across them here: In the first
                background paragraph, check for missing words, typos, etc., there are a couple that
                standout. I recommend against listing experience with Microsoft Office and then
                listing specific programs, your resume can speak to this, it's probably assumed at
                this point that everyone knows how to use these programs, only mention them if you
                are an Excel expert, etc., something that really stands out. Otherwise, I recommend
                omitting or just mentioning Microsoft Office and leaving it at that. Especially so
                since your following accomplishments are supremely more relevant and impressive.
                Consider rephrasing "traits" to "skills," or add a sentence to talk about
                personal/character trait development.</p>
            <p>In the "personal" paragraph, add in any hobbies or interests that might be relevant
                (read about aircraft development/design, etc.) or any volunteer research work you
                have done in mechanical engineering/related disciplines (or even unrelated personal
                volunteer work that speak to your character). In the final background paragraph, add
                more info on specific higher level classes that are relevant to the position, such
                as thermo, materials, etc. (you know them better than I do) - classes that
                demonstrate you have gained a comprehensive relevant education. Include any minors,
                etc. that might or might not be directly relevant (math minor, etc.).</p>
            <p>We can speak in person about exact phrasings of things, but overall the key takeaways
                are to take a more action-oriented stance, as opposed to passive suggestions, and
                minimize the use of "you" and "your" whenever possible. Remember: this is about you
                trying to get an interview, not about trying to please the reader. My ultimate
                recommendation is to use language that expresses interest in the company or the
                position -- at times you sound dispassionate and disinterested, and a hiring manager
                might not feel the urgency to call someone who outwardly uses
                passive/disinterested/last resort-type language. In terms of structure itself, I might
                suggest making your work experience last, so that your big accomplishments are the
                most recent thing on their mind when they reach the bottom. Also, upon realizing
                this is for a lead engineering position, I recommend citing any
                leadership/teamwork/teambuiling experience you have (mention it to have it come up
                in the interview) that would make you a strong candidate for this
                position, as opposed to a process engineering/lower-profile position in the same
                department with less leadership expectations.</p>
            <p>Overall, you did a great job of using all/most of the elements of the schema, and did
            a fantastic job using skills, accomplishments, programs tags. If possible, include a few
            more accomplishments to really demonstrate your prowess. After you visit each of the
            comments listed above, feel free to remove them, the XML schema agreement was impeccable
            before it started getting upset that I used my xml id multiple times (giving the red
            flags -- just delete them when you're done with them). Overall the schema use is
            perfect, only steps need to be taken on typos and rephrasings, and adding more content
            as suggested previously. Great start.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
