<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Writing Project 3</title>
        <author xml:id="v26">Michael Van Wickle</author>
        <version n="2" date="2016-08-22"/>
    </docHead>

    <blog_post>
        <title>A Second Sun?</title>
        <background>
            <question> What would happen if a second sun appeared where Pluto currently is? </question>
            <pb/>
            <technical_principle n="1"> The core principle involved here is the theory of
                gravitation. We will be using the Newtonian theory, first formulated by Isaac Newton
                in the 17th century. <important_idea n="1"> The gravitational force is predicated on
                    the mass of each object and the distance between them. </important_idea> This
                version of gravitation has since been replaced by General Relativity, described
                first by Albert Einstein, but still serves fine for large-scale approximations,
                which we will do here. </technical_principle>
        </background>
        <answer>
            <pb/>
            <section_header>The Situation</section_header>
            <important_idea n="2"> Imagine it's any other day, like a Tuesday, you're going about
                your day when suddenly Pluto suddenly becomes a G-type main sequence star (the same
                type of star as the sun). This star is exactly identical to the Sun. <visual
                    type="drawing" url="http://i.imgur.com/bRLFQnU.jpg">Close up of Pluto</visual>
            </important_idea>
            <pb/>
            <section_header>Assumptions</section_header>
            <important_idea n="3"> In order to make this problem more tractable, we make a few
                assumptions about the situation. First, the planets are basically aligned and at
                their furthest distance. This is important as the planets, and particularly Pluto,
                do not have perfectly circular orbits. Also this helps as the gravitational effect
                on the planets is more uniform. We will also only be looking at the effects in the
                short term. The long term effects on orbits is a complex problem that would likely
                take a fair amount of simulation, so I'll ignore it, for now. <pb/> As a notation
                note, I'll be using Sol1 to refer to the Sun we have now and Sol2 to refer to the
                star where Pluto is now. </important_idea>
            <pb/>
            <section_header>Effects on Earth</section_header>
            <technical_principle n="2"> Gravitation, as stated above, is predicated on three
                variables, the mass of object one, the mass of object 2, and the inverse square of
                the distance between them. The distance between Earth and the Sun (Sol1) is defined
                as one astronomical unit (AU), which is about 150 kilometers (93 million miles). The
                distance between Pluto (Sol2) and Earth is 48 times that distance. </technical_principle>
            <specific_topic n="1"> We'll first tackle the effects this change would have on us,
                since we're so self centered. The good news, sort of, is that Earth will remain in
                orbit mainly around Sol1. Since Sol2 is so very, very far away, its gravitational
                effect is very, very small compared to Sol1's (around 23 hundred times smaller). The
                overall effect is, essentially Sol1's gravity becomes slightly weaker and we move
                slightly further away from the Sol1. <visual type="drawing"
                    url="http://i.imgur.com/jc82jmo.jpg">Force on Earth</visual> The net effect?
                Earth gets a little colder and slowly drifts outwards, towards an equilibrium point
                between Sol1 and Sol2. This may sound bad, and it is. </specific_topic>
            <important_idea n="4"> Net gravitational force from Sol1 is decreased, we drift
                outwards, and most likely slowly freeze to death. This outcome is predicted even
                without taking into account other effects of having a second sun. </important_idea>
            <pb/>
            <section_header>Effects on Other Planets</section_header>
            <technical_principle n="3"> What I'll be doing here is comparing the gravitational force
                exerted by Sol1 with the gravitational force exerted by Sol2 (on each planet). If
                the force exerted by Sol2 is the larger value, then it "captures" the planet. This
                is a fairly simplistic way of looking at this, and would only really apply in the
                short term. </technical_principle>
            <specific_topic n="2"> Using the mass of each planet along with each planet's distance
                we can gain an early estimate of what the new solar system will look like. We'll
                start from the outer solar system and work our way in. Starting, for some reason,
                with Pluto (not actually a planet). Pluto is gone, completely, vaporized; no
                gravitational effect from either star. Neptune is captured, just barely, by Sol2
                whose gravitational effect is around two and a half times larger than that of Sol1.
                It is, in fact, the only planet captured outright by Sol2. All the other planets,
                while feeling some gravitational effect from Sol2, are still chiefly affected by
                Sol1. </specific_topic>
            <important_idea n="5"> Neptune is the only planet remotely close enough to Sol2 to be
                more affected by its gravity than that of Sol1. </important_idea>
            <explanation> The effects on Earth will be similar to effects on the solar system as a
                whole, with the added downside of the fact that we live here. The general effect on
                the planets is that at first they will spread out, moving towards Sol2 as it negates
                some of the gravitational force of Sol1. In a longer time frame, the orbits of the
                planets will become more and more perturbed and complicated. In fact, at a certain
                point, some planets may be ejected from the solar system or collide with Sol1 or
                Sol2. </explanation>
            <pb/>
            <conclusion>
                <section_header></section_header>
                <important_idea n="7"> The general takeaway here is that in this situation, the
                    solar system will change drastically. A side effect of this change: human
                    extinction comes much sooner than most people currently expect.
                </important_idea> Luckily this situation has effectively zero percent chance of
                happening, so we can sleep easy at night knowing that Pluto will not become a star.
            </conclusion>
        </answer>
        <pb/>
        <sources> Wikipedia was a great help in finding the masses and orbital radii of planets.
                <ref type="source" url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Solar_System">Solar System
                Article</ref>
        </sources>
    </blog_post>
    <!-- Writer's Memo 
        
    - I would say that I am in the very early rough draft phase. I have an question, for which I have
    a few answers. However, I am not close at all to this project's final form. I have no pictures and
    no analogies. My answers are also mainly super short term. 
    
    - My rhetorical situation is the answering of a question. I would say that it is geared towards
    curious people who are relatively scientifically literate. They also should have a mind that
    would be interested in the answer to the question: "what if Pluto became the sun?"
    
    - The main (only) thing that is going well is that I thought of a question to answer. 
    
    - It has been difficult thinking of analogies that could go with this, shown by the fact that I
    have none. Also difficult has been making sure that I'm not saying the same thing over and over
    again. 
    
    - Specific Things:
    1. Am I writing the same thing over and over again? cause it writing/reading this felt like
    Groundhog Day. 
    2. Is the writing too scientific? Not scientific enough? I can't tell.
    3. Thoughts on analogies? I got nothing. 
    
    -->

    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="s25"/>
        <report type="peer" resp="#s25">
            <p>This edutainment science blog post explores the gravitational effects on the solar
                system if Pluto suddenly became a second Sun.</p>
            <p>This blog post does a good job of answering a hypothetical situation in a way that I
                could easily understand. My main critique, in terms of content, is that there could
                be more information regarding what happens to the solar system. A good point of
                elaboration would be where you mention a decrease in the temperature on Earth. It
                would be interesting to know how significant this change would be, and you could
                also answer a possible misconception I had which is the distance of the Earth from
                the Sun is not extremely important with regards to temperature. Something like this
                might also make the post seem less repetitive, which is a valid point you had,
                though I think that simply may be due to the nature of the answer.</p>
            <p>In terms of how scientific the writing is, I think you do a good job of not making it
                too complicated for the reader. However, I think it might make sense to add some
                more numerical answers to quantify your explanations. This could include just how
                far the Earth displaces after a year, or how fast it accelerates immediately after
                getting hit by the gravitational waves. I would also be interested to know how long
                it takes for the gravitational waves to reach Earth after Sol2 appears. Another
                small suggestion I would like to make in terms of scientific writing is that it
                might be worthwhile to explain what a "G-type main sequence star" since that might
                not be common knowledge.</p>
            <p>In terms of your third point, I agree analogies are difficult to think of for this
                topic. One possible place for an analogy could be where you describe the distance
                from the Earth to the Sun. Personally, that is a number too large for me to
                comprehend, so it might make sense to compare it to something more common. Other
                than that, I think there is good potential for analogies for sections you can add.
                One idea could be looking into how many times bigger the Sun is compared to Pluto,
                and how many Plutos could fit inside of the Sun. This could then be compared to
                something like bouncy balls fitting inside of a jar. Something like this could help
                the reader grasp why Sol2 has such a large effect on the Earth even though it is so
                far away.</p>

        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
