<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Cover Letter - Djordje</title>
        <author xml:id="v_27">Djordje Vlajkovic</author>
        <version n="1" date="2016-08-11"/>
    </docHead>
    
    <cover_letter>
        <header>
            <name>Djordje Vlajkovic</name>
            <contact_info>
                <!-- One or More Contact -->
                <contact type="address">1050 Main Street, Melrose MA 02176</contact>
                <contact type="phone"> 857-285-8415 </contact>
                <contact type="email"> vlajkovic.d@husky.neu.edu </contact>
            </contact_info>
        </header>
        <greeting>Hello hiring committee,</greeting>
        <intro_para>
            <intent type="purpose">I am applying for the open lead engineering position in your development department at GE Aviation.</intent> I have been looking for a job lately and when I saw that you were
            hiring for this position, I immediately had to put in my application. 
            <intent type="connection">After showing up to a seminar hosted by one of your employees, I found some open positions at your company and when I saw this position open I knew where I want to apply to.</intent>
            <reason>Considering my background and qualifications, I think that I would be a perfect fit for the position</reason> and <proposition>if you hire me I will translate well into the culture of the 
            company and excel at every turn.</proposition>
        </intro_para>
        <para_background>
            <!-- One or More -->
            <experience type="work">In my previous work experience, I've with GE Aviation in a business and manufacturing capacity. From that experience I've worked within <programs>Solidworks and DWB</programs> to design and  
                review parts of the engine. I've also worked with customers in a business manners, fulfill their needs and making sure necessary arrangements are made to satisfy their experience. I am also 
                experienced in the<programs>Microsoft Office Programs such as Excel, Powerpoint and Word.</programs> Through my experiences I have been able to acquire a lot of knowledge and skills that have enabled 
                me to succeed at my previous positions. Some of my achievements over the years include <accomplishments>reducing inventory by over a quarter million dollars, creating engine shipments to multiple nations, 
                identifying and incorporating process drawings to thousands of parts and designing apparatuses for fully automated production cells.</accomplishments> From my experiences I've been able to attain many 
                beneficial traits while also helping the individuals around me.</experience>
            <experience type="personal">Outside of work I also have many other skills that I practiced or learned in my spare time. One such skill that I've acquired over the years has been coding in languages such as
                 <programs>C++, Matlab, and Python </programs> where I've developed many programs and in turn strengthen my ability to comprehend and write within those languages. I also come from a diverse background
                from which I capable of speaking languages like <languages>Serbian, Bosnian, Croatian, and Montenegrin</languages>.</experience>
            <experience type="school">I received a bachelor's degree in Mechanical Engineering at Northeastern University. From there I have developed a strong understanding in math and sciences and have learned 
            all of the necessary information that the field of Mechanical Engineering would require. From my classes in school I am capable of <skills>understanding the mechanics and principles with components like 
            turbines, compressors and combustors</skills>.</experience>
        </para_background>
        <closing_statements>
            <compatability>Hopefully you can see from what I have written that I would be right for the position. I am a very easy person to get along with and communicate well with my co-workers. I am very respectful 
            of others views and can conform to the environment that I am placed in.</compatability><pb/>
            <next_step>I hope that you find my application to your liking, and if you need to reach me for an interview and need to acquire any additional information my phone number is 857-285-8415 and my email 
            address is vlajkovic.d@husky.neu.edu. I appreciate the time you took to go through my application and thank you for your consideration.</next_step>
        </closing_statements>
        <signature>
            <salutation>Sincerely,</salutation>
            <name>Djordje Vlajkovic</name>
        </signature>
    </cover_letter>
    
    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="peer_id_here"/>
        <report type="peer" resp="#peer_id_here">
            <p>Peer review report will appear here.</p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>