<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../schema_3302.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<!--the second line in the document associates the schema, so be sure not to change it-->
<DOC>
    <docHead>
        <!--required header includes metadata about the assignment (title, author, version)-->
        <title>Cover Letter - Writing Project 3</title>
        <author xml:id="your_id_here">Samantha Wagner</author>
        <version n="1" date="2016-08-11"/>
    </docHead>

    <cover_letter>
        <header>
            <name>Samantha Wagner</name>
            <contact_info>
                <!-- One or More Contact -->
                <contact type="address">38 Hemenway Street; Boston, MA 02115 </contact>
                <contact type="phone">425-686-0452 </contact>
                <contact type="email">sammwag@gmail.com</contact>
            </contact_info>
        </header>
        <greeting>Dear Mr. Sarkisian,</greeting>
        <intro_para>
            <intent type="purpose">I am interested in applying for a summer internship position
                within the structural engineering group at Skidmore, Owings and Merrill during the
                summer of 2017.</intent>
            <intent type="connection">After speaking with you over the phone this past summer about
                the different opportunities at SOM, I became increasingly interested in pursuing a
                job within the engineering department.</intent><note type="peer">What did he say
                over the phone that really attracted you?</note>
            <reason>I have a strong interest in both architecture and structural
                engineering</reason> and <proposition>I think I would be a great fit with the SOM
                culture. I have the necessary technical skills and passion for learning
            that would help me to succeed in a fast paced environment.</proposition>
        </intro_para>
        <para_background>
            <experience type="personal">Growing up I was exceedingly interested in the study of
                architecture and the design of the built environment. However it was not until late
                in highschool that I realized that my interests were more technical in nature. <note
                    type="peer">Formatting: extra closing accomplishments section</note></experience>
            <experience type="school">Now in my fourth year at Northeastern University I am pursuing
                a master's degree in civil engineering with a focus in structural.<accomplishments> I have taken
                courses in both the technical aspects of engineering and design as well as on the
                history of architecture in America.</accomplishments> </experience>
            <experience type="work">Entering into the industry I did not realize how isolated each
                of the different companies working on a project could be. In the past two years I
                have co-oped with two different companies within the building industry. With Skanska
                I <accomplishments>developed a better understanding of the technical and
                    coordination aspects involved with the construction of a
                    project.</accomplishments> While working at Simpson Gumpertz and Heger I was
                able to apply my <skills>technical knowledge from classes</skills> and improve my
                design skills with programs such as <programs>AutoCAD, Revit and RAM Steel.</programs>
                Ultimately I hope to one day use my technical background and project management
                skills to bring the separate groups together to work as a cohesive unit under each
                    project.<note type="peer">maybe be more specific with an accomplishment you've
                    made at work, this is our chance to show off your technical skills. Consider
                    mentioning how your structural expertise played into your ability to quickly
                    pick up new programs</note></experience>
        </para_background>
        <closing_statements>
            <compatability> For these reasons I think I will fit in well with the holistic design
                culture of SOM.</compatability>
            <next_step>I have attached my resume to this letter and I hope to hear from you in the
                future regarding possible opennings for interns in the Summer of 2017.</next_step>
        </closing_statements>
        <signature>
            <salutation>Sincerely,</salutation>
            <pb></pb>
            <name>Samantha Wagner</name>
        </signature>
    </cover_letter>

    <docReview>
        <reviewer type="peer" xml:id="p22"/>
        <report type="peer" resp="#p22">
            <p> Your background sections shows how you came to the conclusion that SOM would be a
                good fit for you. Maybe touch on how your desires play well into what SOM wants. For
                example, your interest in architecture combined with your technical expertise will
                allow you to be a crucial player in late-term project meetings where these two,
                commonly incompatible, goups have to meet (architects and structural engineers).
                Your ability in one field and your interest in the other sets you up well for upper
                management down the line as well as allows you to save the company money by not
                persuing one path initially with complete ignorance of the priorities of the other
                departments. For a company, having someone that can act as a technical specialist
                and a communications asset is extremely valuable. </p>
        </report>
        <reviewer type="instructor" xml:id="kgs"/>
        <report type="instructor" resp="#kgs">
            <p>Comments on assignment will appear here.</p>
        </report>
    </docReview>
</DOC>
